<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Passwords on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/passwords/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Passwords on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/passwords/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Confirming Passwords Is Annoying: Is There a Better Way?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/confirming-passwords-annoying-there-better-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/confirming-passwords-annoying-there-better-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.viget.com/advance/password-fields-are-annoying/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2198&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4b02bd5209f8f_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This an article from March 09 by Kevin Vigneault of Viget that explores some &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.viget.com/advance/password-fields-are-annoying/&#34;&gt;techniques using Javascript to create more usable password inputs&lt;/a&gt; in forms. The ideas range from using a checkbox or button to temporarily show the password or changing type from text to password when the input is not in focus. Great ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re interested in this topic, you might also want to check out Chris Dary&#39;s experiments with &lt;a href=&#34;experiments-password-masking.html&#34;&gt;password masking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.viget.com/advance/password-fields-are-annoying/&#34;&gt;http://www.viget.com/advance/password-fields-are-annoying/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiments in Password Masking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/experiments-password-masking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/experiments-password-masking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lab.arc90.com/2009/07/halfmask.php&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/halfmask.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jakob Nielsen recently &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.useit.com/alertbox/passwords.html&#34;&gt;called for an end to&lt;/a&gt; password masking, and a few people have come up with interesting approaches that try to find a middle ground between the typical prractice of masking passwords with asterisks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;arc90 are &lt;a href=&#34;http://lab.arc90.com/2009/07/halfmask.php&#34;&gt;experimenting with a half-masking technique&lt;/a&gt;. The method partially obscures the password by placing a few blurred characters in the background so that the characters are not easily read by someone looking over the user&amp;rsquo;s shoulder. This seems like an interesting idea. The problem for me is that I can&amp;rsquo;t say that the characters are easily read by me either. Can you make out the password in the screenshot above? It&amp;rsquo;s hard to, I would argue. But, I&amp;rsquo;m one of those people who has trouble with the more twisted captchas or those with too much background noise. My eyesight is not bad, mind you, I just interpret some of the characters more creatively I guess. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interesting idea uses a behavior that is typical in mobile phones, which masks the typed character after it is displayed briefly in the input for a specified time, or after the user enters a subsequent character. This is a terrific behavior in phones because the character is completely visible to the user. I guess it could argued that it could still be read over the user&amp;rsquo;s shoulder, however. You can try that solution in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.decaf.de/2009/07/iphone-like-password-fields-using-jquery/&#34;&gt;iPhone-like passwords using jquery&lt;/a&gt; post on the Decaf blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both are interesting solutions to a problem that might be a minor nuisance to some users (although I would argue that captcha is a much bigger one to me). But my opinion is that simply having a toggle to hide/show the password clearly might be an even simpler approach. For users in public places, the input might be masked, but when they&amp;rsquo;re alone they can keep it in the clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Chris Dary also pointed to his &lt;a href=&#34;http://lab.arc90.com/2009/07/hashmask.php&#34;&gt;HashMask&lt;/a&gt; experiment at arc90, which we discuss below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lab.arc90.com/2009/07/halfmask.php&#34;&gt;http://lab.arc90.com/2009/07/halfmask.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>