<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fair Use on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/fair-use/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fair Use on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/fair-use/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Plagiarism Vs. Inspiration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/plagiarism-vs-inspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/plagiarism-vs-inspiration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recent &lt;a href=&#34;../design/skittles.html&#34;&gt;Skittles launch&lt;/a&gt;, which appropriated Modernista&#39;s idea, and the &lt;a href=&#34;milton-glaser-shepard-fairey-and-plagiarism.html&#34;&gt;Shepard Fairey law suit&lt;/a&gt;, which questions whether or not the artist has a first ammendment right to use images appropriated from an AP photohjournalist, is making me think more and more about the issue of plagiarism vs. inspiration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know who was involved with the making of the Skittles site, but it reminds me of how BBDO ripped off Spike Jonze&#39;s &#34;Full Flared&#34; video for its Skittles commercials. If, for instance, Modernista designed Skittles or Jonze directed the Snickers ad, I wouldn&#39;t be bothered. But this just feels like someone is plagiarizing and being lazy. I don&#39;t know how a creative agency can be this blatant and not think they&#39;re going to get called out for it. What&#39;s bothersome in all of this is that credit is not given to the original, permission is not granted I am sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m a firm believer in finding inspiration from others&#39; work, but only if the concept and design is altered significantly enough that it becomes one&#39;s own and only marginally refers to the original. What Fairey does, in my opinion, pales in comparison to what these ad agencies are doing, and it can be debated whether or not his work is too close to the original and falls into the rules for fair use. I think it&#39;s pretty close and my opinion on that has been changing pretty regularly on the Fairey issue. What makes the issue sticky is that it is both art and it results in a commercial product. I think it would be less likely to be troublesome if the result was simply some form of communication or a more pure attempt at free speech. But the commercial aspect alters that view of the copy in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case this is an issue that re-emerges constantly and becomes more and more laborious for me to think about and discuss each time it arises. &lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milton Glaser on Shepard Fairey and Plagiarism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/milton-glaser-shepard-fairey-and-plagiarism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/milton-glaser-shepard-fairey-and-plagiarism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.printmag.com/design_articles/MiltonGlaseronShepardFairey/tabid/492/Default.aspx&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/glaser-on-fairey.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Print Magazine &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.printmag.com/design_articles/MiltonGlaseronShepardFairey/tabid/492/Default.aspx&#34;&gt;interviews Milton Glaser to discuss Shepard Fairey&lt;/a&gt; and the topic of appropriation and plagiarism. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar, Fairey is the graffiti artist responsible for such iconic imagery as the ubiquitous Andre OBEY tag and the Obama Hope image. Glaser had this to say, on the topic of copying other artists&amp;rsquo; work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The process of looking back at the past is very accepted in our business—the difference is when you take something without adding anything to the conversation. &amp;hellip; I think unless you’re modifying it and making it your own, you’re on very tenuous ground. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He makes the finer point that copying ideas and appropriating imagery is not patently wrong. To the contrary, it is the basis for a lot of work that is celebrated. The difference comes in appropriating and making one&amp;rsquo;s own. He points out the danger the idea of copying poses to future designers and artists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a dangerous example for students, if they see that appropriating people’s work is the path to success. Simply reproducing the work of others robs you of your imagination and form-making abilities. You’re not developing the muscularity you need to invent your own ideas. &amp;hellip; But it’s important for students to understand that any idea can be exploited, but not simply reproduced. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, for one, don&amp;rsquo;t sit in judgement of Shepard Fairey&amp;rsquo;s work because I find the idea of what he does, the mass underground distribution of iconic imagery in the form of an ilegal activity for spreading one&amp;rsquo;s art, to be interesting for that controversial aspect alone. Is it art or is it vandalism? Is it stealing or is it some sort of free speech that should be protected? But, I digress on that issue, only to share what I think is provocative. Getting back to Glaser&amp;rsquo;s point, if in the realm of design we tend to be gray on the issue of copying ideas or actual form without making a thing our own, what do we gain from that experience? Not very much, for not very long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might also want to check out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=101182453&#34;&gt;interview with Shepard Fairey on the Fresh Air show at NPR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.printmag.com/design_articles/MiltonGlaseronShepardFairey/tabid/492/Default.aspx&#34;&gt;http://www.printmag.com/design_articles/MiltonGlaseronShepardFairey/tabid/492/Default.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>