<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Professional Development on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/professional-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Professional Development on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/professional-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Give it five minutes</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/give-it-five-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/give-it-five-minutes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m certainly no stranger to being opinionated and argumentative. I&#39;ve put my foot in my mouth a few times by pushing back on others&#39; ideas, and am well aware that being quick to react can be detrimental. The older I get, the more I realize how little I know and how much more time I need to spend thinking after listening, before I open my mouth or start to type to respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admire Jason Fried&#39;s recent blog post, &lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Give it five minutes.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; In it, he writes candidly about the issue of pushing back on ideas, starting from an exchange he had with Richard Saul Wurman, where the two had given talks at the same event. Wurman approached Fried to congratulate him, and Fried replied by telling Wurman what he disagreed with about his talk. The take away from that exchange was that Wurman taught Fried to stop and think, to give ideas a chance before challenging them with little respect or consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like this bit of advice from Fried, who turned that lesson into an opportunity to grow personally, and share what he learned from that exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;There are two things in this world that take no skill: 1. Spending other people’s money and 2. Dismissing an idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dismissing an idea is so easy because it doesn’t involve any work. You can scoff at it. You can ignore it. You can puff some smoke at it. That’s easy. The hard thing to do is protect it, think about it, let it marinate, explore it, riff on it, and try it. The right idea could start out life as the wrong idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So next time you hear something, or someone, talk about an idea, pitch an idea, or suggest an idea, give it five minutes. Think about it a little bit before pushing back, before saying it’s too hard or it’s too much work. Those things may be true, but there may be another truth in there too: It may be worth it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a fantastic little Jonathan Ive anecdote in there as well, where Ive explains Steve Jobs&#39; respect for the fragility of ideas, the best of which can start out naive, but lead to beautiful things if they&#39;re allowed the time and space to be explored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some of the best products can grow out of one&#39;s work done in isolation, the ideas need to be shared to grow into products. Stifling others&#39; ideas with immediate push back is not only a quick way to alienate your team, but squashing them too early can really do the most harm to you, by depriving you from seeing what it might become. This is one of those rare reminders that with maturity, hopefully we can learn to become more humble and grow. We just have to be open to the ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes&#34;&gt;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seth Godin on the Importance of Domain Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/seth-godin-importance-domain-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/seth-godin-importance-domain-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seth Godin&#39;s blog often talks about where successful ideas come from, and in this post talks about &lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/08/bypassing-the-leap.html&#34;&gt;bypassing the need to make huge leaps in innovation&lt;/a&gt; by synthesizing what we know and have learned from history, using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.appleinsider.com/articles/10/01/09/palm_ceo_former_apple_exec_says_hes_never_used_an_iphone.html&#34;&gt;Palm as the cautionary tale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;It&#39;s not enough to be aware of the domain you&#39;re working in, you need to understand it. Noticing things and being curious about how they work is the single most common trait I see in creative people. Once you can break the components down, you can put them back together into something brand new.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why we are constantly doing competitive monitoring and analysis of the products in the industries we work in. At times I feel kind of crazed signing up for betas out there, because the speed at which they appear now is overwhelming. I just have to remind myself that it&#39;s ok to spend the time if there&#39;s some research value, and then quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether we&#39;re just looking at the landscape from a high level, or deeply investigating and deconstructing how things work, continually expanding or improving domain knowledge is always going to be an important activity for us as designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/08/bypassing-the-leap.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Fsethsmainblog+%28Seth%27s+Blog%29&#34;&gt;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/08/bypassing-the-leap.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Fsethsmainblog+%28Seth%27s+Blog%29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why The Valley Wants Designers That Can Code</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/why-valley-wants-designers-can-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/why-valley-wants-designers-can-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jared Spool talks about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2011/05/31/why-the-valley-wants-designers-that-can-code/&#34;&gt;why designers who code are popular in Silicon Valley&lt;/a&gt; right now, and for the most part, it boils down to this. Small software and web startups value and are able to use a broader range of skillsets, because one of the highest priorities, especially for bootstrapped startups, is to ship while lean on resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jared notes that those who don&#39;t think designers should know how to code say this dilutes the designer&#39;s value. I think we&#39;re talking both interaction designers and visual designers here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main point for me is that particular organizations favor someone more M-shaped than T-shaped, which is to say, they need to be deeper in more than one set of skills. This is true of more types of organizations than just small startups, but the main idea is that multi-role people &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; valued in organizations that are open to having  a person who can execute on a diverse set of responsibilities, even if they&#39;re viewed as &amp;quot;diluted&amp;quot; in terms of being less deep in one area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll say this. I started out doing interface design and development work on databases in-house in a corporation. Early on in my career, I envied the people who got to work on the sexy, high-profile projects and made the switch to doing front end-development at an agency. Unsatisfied with that, I went back in-house doing both design and development, and then envied the design side, and went to a company to do interaction design only. I&#39;ve never been satisfied in a silo, and have been happiest being involved across a project. I&#39;ve found that working on both ends as a designer and developer to be ideal for me, even if the development is only front-end development and prototyping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I don&#39;t think it is particularly easy to find a home when you&#39;re more M than T-shaped. Certain types of organizations won&#39;t even let you interview for more than one type of role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve spoken to quite a few people looking to make a shift from one side to another over the years. It&#39;s kind of easy to recognize an M-shaped person. They may have worked in small organizations that gave them more room to flex their muscles outside of their role, or they may be freelancers that get to and maybe have to do design and development. For whatever reason, that varied experience can make it hard for them to find the right home and to convince hiring people to consider a cross-disciplinary role to fit them into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I think what Jared is talking about could be very helpful to both the budding UX designers out there, and those considering making a change in role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems obvious to say, but if you can already do some development and you want to use it, you might look for an organization that values it. Small startups or in-house positions with small development organizations where multi-role people are valued is a good start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can&#39;t do some kind of code, at least learn HTML5, CSS and a little Javascript, and maybe some other server-side scripting languages. If you can&#39;t convince your organization to use you in that capacity, then demonstrate your skill doing prototypes in code when the opportunity presents itself, and keep your skills sharp. When there seems like no way to flex your development muscles in your current job, work on personal projects continually to stay sharp and relevant!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2011/05/31/why-the-valley-wants-designers-that-can-code/&#34;&gt;Read more at UIE&lt;/a&gt;. Interested in learning to code for the web? There are &lt;a href=&#34;../wiki/learn-code.html&#34;&gt;some resources for that here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2011/05/31/why-the-valley-wants-designers-that-can-code/&#34;&gt;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2011/05/31/why-the-valley-wants-designers-that-can-code/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nine Essential Characteristics of Good UX Designers</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/nine-essential-characteristics-good-ux-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/nine-essential-characteristics-good-ux-designers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fred Beecher wrote what he thinks are the nine essential characteristics you must possess to make a good software user experience designer, in reaction to a comment made about skills an IA should possess. It&#39;s an excellent read for those listing qualifications and evaluating UX Designers for hire, and a great list of qualities for job-seekers to demonstrate during interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Deep Understanding of Human Psychology &amp;amp; Research Methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Competence in the Basics of Graphic Design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An Awareness of and Interest in Technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verbal &amp;amp; Visual Communication Skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moderate Familiarity with Business, Deep Familiarity with Your Business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Ability to Quickly Learn a Subject Matter Area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mediation, Facilitation, &amp;amp; Translation Skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creativity &amp;amp; Vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elizabeth Buie also added a familiarity with HCI literature, and undboubtedly with HCI history, which I think should be there as well. For descriptions of each characteristic &lt;a href=&#34;http://userexperience.evantageconsulting.com/2009/07/characteristics-good-ux-designers/&#34;&gt;read the full article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://userexperience.evantageconsulting.com/2009/07/characteristics-good-ux-designers/&#34;&gt;http://userexperience.evantageconsulting.com/2009/07/characteristics-good-ux-designers/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So you&#39;re thinking about becoming a designer?</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/so-youre-thinking-about-becoming-designer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/so-youre-thinking-about-becoming-designer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Liz Danzico sought out the advice of digital designers and designer conspirers to ask them to respond to the following statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;So you’re thinking about becoming a designer? If I could tell you only one thing about going into the field, my advice would be ___________ .&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The suggestions ranged from the philosophical to the pragmatic. Below are the ones that resounded with me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Focus on empathy and understanding problems&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;martop1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Being empathetic helps designers create things that move people.&lt;br /&gt;
- Jennifer Bove&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t just fall in love with a solution and go full force and making it look great, but really make sure that whatever you design is filling a need in the world and has a purpose.&lt;br /&gt;
- Whitney Hess
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to design, I&#39;m a big believer in empathy, as are most IA/IXD&#39;s who invest in user research. Jennifer Bove&#39;s video focusses on this. Whitney Hess also hits on a similar point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=5802242&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=5802242&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to finding solutions for people, I&#39;m also a fan of JM Spool&#39;s &#34;don&#39;t do anything stupid, don&#39;t do anything clever,&#34; although it&#39;s more about finding the middle ground between clever and stupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Embrace the unfamiliar to innovate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;martop1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be a champion of effortful study, the act of constantly tackling problems and challenges that lie at the very edge of your ability.&lt;br /&gt;
- Ryan Sims&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m also a big fan of taking on new work that is unfamiliar in order to be &lt;a href=&#34;tags/innovation.html&#34;&gt;innovative&lt;/a&gt; and improve one&#39;s skills. I love what Bill Buxton and Paula  Scher have to say on this topic. Ryan Sims, also states it rather succinctly and points out that there will be dues to pay if you want the experience and wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=5802338&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=5802338&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Be passionate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;martop1&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have undying, unending passion for what it is you&#39;re doing. You&#39;ll run up against people who don&#39;t understand, who don&#39;t want to pay for it, who don&#39;t respect it. Ultimately none of that matters if you have the passion to make that happen.&lt;br /&gt;
- John Kolko&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I think the thing that I agree with most, whether it has to do with design or knitting or whatever you do, is that you have to be passionate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;307&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=5802291&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=5802291&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;307&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&#39;t believe that passion is important, or that you can&#39;t get you far without &lt;em&gt;talent&lt;/em&gt;, I suggest watching &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0878134/&#34;&gt;A Man Named Pearl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, the documentary about a self-taught topiary artist who, prompted by a bigoted comment,  proves to everyone around him that hard work and passion are what matter.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://interactiondesign.sva.edu/blog/entry/video_notes_from_the_field/&#34;&gt;http://interactiondesign.sva.edu/blog/entry/video_notes_from_the_field/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>