<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Must Read on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/must-read/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Must Read on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/must-read/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation Skills Considered Harmful</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/presentation-skills-considered-harmful/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/presentation-skills-considered-harmful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t like public speaking. I love talking to people one to one and in very small groups. But public speaking and me don&#39;t mix, and if you&#39;ve ever seen me speak, you probably agree. In the handful of times that I have spoken publicly, I think only two were really worth coming to see and hear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe the only reason the worthwhile talks were not utter failures was because I had something to share that I think people wanted to hear, and could get something out of. They really had little to do with me. I think those talks had more to do with what the audience could do with what I shared. My passion about the topic let me forget about myself until I was just basically just giving people something they wanted instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathy Sierra is one of the people whose articles I like to read and presentations I like to watch, because I come away with ideas that I feel I can do something with. There&#39;s something almost pragmatic to me about what she shares. Don&#39;t get me wrong though, she is a charismatic, funny, and super smart speaker. But &lt;a href=&#34;http://seriouspony.com/blog/2013/10/4/presentation-skills-considered-harmful&#34;&gt;her post about public speaking and presentation skills&lt;/a&gt; is useful to me as someone who hates public speaking, and always feels bad turning down the invitation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s the message: If you imagine that your role in speaking is to be the delivery mechanism for the message/story/whatever, you become the UI for the User Experience of that exchange between you and the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I think this thought sums up what the role is about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not really about the user experience they have during your presentation. Like your presentation, their experience of it is also just the enabler for something bigger. Because what matters most is NOT the UX but the POST-UX UX. What happens after and as a result of the user experience?  ... What happens after what happens happens? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When they walk away from the user experience, then what? Are they different? Are they a little smarter? Are they a little more energized? Are they a little more capable? Are they a little more likely to talk to others about it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe there&#39;s hope for me after all? I like this idea of the post-UX-UX, when it comes to products or presentations. At the end of the day, while the delivery and execution are very important, your presentation skill holds much less weight than how you&#39;ve impacted the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this brings me back to why I got into working in this field to begin with. I started professional life working on libraries, and wanting to help people find information that helps them do things that fulfill needs in the real world, outside of the experience of using the library. What I do still comes down to that, and I guess public speaking should be no different. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m still afraid of being the awkward kid at the head of the class, even if I know the material. But maybe next time, I&#39;ll just imagine myself as the UI, and the rest will fall away. &lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://seriouspony.com/blog/2013/10/4/presentation-skills-considered-harmful&#34;&gt;http://seriouspony.com/blog/2013/10/4/presentation-skills-considered-harmful&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pace</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/pace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/everything-in-its-right-pace/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2576&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt503901bbde9e1_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hannah Donovan&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/everything-in-its-right-pace/&#34;&gt;essay in A List Apart&lt;/a&gt; considers the issue of pace of delivery of information in web products. In a world where information is streamed constantly to us if we allow it, sometimes a slower pace, selective or scant data delivery, and better signal to noise is more appropriate and valuable. Context, medium, and place of use are important factors for determining delivery and pace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been interested in the slow movement in recent years, as it relates to sustainable living, slow design, slow food, and the 1K Movement. In the summer of 2011, I was fortunate enough to experience a very special meal on a very small farm/restaurant in Italy&#39;s Le Marche region. All the food and drink prepared is grown on the farm or sourced hyper-locally, from meat and vegetables, to wine—everything within 1 kilometer. It was the most profound eating experience of my life. Little bits and pieces of that day have made me think about how my approach to work and life have become more and more connected to each other, and how much of an impact one&#39;s production and consumption decisions have on the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a design and lifestyle perspective, I like to reference this summary of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slow_Movement&#34;&gt;philosophy of the Slow Movement&lt;/a&gt; by Professor Guttorm Fløistad, found on Wikipedia:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;The only thing for certain is that everything changes. The rate of change increases. If you want to hang on you better speed up. That is the message of today. It could however be useful to remind everyone that &lt;strong&gt;our basic needs never change&lt;/strong&gt;. The need to be seen and appreciated! It is the need to belong. The need for nearness and care, and for a little love! This is given only through slowness in human relations. In order to master changes, we have to recover slowness, reflection and togetherness. There we will find real renewal.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a bit touchy-feely, and lives entirely in the center of Maslow&#39;s Heirarchy of Needs. But the idea of taking a holistic approach to fulfilling needs in all things, provides the basis for actually satisfying them in other ways up the triangle. Specifically, I&#39;m thinking of the idea of fulfilling the needs for esteem and self-actualization as one example. In a scenario where speed and volume has become the norm, how has that situation impacted our lives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like how Donovan tells the story of learning from the experience at &lt;a href=&#34;http://last.fm/&#34;&gt;Last.fm&lt;/a&gt; to imagine &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thisismyjam.com/&#34;&gt;This is My Jam&lt;/a&gt;, a product that goes the other way, and focuses on the quality and value of the experience, using pace as the point of pivot. I like this approach. I have mostly stopped consuming from the firehose, and seek out the products that deliver a signal that I get more value from, more satisfaction, or that fulfill my basic needs with less fluff and noise. The decision to work with a product and team that follows those ideals is important to me as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beth Meredith and Eric Storm &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.create-the-good-life.com/slow_design.html&#34;&gt;summarize the concept of Slow Design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Slow Design is a democratic and holistic design approach for creating appropriately tailored solutions for the long-term well being of people and the planet. To this end, Slow Design seeks out positive synergies between the elements in a system, celebrates diversity and regionalism, and cultivates meaningful relationships that add richness to life.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Slow Movement is not just a lifestyle choice, but as designers, we can choose to have an impact on the world based on these ideals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/everything-in-its-right-pace/&#34;&gt;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/everything-in-its-right-pace/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your app is a collection of tiny details</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/your-app-collection-tiny-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/your-app-collection-tiny-details/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;t14&#34;&gt;&#34;Getting the details right is the difference between something that delights, and something customers tolerate.&#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8212;Jeff Atwood&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/05/this-is-all-your-app-is-a-collection-of-tiny-details.html&#34;&gt;Jeff Atwood&#39;s article about cat feeders&lt;/a&gt; right away, because it really is 90% about a cat product. It&#39;s also a terrific demonstration of what he&#39;s saying above. The first version of the product, a cat feeder, served a core need well enough for him to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satisficing&#34;&gt;satisfice&lt;/a&gt; with its shortcomings because the net return in time savings and improved quality of life, for him anyway, was absolutely worth it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The punchline is this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure you&#39;re first getting the primary function more or less right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the work of listening to users every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refine the details of your product based on their feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening to the opinions expressed by customers, obsessing over the details, and getting them right in the design is necessary and hard. But over time, if the points of pain are incrementally addressed and the design improved, the collection of those well-thought-out details embody a better experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get better slowly, but &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; get better. Suck it up and feel your users&#39; pain. Assure them that you&#39;re listening by sweating the details. &lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/05/this-is-all-your-app-is-a-collection-of-tiny-details.html&#34;&gt;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/05/this-is-all-your-app-is-a-collection-of-tiny-details.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letting Go</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/letting-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two great slides from Yiibu&#39;s presentation, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/yiibu/letting-go-9109114&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;Letting Go&lt;/a&gt;, a talk about design in an time of increasing disruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6170/6188891324_71eb68e152_z.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#34;Issuing your customers with something that is rough, incomplete, and possibly even substandard seems counterintuitive but there is growing evidence that people don&#39;t necessarily want the perfect product. They prefer to deal with something ragged around the edges that they can adapt or improve.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8212;  Martin Thomas in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Loose-Future-Business-Letting-Go/dp/0755361555&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&#34;Loose: The Future of Business is Letting Go&#34;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6127/6189715023_b5fc1f1b73_z.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#34;The best designs will set the stage, but stop short of fully defining the experience.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8212; Adam Silver, Frog Design&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awesome presentation deck. Would have loved to see and hear it in person. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/yiibu/letting-go-9109114&#34;&gt;See the full presentation here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Photo credits: &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/tiseb/13541804&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/hodac/2243470147&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/yiibu/letting-go-9109114&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/yiibu/letting-go-9109114&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caterina Fake on why working hard is overrated</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/caterina-fake-why-working-hard-overrated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/caterina-fake-why-working-hard-overrated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caterina.net/archive/001196.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1902&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4ac372308eb1f.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Caterina Fake, founder of Flickr and Hunch, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caterina.net/archive/001196.html&#34;&gt;talks about why working hard isn&amp;rsquo;t as important as working on the right things&lt;/a&gt;. Or as I once heard on a cartoon as a kid&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;you have to work smarter not harder.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much more important than working hard is knowing how to find the right thing to work on. Paying attention to what is going on in the world. Seeing patterns. Seeing things as they are rather than how you want them to be. Being able to read what people want. Putting yourself in the right place where information is flowing freely and interesting new juxtapositions can be seen. But you can save yourself a lot of time by working on the right thing. Working hard, even, if that&amp;rsquo;s what you like to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved that paragraph. I also loved the anecdote about Watson and Crick, the scientists who discovered the structure of DNA, and how their discoveries didn&amp;rsquo;t come from hard work, as much as from being in the world thinking, experiencing, allowing ideas to happen. I think there&amp;rsquo;s a valuable nugget in there to product developers about that space that&amp;rsquo;s sometimes needed for creativity that isn&amp;rsquo;t valued enough and understood. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating features to compete, building, and accretion without the relentlessness to say no and focus on the right things isn&amp;rsquo;t the path to quality and excellence. The right path in product development is kind of like finding the right path in life. Asking the hard questions about the things that matter and prioritizing effort around those things &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; hard work. But it&amp;rsquo;s not working hard on the wrong problems, for the sake of working or existing. It&amp;rsquo;s defining what is meaningful and pursuing those thing with fervor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/1951-so-often-people-are-working-hard-at-the-wrong&#34;&gt;37signals&lt;/a&gt; for the link. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caterina.net/archive/001196.html&#34;&gt;Read more at Caterina.net&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caterina.net/archive/001196.html&#34;&gt;http://www.caterina.net/archive/001196.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Buxton on How to Keep Innovating</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/bill-buxton-how-keep-innovating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/bill-buxton-how-keep-innovating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In BusinessWeek, Bill Buxton discusses &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessweek.com/innovate/content/feb2009/id20090218_337947.htm&#34;&gt;how to keep innovating&lt;/a&gt;, with the main idea being that you can continue to cultivate creativity and innovation by finding new things that you have a passion for. He suggests that when you get good enough at a thing, you should find something else to be passionate about, and commit and throw yourself into learning how to do it. You&#39;ll be bad at it at first, but the experience of learning something new, no matter how bad you are at it at first, may affect your creativity in positive ways that you won&#39;t realize until you experience it. In some cases, they may inform what you are already expert at, and in others lead you in entirely new and surprising directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discussion reminds me of Paula Scher&#39;s talk focussing on &lt;a href=&#34;paula-scher-gets-serious-ted.html&#34;&gt;serious versus solemn design&lt;/a&gt; at TED. Scher spoke about the different times in her career where she was able to be most innovative in her craft, and the thing that was common in each case was that she was doing something new--something she didn&#39;t know much about when she started that particular project. The fact that one has no reference point or bearing can lead to innovative thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the same argument Buxton is making. I think Buxton is saying that the continued pursuit of new endeavors itself, is what can help cultivate one&#39;s creativity and create the pre-conditions for innovation. I&#39;m sure a lot of people who take up new hobbies and have the continuing need to learn see the obvious in this. This is one of the reasons I feel at home in a city where it is easy for me to start investigating and learning something new all the time. Being in a city isn&#39;t necessary, per se, but being able to get inspired and start doing something new is a hell of a lot easier for me here. This coupled with the fact that my wife and I homeschool our 8 year old son, which has lead me to dive deep on countless topics and project that I would never have held my interest in the past. If you read my personal blog, you know about my forays into toy making, game design, character creation and storytelling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, the story is not new, but is a reminder for me that being well-rounded and having many interests is a good thing. In fact it&#39;s one of the top criteria I&#39;ve used when participating in the hiring of people.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessweek.com/innovate/content/feb2009/id20090218_337947.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.businessweek.com/innovate/content/feb2009/id20090218_337947.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Buxton on Innovation and the Long Nose Theory</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/bill-buxton-innovation-and-long-nose-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/bill-buxton-innovation-and-long-nose-theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://boltpeters.com/blog/?p=31&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1200&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt48079d9619afd.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bolt|Peters &lt;a href=&#34;http://boltpeters.com/blog/?p=31&#34;&gt;summarizes Bill Buxton&amp;rsquo;s talk&lt;/a&gt; at CHI 2008, which is focussed largely around his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessweek.com/innovate/content/jan2008/id2008012_297369.htm&#34;&gt;theory of long nose&lt;/a&gt;. The article in BusinessWeek describes the danger of trying to innovate around the long tail theory alone, and attempts to create awareness for this other phenomenon which he calls the long nose. The theory describes how the bulk of innovation is low-amplitude and takes place over a long period of time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;[T]he bulk of innovation behind the latest &amp;ldquo;wow&amp;rdquo; moment (multi-touch on the iPhone, for example) is also low-amplitude and takes place over a long period—but well before the &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; idea has become generally known, much less reached the tipping point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of the long, often slow process of arriving at that critical point of acceptance or realization, Buxton referenced in his Chi talk the work of Benvenuto Cellini. Cellini was an Italian Renaissance painter and craftsman who, Buxton pointed out, worked on a single sculpture over the course of seven years. By craft, he wasn&amp;rsquo;t a sculptor, but he was able to invest in this long term engagement, driven by a heady pursuit that ended in the creation of a masterpiece, &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image:PerseusSignoriaStatue.jpg&#34;&gt;Perseus with the Head of Medusa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buxton&amp;rsquo;s long nose theory asks us to focus on refining existing tools as much as creating new ones. He also reminds us to recall and understand the history of what has been done in the past. This knowledge of the history of design, and the refinement of those ideas, he argues, is what leads to the acceptance of innovation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make this point, he references the Marcel Proust quote below when he discusses his tongue-in-cheek press release calling the iPhone a re-release of the Newton:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The only true voyage of discovery is not to go to new places, but to have other eyes.” Basically, you don’t transform things by doing them from scratch, but by seeing them through different eyes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His point here is that the lessons learned and the refinement of ideas introduced in the Newton years ago, and in the research on input devices and touch screens must have certainly played a part in the evolution of ideas leading to the iPhone. This was a slow evolution, and not an overnight innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buxton also references the 30 year history of the introduction of the idea of the mouse with Doug Englebart&amp;rsquo;s 1965 demonstration to the broad acceptance of the input device in the mainstream when Microsoft released Windows 95. He goes on to say that this length of time is common&amp;ndash;that any technological innovation &amp;ldquo;that is going to have significant impact over the next 10 years is already at least 10 years old.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final message of the long nose is that refinement, not invention, is the bulk of the work and creativity required for innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://boltpeters.com/blog/?p=31&#34;&gt;http://boltpeters.com/blog/?p=31&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple&#39;s Design process</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/apples-design-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/apples-design-process/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michael Lopp, Senior Engineering Manager at Apple discussed Apple&#39;s design process at a presentation given at SXSW. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessweek.com/the_thread/techbeat/archives/2008/03/apples_design_p.html&#34;&gt;Business Week summarized the points&lt;/a&gt;, excerpted below. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Pixel Perfect Mockups&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This, Lopp admitted, causes a huge amount of work and takes an enormous amount of time. But, he added, “it removes all ambiguity.” That might add time up front, but it removes the need to correct mistakes later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10 to 3 to 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Apple designers come up with 10 entirely different mock ups of any new feature. Not, Lopp said, &#34;seven in order to make three look good&#34;, which seems to be a fairly standard practice elsewhere. They&#39;ll take ten, and give themselves room to design without restriction. Later they whittle that number to three, spend more months on those three and then finally end up with one strong decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paired Design Meetings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This was really interesting. Every week, the teams have two meetings. One in which to brainstorm, to forget about constraints and think freely. As Lopp put it: to &#34;go crazy&#34;. Then they also hold a production meeting, an entirely separate but equally regular meeting which is the other&#39;s antithesis. Here, the designers and engineers are required to nail everything down, to work out how this crazy idea might actually work. This process and organization continues throughout the development of any app, though of course the balance shifts as the app progresses. But keeping an option for creative thought even at a late stage is really smart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pony Meeting&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This refers to a story Lopp told earlier in the session, in which he described the process of a senior manager outlining what they wanted from any new application: &#34;I want WYSIWYG... I want it to support major browsers... I want it to reflect the spirit of the company.&#34; Or, as Lopp put it: &#34;I want a pony!&#34; He added: &#34;Who doesn&#39;t? A pony is gorgeous!&#34; The problem, he said, is that these people are describing what they think they want. And even if they&#39;re misguided, they, as the ones signing the checks, really cannot be ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution, he described, is to take the best ideas from the paired design meetings and present those to leadership, who might just decide that some of those ideas are, in fact, their longed-for ponies. In this way, the ponies morph into deliverables. And the C-suite, who are quite reasonable in wanting to know what designers are up to, and absolutely entitled to want to have a say in what&#39;s going on, are involved and included. And that helps to ensure that there are no nasty mistakes down the line.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to this article, I heard someone in my office referring to dream features as ponies.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessweek.com/the_thread/techbeat/archives/2008/03/apples_design_p.html&#34;&gt;http://www.businessweek.com/the_thread/techbeat/archives/2008/03/apples_design_p.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shneiderman&#39;s Eight Golden Rules of Interface Design</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/shneidermans-eight-golden-rules-interface-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/shneidermans-eight-golden-rules-interface-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben Shneiderman&#39;s Eight Golden Rules of Interface Design are user interface design rules described in &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321197860?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=urlgreyhot-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0321197860&#34;&gt;Designing the User Interface: Strategies for Effective Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=urlgreyhot-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=0321197860&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. Shneiderman proposed this collection of principles that are derived heuristically from experience and applicable in most interactive systems after being properly refined, extended, and interpreted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To improve the usability of an application it is important to have a well designed interface and these &#34;Eight Golden Rules of Interface Design&#34; are claimed to be a guide to good interaction design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Strive for consistency&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Consistent sequences of actions should be required in similar situations; identical terminology should be used in prompts, menus, and help screens; and consistent commands should be employed throughout.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Enable frequent users to use shortcuts&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;As the frequency of use increases, so do the user&#39;s desires to reduce the number of interactions and to increase the pace of interaction. Abbreviations, function keys, hidden commands, and macro facilities are very helpful to an expert user.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Offer informative feedback&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;For every operator action, there should be some system feedback. For frequent and minor actions, the response can be modest, while for infrequent and major actions, the response should be more substantial.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Design dialog to yield closure&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Sequences of actions should be organized into groups with a beginning, middle, and end. The informative feedback at the completion of a group of actions gives the operators the satisfaction of accomplishment, a sense of relief, the signal to drop contingency plans and options from their minds, and an indication that the way is clear to prepare for the next group of actions.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Offer simple error handling&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;As much as possible, design the system so the user cannot make a serious error. If an error is made, the system should be able to detect the error and offer simple, comprehensible mechanisms for handling the error.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Permit easy reversal of actions&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;This feature relieves anxiety, since the user knows that errors can be undone; it thus encourages exploration of unfamiliar options. The units of reversibility may be a single action, a data entry, or a complete group of actions.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Support internal locus of control&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Experienced operators strongly desire the sense that they are in charge of the system and that the system responds to their actions. Design the system to make users the initiators of actions rather than the responders.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Reduce short-term memory load&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;The limitation of human information processing in short-term memory requires that displays be kept simple, multiple page displays be consolidated, window-motion frequency be reduced, and sufficient training time be allotted for codes, mnemonics, and sequences of actions. &lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia contributors, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shneiderman&#39;s_rules_for_design&#34; class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&#34;Shneiderman&#39;s rules for design,&#34;&lt;/a&gt; Wikipedia, The Free Encyclopedia, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Plagiarism&amp;amp;oldid=5139350&#34; title=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Plagiarism&amp;amp;oldid=5139350&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Plagiarism&amp;amp;oldid=5139350&lt;/a&gt; (accessed January 17, 2008).&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321197860?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=urlgreyhot-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0321197860&#34;&gt;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321197860?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=urlgreyhot-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0321197860&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>