<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Play on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/play/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Play on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/play/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Enjoyable User Interfaces: Lessons learned from computer games</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/designing-enjoyable-user-interfaces-lessons-learned-computer-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/designing-enjoyable-user-interfaces-lessons-learned-computer-games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I find inspiration in the literature that examines &lt;a href=&#34;tags/games.html&#34;&gt;games&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;tags/play.html&#34;&gt;play&lt;/a&gt; as factors in creating delightful and engaging experiences. I like to think of how this applies to products outside of the video gaming industry. I&#39;ve had Thomas Malone&#39;s 1981 paper, &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=800049.801756&#34;&gt;Heuristics for Designing Enjoyable Interfaces: Lessons from computer games&lt;/a&gt;&#34; on my desk for a while. I finally got around to reading it and found some interesting ideas that resonated with me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper asks why users find games captivating and proposes guidelines for designing enjoyable systems. What I found relevant for interface design are Malone&#39;s observations about the experience with toys versus tools, and how to incorporate elements of game play to make tools more enjoyable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the distinctions he makes is that when using tools, their interfaces tend to become virtually invisible, to allow the user to focus attention on tasks that satisfy their external needs and goals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think all tools become invisible, but well-designed, efficient interfaces for business software tend to feel this way. I also think of it this way&amp;#8212;I don&#39;t go to the library to experience the library, I go to satisfy a need external to that physical place. The collection of the building, its contents, and it&#39;s staff are the tool, and more importantly they are simply a means to an end. The same is true of research databases or search engines. Most business software is focussed on fulfilling needs and goals, and the ones that I&#39;ve used that feel efficient tend to have interfaces that fall away so I can focus on tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re using tools during large portions of our work day, and to some extent, for power users, their utility sometimes makes them boring, and we seek out ways to find challenges using them. I found this passage particularly relevant to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a sense, a good game is intentionally made difficult to play, but a tool should be made as easy as possible to use. This distinction helps explain why some users of complex system may enjoy mastering tools that are extremely difficult to use. To the extent that these users are treating the systems as toys rather than tools, the difficulty increases the challenge and therefore the pleasure of using the systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting idea, although the conflict of simple versus complex presents a challenge. With tools, simple features are great for satisfying that 80% of users that need efficiency, but the 20% of power users can probably stand to go beyond that simpler experience. For them, the challenge is to find ways to unlock the hidden features beneath the iceberg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought of it as an iceberg representing features (excuse the cliche metaphor). The tip represents defaults and simple features for the majority of average users, and the larger mass below the surface represents power users and the often hidden, advanced features they use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/malone-graph.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conflict really has to do with power users. They want to push the tool to do more, they want to do advanced things. What Malone proposes in this case is to build in a progression of increasingly complex levels, and the analog in the business tools world would be access to advanced features, whether they be built into the interface itself, or require expert-level expertise to access those features. Have you ever looked at the  insanity of an MS Excel spreadsheet loaded with macros? That&#39;s the kind of analog we&#39;re talking about. Or in a SaaS environment, it&#39;s an API that gives access to data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are simpler examples from our world. Some IAs use these kinds of expert-level skills to get access to data from websites to come up with information graphics that help us visualize that information when wrestling with server log analysis or content inventories. I did a lot of this with tools like Graphviz in the past. In traditional design tools, it could mean pushing an advanced feature in graphics software to do things beyond what they were intended for. I&#39;m thinking of things like using JavaScript and Scriptographer in Illustrator, in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malone talks about building multi-layered systems in games in order to push advanced users to become more engaged and sustain their use with the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;[A] multi-layered system could not only help resolve the trade-off between simplicity and power. It could also enhance the challenge of using the system. Users could derive self-esteem and pleasure from successively mastering more and more advanced layers of the system, and this kind of pleasure might be more frequent if the layers are made an explicit part of the system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What he&#39;s talking about is common in games&amp;#8212;providing an ecosystem that supports leveling up with the purpose of providing incentive and reward via building up expertise and engagement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reminds me of what Kathy Sierra talks about in her talks on &lt;a href=&#34;kathy-sierra-creating-awesome-users.html&#34;&gt;creating awesome users&lt;/a&gt;. Experiences that progressively introduce and teach users about advanced features have a better chance of sustaining engagement with them.  This is something we all want in our products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the idea behind this. It becomes our responsibility as interface designers to know how to identify the tip of the iceberg to provide the simple defaults, but simplicity isn&#39;t all. We might keep the majority of our users working with the obvious features, but we want to provide the conditions that will let them become expert, and over time keep them feeling continually challenged and satisfied. Our challenge comes in knowing how to push the iceberg up, or teach the user how to swim deeper below the surface.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=800049.801756&#34;&gt;http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=800049.801756&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will Wright on Game Play and Education</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/will-wright-game-play-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/will-wright-game-play-and-education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/22670388&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/22670388&#34;&gt;Will Wright&amp;rsquo;s talk&lt;/a&gt; at the Summit on Science, Entertainment, and Education looks at how game play can be relevant to education. These are my notes from this talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How we process information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our basic model for processing and acting on data that we receive in the world looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Behavior&lt;br /&gt;
- Models (Predictive) ↑&lt;br /&gt;
- Schema (Abstractions) ↑&lt;br /&gt;
- Metaphors (Patterns) ↑&lt;br /&gt;
- Examples (Data) ↑&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How our minds work when we play games&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Games become relevant in education because they offer a more effective way to use and build knowledge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game play is about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- failing&lt;br /&gt;
- changing your model&lt;br /&gt;
- repeating&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game players, through experimentation and repeated failure, ramp their model of the game up over iterations of play. Their model becomes more complex as their understanding and ability to succeed increases over each interaction and learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wright tells a story about a pottery class, in which a teacher tells one group of students that their grade will be based on one single pot they are produced. The second group is told their grade will be based on the amount of pots they produce. The second group ended up with the highest grades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your work is based on building the most rather than creating the perfect work, you fail repeatedly, update your model, and produce the best work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What makes a good educational experience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wright applies what James Paul Gee lists as attributes for a good education experience and says these are the same for game play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- allow identity&lt;br /&gt;
- offer a reason to do it&lt;br /&gt;
- allow and mitigate risk&lt;br /&gt;
- encourage failure&lt;br /&gt;
- provide situated meanings: you&amp;rsquo;re learning for things you immediately need&lt;br /&gt;
- get you out of ordered problem solving&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Blurring the lines of maker/player&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to becoming effective tools for learning, the game community is blurring lines between the game ecology and the community. Social experiences afforded by games like Spore and LIttle Big Planet are good examples. Players become creators and contributors. Learning and creation and contribution are one and the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Thanks to Alex for pointing me to this vid.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/22670388&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/22670388&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playfulness, Usability, &amp; Context: The Three Pillars of a Delightful User Experience</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/playfulness-usability-context-three-pillars-delightful-user-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/playfulness-usability-context-three-pillars-delightful-user-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://userexperience.evantageconsulting.com/2009/09/playfulness-usability-context-delightful-user-experience/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1896&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4ab7c8d1441ca.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fred Beecher did an informal usability test of 2 conversion apps for the iPhone&amp;ndash;Convert and Covertbot&amp;ndash;and wrote up a thought provoking review regarding the relationship between playfulness and usability. Convertbot could be viewed as the more playful and whimsical of the 2 apps. He writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fun isn’t always the new usable. There are situations in which usability is more important than playfulness and those in which it’s the other way around. The delight that playfulness contributes to an experience depends on the context surrounding that experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[W]hile playfulness is undoubtedly an important new focus in user experience design, it’s not a panacea. User experience designers need to understand when playfulness is more effective than pure usability in inspiring delight and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fred observed that playfulness wasn&amp;rsquo;t always favored, but that &amp;ldquo;playfulness is more effective at certain levels of interaction and when there is a clear benefit to the user to learn the mechanics of that playfulness.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With regard to the use case of converting measurements, his small sample favored the less playful interface that required less to learn. Clearly the dimensions of frequency of use, and specificity of the use case are big factors. The quick information need when converting a measurement is nothing like exploring other kinds of information-rich environments. But the exception in his test points out that once she learned how to use the playful app, she preferred it better. What I&amp;rsquo;m wondering is, how do you determine when playful comes at too large a cost? What is the point where the burden of learning is outweighed by the benefit of use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s suggesting that ultimately UX designers need to understand the balance between playfulness and usability, and the goal is to deliver appropriate experiences that achieve sustainability while making users enjoy using the product. Again, I think audience, context, and use case seem to be key factors. &lt;a href=&#34;http://userexperience.evantageconsulting.com/2009/09/playfulness-usability-context-delightful-user-experience/&#34;&gt;Read the full article for more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://userexperience.evantageconsulting.com/2009/09/playfulness-usability-context-delightful-user-experience/&#34;&gt;http://userexperience.evantageconsulting.com/2009/09/playfulness-usability-context-delightful-user-experience/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone is all Fun and Games</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/iphone-all-fun-and-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/iphone-all-fun-and-games/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://johnnyholland.org/magazine/2009/08/the-iphone-is-not-easy-to-use-a-peek-into-the-future-of-experience-design/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1863&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4a8b1adb1092d.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fred Beecher wrote the excellent article &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://johnnyholland.org/magazine/2009/08/the-iphone-is-not-easy-to-use-a-peek-into-the-future-of-experience-design/&#34;&gt;The iPhone is Not Easy to Use: A New Direction for User Experience&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; on Johnny Holland to talk about why the iPhone is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; easy to use (at first), and why it changes the game for user experience designers. The examples illustrate how gestural interfaces are hidden, and lack the affordances of physical buttons. But the real story here is how the iPhone brings one thing to the experience that is more important than usability&amp;#8212;fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a user experience designer, I thought my job was to make things not suck. Until recently. As technology has evolved, human behavior has evolved along with it. Since behavior is the basis of user experience design, my job has evolved as well. Now, my job is to make things people love. At the 2009 IA Summit, Karl Fast articulated the value proposition of user experience design with sparkling clarity. “Engineers make things,” he said, “we make people love them.” And then he held up an iPhone as an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a crucial change, the importance of which cannot be overstated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s cool to me that creating pleasurable and fun experiences has become such a meme because the issue of usability has become less important when compared with the feel of the product. It&amp;rsquo;s always there in terms of principles, but I personally never want to lean on it as a crutch when designing. I think we sometimes equate usability with sterility and boredom. This is an odd thing to see myself write, since I&amp;rsquo;ve spent so much of my time trying to design usable things, or make things other people create more usable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the point about finding fun and exploiting the users&amp;rsquo; willingness to play are key. Having an 8 year old son that is really into games of every type (card, board, video, and schoolyard games) has helped me gain a different perspective on interface design. It&amp;rsquo;s not just in terms of seeing his immediate adaptability to the iPhone without the burden of reference to older interfaces. Most kids from pre-literacy learn to push and pull buttons and screens right away until something happens. But what I&amp;rsquo;ve been experiencing is how a child&amp;rsquo;s curiosity, continual exploration and willingness to absorb information and fail quicker to get to desired goals is such a positive thing in terms of the learning experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that has also immersed me in all of this fun learning is that we homeschool our son here in NYC. I&amp;rsquo;ve used gaming a great deal as a part of the learning experience with my son. I went through a period years ago when he was very young where I read &lt;em&gt;Got Game&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Everything Bad is Good for You&lt;/em&gt;. Our son talked us into getting him a GameBoy Advance so he could play with an older child, and my wife and I thought, &amp;ldquo;Why not make it part of his learning experience?&amp;rdquo; And we&amp;rsquo;ve been doing that with whatever he becomes interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s great that Fred mentions the game Fluxx. We&amp;rsquo;ve been playing this game all summer, and I bought blank cards to make our own rules. To my son, games aren&amp;rsquo;t just about accomplishing goals and earning stuff, they&amp;rsquo;re also largely about becoming an actor in the story and taking that experience to think of new games he wants to create. Fluxx is a great example of a game that lets users become more active participants in the rules. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MMPORG games immerse the gamer in a world where the player is part actor. SIM games like Spore bring God-like power to gamers. Games with creation mode like Little Big Planet allow users to re-cast the rules and experience. All of these create a different kind of user mentality that will be more interested in not only exploring the hidden, pleasurable world of easter egg interfaces, but who will also want to do more, explore more, and view computers as social and recreational tools as much if not more than tools to get things done. And that opens up the range of elements and methods you can use in interfaces.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are great challenges. On my last large project I spent a lot of time working on game interfaces to push creation of user generated content within a video watching community. A few years after leaving, I see that none of that experimental work got to see the light of day. But I found the experience of thinking about how playfulness and even play within the application could make the use more pleasurable and as a designer it was incredibly exciting. I&amp;rsquo;ve jumped into a totally different world&amp;#8212;enterprise software&amp;#8212;where the challenge to make the experience pleasurable is even greater, and the implementation of these types of UIs more subtle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think what I take away from Fred&amp;rsquo;s article is that we can&amp;rsquo;t overlook the value of play, and I would add that empathy for the different experience of the younger generations who value things and possibly approach using things differently than we might. For more on this topic, read Fred Beecher&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://johnnyholland.org/magazine/2009/08/the-iphone-is-not-easy-to-use-a-peek-into-the-future-of-experience-design/&#34;&gt;article in Johnny Holland&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://johnnyholland.org/magazine/2009/08/the-iphone-is-not-easy-to-use-a-peek-into-the-future-of-experience-design/&#34;&gt;http://johnnyholland.org/magazine/2009/08/the-iphone-is-not-easy-to-use-a-peek-into-the-future-of-experience-design/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>