<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emotion on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/emotion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emotion on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/emotion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Playfulness, Usability, &amp; Context: The Three Pillars of a Delightful User Experience</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/playfulness-usability-context-three-pillars-delightful-user-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/playfulness-usability-context-three-pillars-delightful-user-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://userexperience.evantageconsulting.com/2009/09/playfulness-usability-context-delightful-user-experience/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1896&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4ab7c8d1441ca.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fred Beecher did an informal usability test of 2 conversion apps for the iPhone&amp;ndash;Convert and Covertbot&amp;ndash;and wrote up a thought provoking review regarding the relationship between playfulness and usability. Convertbot could be viewed as the more playful and whimsical of the 2 apps. He writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fun isn’t always the new usable. There are situations in which usability is more important than playfulness and those in which it’s the other way around. The delight that playfulness contributes to an experience depends on the context surrounding that experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[W]hile playfulness is undoubtedly an important new focus in user experience design, it’s not a panacea. User experience designers need to understand when playfulness is more effective than pure usability in inspiring delight and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fred observed that playfulness wasn&amp;rsquo;t always favored, but that &amp;ldquo;playfulness is more effective at certain levels of interaction and when there is a clear benefit to the user to learn the mechanics of that playfulness.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With regard to the use case of converting measurements, his small sample favored the less playful interface that required less to learn. Clearly the dimensions of frequency of use, and specificity of the use case are big factors. The quick information need when converting a measurement is nothing like exploring other kinds of information-rich environments. But the exception in his test points out that once she learned how to use the playful app, she preferred it better. What I&amp;rsquo;m wondering is, how do you determine when playful comes at too large a cost? What is the point where the burden of learning is outweighed by the benefit of use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s suggesting that ultimately UX designers need to understand the balance between playfulness and usability, and the goal is to deliver appropriate experiences that achieve sustainability while making users enjoy using the product. Again, I think audience, context, and use case seem to be key factors. &lt;a href=&#34;http://userexperience.evantageconsulting.com/2009/09/playfulness-usability-context-delightful-user-experience/&#34;&gt;Read the full article for more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://userexperience.evantageconsulting.com/2009/09/playfulness-usability-context-delightful-user-experience/&#34;&gt;http://userexperience.evantageconsulting.com/2009/09/playfulness-usability-context-delightful-user-experience/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kicker Studio&#39;s Jennifer Bove on how to design enjoyment</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/kicker-studios-jennifer-bove-how-design-enjoyment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/kicker-studios-jennifer-bove-how-design-enjoyment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jennifer Bove, principal at Kicker Studio, writes about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativity-online.com/?action=blog:article&amp;amp;newsId=136614&amp;amp;sectionName=on_design&#34;&gt;ways interaction designers can make design more about people&lt;/a&gt; and less about technology--designing behaviors that are defined from the point of view of humans, and designed to elicit emotion, make products and services more enjoyable and easier to use. Bove writes about the subtle things that can reference human connection, whether it is the language presented in system messages, the logic behind system behaviors that reflects human thought and desire, or subtle cues and movement that feels organic &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an excellent read that picks up the thread in Don Norman&#39;s &lt;em&gt;Emotional Design&lt;/em&gt;, and Dave Malouf&#39;s recent writing about &lt;a href=&#34;move-beyond-function-towards-connection.html&#34;&gt;moving beyond function towards enjoyment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativity-online.com/?action=blog:article&amp;amp;newsId=136614&amp;amp;sectionName=on_design&#34;&gt;http://creativity-online.com/?action=blog:article&amp;newsId=136614&amp;sectionName=on_design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move beyond function towards connection</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/move-beyond-function-towards-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/move-beyond-function-towards-connection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;David Malouf believes that &#34;most successful products create a sense of connectedness between the consumer and the designer and that this connection occurs when designers balance the pull towards the rational, functional, &amp;amp; expedient with the natural &amp;amp; emotional.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his &lt;a href=&#34;http://johnnyholland.org/magazine/2009/04/function-to-connection/&#34;&gt;article on Johnny Holland&lt;/a&gt;, David looks more deeply at what it means for an end-user to be connected to a product. He first looks at how art creates connection with humanity. It is the type of soulful connection that we experience in master works of art that either reach universal touch points, or resonate with us at a level that transcends pure aesthetic appreciation. David considers what it might mean to connect the user experience with the user on that kind of level. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;[S]oul comes through a feeling of connectedness. The ... flick of the iPhone is more than just a great metaphor: it is a calling card. It is that random sign that is completely analog in its interpretation. No machine could have ever conceived that. Apple through almost all of their products have become expert at adding these “human” touches in their designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great design in the end will give us something to relate to, to feel connected with, and to reinforce our humanity. Tapping that right balance between emotion and logic, chaos and control, analog and digital, is the key to this success. We can no longer rely on “form follows function”. Form has to be parallel to function, as function is growing in commodity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is a wonderful look at how function can be abstracted to create experiences that seem natural over time and have a human feel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other characteristics of the experience that I think might help products bridge the gap between purely functional existence to sympathetic, connection-seeking being, by also touching elements other than the designed object or interface. Take the use of language in interfaces for example.  Simply choosing the right interface to approach natural conversation without being cheeky can sometimes achieve this connection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point that purely providing functional products is no longer adequate for survival can&#39;t be understated. If companies want to differentiate themselves and retain loyal customers, design is what will separate all of the generic products from those that create connection with the user.  &lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://johnnyholland.org/magazine/2009/04/function-to-connection/&#34;&gt;http://johnnyholland.org/magazine/2009/04/function-to-connection/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>