<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Industrial Design on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/industrial-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Industrial Design on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/industrial-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Jeff Smith ID Sketch Demos on Core77</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/jeff-smith-id-sketch-demos-core77/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/jeff-smith-id-sketch-demos-core77/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I could watch Jeff Smith sketching with a Sharpie all day. Core 77 featured Smith, principal/Design Director at Reflex Design, doing sketch demos for the students at Virginia Tech&#39;s ID department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;377&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/4szf2FTaVU0?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;hd=1&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/4szf2FTaVU0?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;hd=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;377&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://boards.core77.com/viewtopic.php?f=27&amp;amp;t=25012&#34;&gt;Core 77 Boards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.core77.com/blog/tools/forum_frenzy_sketch_demos_from_blaster701_19745.asp&#34;&gt;http://www.core77.com/blog/tools/forum_frenzy_sketch_demos_from_blaster701_19745.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1st Interaction Design Contest | Building the Internet of Things</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/1st-interaction-design-contest-building-internet-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/1st-interaction-design-contest-building-internet-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.interactiondesigncontest.com/?lang=en&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2451&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4cc03de25ea18_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;IDAT, the Institute of Design, Art and Technology of Barcelona is holding its &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.interactiondesigncontest.com/?lang=en&#34;&gt;1st Interaction Design Competition&lt;/a&gt; based on the theme of designing applications for the next generation Internet of Things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competition calls for ideas of interfaces, interactions, and applications that can be designed with technologies such as embedded Radio Frequency Identification (RFID), short-range wireless communication, ubiquitous data networks, mobile devices, hardware prototyping tools and digital fabrication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deadline to submit projects is December 15, 2010, and the award is 16.000 euro. If you haven&#39;t already started tinkering with physical computing, this may be a good opportunity to start. ;) &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.interactiondesigncontest.com/?lang=en&#34;&gt;Find out more about entry details.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.interactiondesigncontest.com/?lang=en&#34;&gt;http://www.interactiondesigncontest.com/?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside IDEO</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/inside-ideo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/inside-ideo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design Observer &lt;a href=&#34;http://designobserver.com/archives/observed.html?id=47147&#34;&gt;points to&lt;/a&gt; the 1999 ABC Nightline program that took an inside look at IDEO. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;How does the process of designing a better product work? To show you, Nightline went to Palo Alto, CA to the designers at IDEO, and gave them the toughest problem we could think of. Take something old and familiar like the shopping cart and completely redesign it in just five days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IDEO&amp;rsquo;s unique brand of brainstorming is called &amp;ldquo;Deep Dive,&amp;rdquo; a sort of total immersion into the problem at hand. It&amp;rsquo;s one company&amp;rsquo;s secret weapon for innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a great quote in video 2 that I took away with me. &amp;ldquo;Enlightened trial and error succeeds over the plans of the lone genius.&amp;rdquo; This was a reaction to the question about why a team vote on brainstorming trumps a boss&amp;rsquo;s opinion. There&amp;rsquo;s also the adage, &amp;ldquo;Fail Often To Succeed Sooner&amp;rdquo; that&amp;rsquo;s often referenced at IDEO, regarding their prototyping process. It&amp;rsquo;s great to see the process of ideation, refinement, organization and focusing, and prototyping in this video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/2Dtrkrz0yoU&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z6z-3ejvvGE&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z6z-3ejvvGE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindle vs. iPhone/iPod Touch: Human/Machine Interaction &amp; User Experience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/kindle-vs-iphoneipod-touch-humanmachine-interaction-user-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/kindle-vs-iphoneipod-touch-humanmachine-interaction-user-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asktog.com/columns/074KindleVsiPhone.html&#34;&gt;Tog&#39;s comparison&lt;/a&gt; and analysis of the human computer interaction versus the user experience with both the Amazon Kindle and the iPhone/iPod Touch is excellent. The separation of HCI/UX in his analysis really drives the point home that good interaction and industrial design can make the experience, and a good experience isn&#39;t only about the design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t use a Kindle daily, so I can&#39;t comment personally on it, but the industrial design was a showstopper for me and kept me from wanting it. Truth be told, though, the kind of books I read are probably better on dead trees. The thing that impressed me most was the mobile connectivity and the screen. But when I held it in my hand and paged through, the buttons kept me paging through accidentally. I think the lack of back light for darkened rooms would also be a let down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the iPhone, I&#39;m not one of those people that dotes on it. Don&#39;t get me wrong. It&#39;s without a doubt the single most enjoyable device I use daily, and I wouldn&#39;t want to be without it. But many of the elements of the experience have frustrated me, and I still won&#39;t be convinced that typing on a touchscreen is a step forward from a physical keyboard. The Sidekick spoiled me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part of this article is that step back that tells the story of why we need to take a holistic approach to the product, from the interaction with the interface to every aspect that radiates from the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Companies that pay attention to both the mechanics of the interface and the subtleties of the user experience win. Explore websites like Bed, Bath &amp;amp; Beyond and see how good screen design and carefully-plotted user experience come together. Don’t just examine look and feel; set up a shopping scenario and experience every step from thinking about maybe buying a product to selecting it and checking out. Bed, Bath &amp;amp; Beyond has perfected a superior experience in their real-world stores, and they have translated it beautifully into the cyber world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no trade-offs here. Human/machine interaction is a subset of the user experience. Anything done to improve the mechanics of the interface will, by its very nature, improve the overall experience. Anything done to improve the user experience will amplify the good qualities of the human/machine interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must, however, research and design each of them separately—and to test each of them separately. They each require a specific frame of mind, and concentrating on just one will lead to the kind of uneven design that both the Kindle and the iPhone/iPod Touch have been offering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that last part strikes home most. These are separate activities, but require a holistic approach and frame of mind. Investing in research and design on both of them can be seen as either a luxury or a given depending on how and where you work. But the holistic approach ensures a better experience.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asktog.com/columns/074KindleVsiPhone.html&#34;&gt;http://www.asktog.com/columns/074KindleVsiPhone.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cooper-Hewitt, National Design Museum: People&#39;s Design Award</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/cooper-hewitt-national-design-museum-peoples-design-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/cooper-hewitt-national-design-museum-peoples-design-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://peoplesdesignaward.cooperhewitt.org/2008/browse/all/0&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1390&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt490614b1a6d76_0.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://peoplesdesignaward.cooperhewitt.org/2008/browse/all/0&#34;&gt;Results are in&lt;/a&gt; of the People&amp;rsquo;s Choice award for the Cooper-Hewitt&amp;rsquo;s National Design Award. The Zon Hearing Aid grabbed the prize.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://peoplesdesignaward.cooperhewitt.org/2008/browse/all/0&#34;&gt;http://peoplesdesignaward.cooperhewitt.org/2008/browse/all/0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iStik Designers Make a Better iPod Holder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/istik-designers-make-better-ipod-holder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/istik-designers-make-better-ipod-holder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goistik.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/istik.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.core77.com/blog/object_culture/couple_makes_good_with_selfdesigned_ipod_accessory_11504.asp&#34;&gt;Core77 talks&lt;/a&gt; about a couple that makes good with self-designed iPod accessory, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goistik.com/&#34;&gt;iStik&lt;/a&gt;. Great example of designers finding buyers in a market saturated with accessory makers. They stand out because they&amp;rsquo;ve thought of the problem, researched how to make the better mousetrap and deliver a product that sells the story of sticking your nano wherever you want when you work out. They&amp;rsquo;ve made $50K in 6 months. Excellent stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goistik.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.goistik.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clover Innovates the Coffee Maker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/clover-innovates-coffee-maker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/clover-innovates-coffee-maker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The $11,000 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cloverequipment.com/home/&#34;&gt;Clover Coffee Maker&lt;/a&gt; brews one cup of coffee at a time using a method similar to a French Press, but with the ability to customize water volume and temperature per cup. The machine is programmable and has a network connection, so the machine can use brewing parameters for specific roasts. Check the video below for the Clover in action. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/zAEagZRoXPY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/zAEagZRoXPY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Wired Magazine, Howard Schultz, the founder of Starbucks described the coffee by saying, &#34;In my 25 years at Starbucks, the Clover machine unquestionably delivers the best cup of brewed coffee I have ever tasted.&#34; Schultz tried his first cup after seeing a line formed outside of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cafegrumpy.com/&#34;&gt;Cafe Grumpy&lt;/a&gt; in Chelsea. The company later bought out the Coffee Equipment Company, which makes the Clover, and will be testing them in Starbucks coffee shops. Shultz, who has retaken the position of CEO is hoping to restore the original idea of Starbucks, and support the the heritage of coffee at their shops. They will be making changes like grinding beans in store, and getting rid of the breakfast sandwiches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Clover seems to have an almost cult-like following. What I like most about this story is the history and back story of the Coffee Equipment Company. The company was started by Zander Nosler, a former product designer at IDEO, with the purpose of perfecting the single-brew coffee machine, based on research he did designing a commercial machine while at IDEO. This single idea led to the realization of a machine that produced unmatched quality in a cup of coffee that no other machine had, by focusing on delivering one cup at a time with very controlled customization of the brewing process. That attention to this process produced this $11,000 machine that indie shops and wealthy coffee connoisseurs were apparently happily paying for to make the perfect cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Clover is no longer for sale to indie shops and individuals. It will be manufactured for Starbucks only in the future. For more about the Clover Coffee Machine, check out the August issue of Wired. &lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cloverequipment.com/home/&#34;&gt;http://cloverequipment.com/home/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future Of Apple Is In 1960s Braun</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/future-apple-1960s-braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/future-apple-1960s-braun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gizmodo.com/343641/1960s-braun-products-hold-the-secrets-to-apples-future&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1320&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt486587c6345d1.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gizmodo.com/343641/1960s-braun-products-hold-the-secrets-to-apples-future&#34;&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/a&gt; puts Dieter Rams&amp;rsquo; designs at Braun next to Jonathan Ives&amp;rsquo; designs at Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10 principles of design according to Rams:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good design is innovative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good design makes a product useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good design is aesthetic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good design helps us to understand a product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good design is unobtrusive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good design is honest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good design is durable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good design is consequent to the last detail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good design is concerned with the environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good design is as little design as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gizmodo.com/343641/1960s-braun-products-hold-the-secrets-to-apples-future&#34;&gt;http://gizmodo.com/343641/1960s-braun-products-hold-the-secrets-to-apples-future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing from the Inside Out</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/designing-inside-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/designing-inside-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://interactions.acm.org/content/?p=1101&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1293&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4845c68eaefef.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Laura Richardson writes in &lt;a href=&#34;http://interactions.acm.org/content/?p=1101&#34;&gt;interactions magazine, May/June 2008&lt;/a&gt; (subscription required for full text) about a philosophy of industrial design whose goal is to &amp;ldquo;get to the heart of the matter&amp;#8212;meaningful interactions at the core of great product design.&amp;rdquo; In a sense, I can boil this down to needs. People have needs, explicit and unexpressed, that have to be described in relation to your product. The successful products are those where the flow between need and fulfillment are fluid and natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This design philosophy is based on the idea that the experience with the product necessarily connects the user&amp;rsquo;s desire or impetus for use with the manifestation and interaction with the product. Designing towards these goals is not simply a matter of form following function, but, more importantly, relating to desire and emotion. &amp;ldquo;Form &amp;hellip; is designed to interact, reflect, and engage with the interior as well as the external audience.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside-Out design considers interior issues such as purpose/function, desire, and emotion on one hand. On the other hand, it thinks about the exterior elements of form, interfaces, physical use, possibilities and limitations of the medium. The resulting experience&amp;#8212;the outcome of I-O design&amp;#8212;reflects the process of designing the product to reflect elements of the interior. Richardson goes on to describe the process used for doing I-O design of a smarter driving glove that produces better feedback, and a medical ID that considers the emotional needs of those who need them.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All projects must start with understanding the fundamental goals and desires driving the reason for the product&amp;rsquo;s existence. What Richardson is exposing in the examples is the process that led to solutions. It&amp;rsquo;s really like the unfolding of a story. It starts with an expression of fundamental desires, talks about how the desires need to touch the product, continues with designers aware of these internal needs making sure they are met, and ends with people using the product to meet their needs. Oh, and somewhere afterward, someone makes money off the process. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Designers of web sites and applications who invest any time in user research, and factor this information into the design process, are already engaged in this type of activity. We have good examples of how rich applications have innovated the web with AJAX, for example. One example that comes to mind are interfaces that use AJAX to focus on efficiency when the primary need is to get things done. Or controls that anticipate what your next step will be, depending on the context of your actions. The innovation comes in the form of re-thinking what could conventionally be done, or what could be created to feel cool, and instead focussing what can be made to get to the heart of what user&amp;rsquo;s desire, and what their emotional needs are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thrust of the article is that some industrial design has, in recent years, fetishized the package to the detriment of the experience. Designers can avoid that trap by re-focusing on interior needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://interactions.acm.org/content/?p=1101&#34;&gt;http://interactions.acm.org/content/?p=1101&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovate or Die Winner, The Aquaduct</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/innovate-or-die-winner-aquaduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/innovate-or-die-winner-aquaduct/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The winners of Specialized&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.innovate-or-die.com/&#34;&gt;Innovate or Die&lt;/a&gt; Pedal-Powered Machine competition have been selected. The Aquaduct Mobile Filtration Vehicle was invented by five students from California: Adam Mac, Brian Mason, John Lai, Paul Silberschatz, and Eleanor Morgan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;355&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/-U-mvfjyiao&amp;amp;rel=1&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;wmode&#34; value=&#34;transparent&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/-U-mvfjyiao&amp;amp;rel=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; wmode=&#34;transparent&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;355&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The Aquaduct transports, filters, and stores water for the developing world. A peristaltic pump attached to the pedal crank draws water from a large tank, through a carbon filter, to a smaller clean tank. The clean tank is removable and closed for contamination-free home storage and use. A clutch engages and disengages the drive belt from the pedal crank, enabling the rider to filter the water while traveling or while stationary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This movie gave me the chills, thinking about how design can be used to improve living conditions, and in this case, truly revolutionize how peoples basic needs are met. Simply brilliant and inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.innovate-or-die.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.innovate-or-die.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>