<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Kathy Sierra on Creating Awesome Users</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/kathy-sierra-creating-awesome-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/kathy-sierra-creating-awesome-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/96807822?byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;color=ffffff&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;The model for sustaining customer loyalty is reverse engineering user awesomeness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peldi pointed me to a video of &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.businessofsoftware.org/2010/05/kathy-sierra-at-business-of-software-2009.html&#34;&gt;Kathy Sierra&amp;rsquo;s presentation at Business of Software 09&lt;/a&gt;, where she talks about sustaining passionate and loyal customers. Positioning and generating sustainable relationships is not what you think it should be about. It&amp;rsquo;s about user benefits, and not features&amp;ndash;about how they feel about themselves in the context of what you provide them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t make a better [X], make a better [user of X].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What creates the conditions for a user to be happy is how they experience what they do in the world because of what you give them. To jump to the chase, it&amp;rsquo;s not about good products, good service, or good companies. It&amp;rsquo;s not about you at all. It&amp;rsquo;s about your users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model for sustaining customer loyalty is reverse engineering user awesomeness. Doing things that continue to let them say, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m awesome&amp;rdquo; because of things your product lets them do. Helping people kick ass FTW. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t sell me, teach me and I&amp;rsquo;ll do the rest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One example she gives has to do with how you treat examples vs. documentation. She references a Nikon learning site that shows people how to capture a waterfall, and cuts right to that user voice that says, &amp;ldquo;I want to do that.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By providing a learning experience that tells this story rather than expecting users to read the manual, the user can do more and go further than any technical document will ever enable them to do. Manuals let users understand tools, but stories and examples help users have great experiences. If you help users have that experience, they associate you with that experience&amp;ndash;that awesomeness they create themselves. It&amp;rsquo;s not about creating better products necessarily, it&amp;rsquo;s about enabling people to become better users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She suggests focussing on compelling questions, like the ones below, that have to do with creating that user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on what the user does, not what you do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask, &amp;ldquo;What does having a solution mean to our users? What [bigger cooler thing] is enabled?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give them super powers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offer better gear and help them justify it to others. Give them higher &amp;ldquo;resolution&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivate and Inspire. Give them motivation for things they WANT to do but aren&amp;rsquo;t. Get stuck camera users out of P mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the right thing easy and the wrong thing difficult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make them actually smarter. Keep users working on the smart things. Offer exercises, games, etc. that support deliberate practice of the right things. Make the time more fun. Turn the brain on with cognitive pleasures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shrink the user&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Outliers_(book)&#34;&gt;10,000 hours&lt;/a&gt; (time spent working on a specific task), by giving them patterns or shortening the duration of that time. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make your product or your documentation reflect how they really feel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does being your user SAY about your user? What would their tshirt read?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the heroes journey, we have to think about who we are to our users, and what role we actually play.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t insist on inclusivity. It&amp;rsquo;s OK to split off the advanced ass kickers from the newbies in your community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to agree with the closing point she makes. What we&amp;rsquo;re doing by making software is increasing the resolution of the universe for people&amp;ndash;increasing their ability to see more and feel expert in their world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.businessofsoftware.org/2010/05/kathy-sierra-at-business-of-software-2009.html&#34;&gt;watched the hour long video above&lt;/a&gt;, I highly recommend making the time to come back to it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.businessofsoftware.org/2010/05/kathy-sierra-at-business-of-software-2009.html&#34;&gt;http://blog.businessofsoftware.org/2010/05/kathy-sierra-at-business-of-software-2009.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build It With Me Connects App Designers and Builders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/build-it-me-connects-app-designers-and-builders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/build-it-me-connects-app-designers-and-builders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.builditwith.me/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2221&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4b2118e56a283_large_0.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build It With Me is a free site that connects like-minded designers &amp;amp; developers with the same goal: create cool &amp;amp; useful apps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Getting funding for your app idea is hard and often unrealistic. Most of the time you may just need to connect with a partner who has a skill set you lack to finish off your app. This is where Build It With Me is comes in, connecting you to those people. Skip the funding. Build It With Me will help you bootstrap your ideas into actual apps.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.builditwith.me/&#34;&gt;Check it.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.builditwith.me/&#34;&gt;http://www.builditwith.me/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caterina Fake on why working hard is overrated</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/caterina-fake-why-working-hard-overrated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/caterina-fake-why-working-hard-overrated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caterina.net/archive/001196.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1902&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4ac372308eb1f.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Caterina Fake, founder of Flickr and Hunch, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caterina.net/archive/001196.html&#34;&gt;talks about why working hard isn&amp;rsquo;t as important as working on the right things&lt;/a&gt;. Or as I once heard on a cartoon as a kid&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;you have to work smarter not harder.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much more important than working hard is knowing how to find the right thing to work on. Paying attention to what is going on in the world. Seeing patterns. Seeing things as they are rather than how you want them to be. Being able to read what people want. Putting yourself in the right place where information is flowing freely and interesting new juxtapositions can be seen. But you can save yourself a lot of time by working on the right thing. Working hard, even, if that&amp;rsquo;s what you like to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved that paragraph. I also loved the anecdote about Watson and Crick, the scientists who discovered the structure of DNA, and how their discoveries didn&amp;rsquo;t come from hard work, as much as from being in the world thinking, experiencing, allowing ideas to happen. I think there&amp;rsquo;s a valuable nugget in there to product developers about that space that&amp;rsquo;s sometimes needed for creativity that isn&amp;rsquo;t valued enough and understood. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating features to compete, building, and accretion without the relentlessness to say no and focus on the right things isn&amp;rsquo;t the path to quality and excellence. The right path in product development is kind of like finding the right path in life. Asking the hard questions about the things that matter and prioritizing effort around those things &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; hard work. But it&amp;rsquo;s not working hard on the wrong problems, for the sake of working or existing. It&amp;rsquo;s defining what is meaningful and pursuing those thing with fervor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/1951-so-often-people-are-working-hard-at-the-wrong&#34;&gt;37signals&lt;/a&gt; for the link. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caterina.net/archive/001196.html&#34;&gt;Read more at Caterina.net&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caterina.net/archive/001196.html&#34;&gt;http://www.caterina.net/archive/001196.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start-Up Forms Library</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/start-forms-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/start-forms-library/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orrick.com/practices/corporate/emergingCompanies/startup/forms_index.asp&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2737&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt5230060d6addd_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Orrick Start-Up Tool Kit provides free legal forms that you will need to start and grow your company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(via &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/balsamiq/status/3195753919&#34;&gt;@balsamiq&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.orrick.com/practices/corporate/emergingCompanies/startup/forms_index.asp&#34;&gt;http://www.orrick.com/practices/corporate/emergingCompanies/startup/forms_index.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kickstarter: Fund your creative project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/kickstarter-fund-your-creative-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/kickstarter-fund-your-creative-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kickstarter.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1612&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4a1fc590bef43.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kickstarter.com/&#34;&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt; is a brilliant idea for creatives needing funding for projects.  It&amp;rsquo;s a funding platform for artists, designers, filmmakers, musicians, journalists, inventors, bloggers, etc. It works much like fundraising sites you may have used if you&amp;rsquo;ve ever had to raise money for events for non profit organizations. A few years ago I used a similar one for Team In Training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You set up a page stating your mission and the need for funding. On this page you state the monetary goal, and a form allows users to pledge donations at different levels of support. The charges are made via Amazon payments. The project gets 100% of all proceeds minus Amazon&amp;rsquo;s fee for credit card processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A filmmaker I recently became acquainted with is shooting a documentary film and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1865033180/let-us-tattoo-you-and-help-us-make-a-documentary-0&#34;&gt;set up a fund raising page for the project&lt;/a&gt; with levels of support that include special bonuses as an incentive, from tickets to the premiere to inclusion in film credits. I remember Jill Sobule also did something similar to this a few years ago to fund an album, giving people bonus gifts and liner note credit for support. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems like a great way for artists to empower themselves by raising funds through peers and fans without the hassle of going to banks or finding angel investors and VCs. I would bet some investors will be watching this space if web app designer/developers start using it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kickstarter.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.kickstarter.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Cost Multi-point Interactive Whiteboards Using the Wiimote</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/low-cost-multi-point-interactive-whiteboards-using-wiimote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/low-cost-multi-point-interactive-whiteboards-using-wiimote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;Researcher provides another Wii Remote hack, this time to help business users create interactive whiteboards on the cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/5s5EvhHy7eQ&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/5s5EvhHy7eQ&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might remember the incredible Wiimote hacks by by Johnny Chung Lee, who gave us head tracking demo for desktop VR displays. Lee, a PhD student in the Human-Computer Interaction Institute at Carnegie Mellon University is back with some more useful Wiimote hacks, this time to turn any surface into an interactive whiteboard. He shows how to turn a wall into a whiteboard with a DIY LED pen interface, and also how to create a multi-touch desktop or laptop LCD display using 2 LED pens. These are incredibly useful ideas for creating inexpensive interactive displays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using an LED array and some reflective tape, you can use the infrared camera in the Wii remote to track objects, like your fingers, in 2D space. This lets you interact with your computer simply by waving your hands in the air similar to the interaction seen in the movie &#34;Minority Report&#34;. The Wiimote can track upto 4 points simultaneously. The multipoint grid software is a custom C# DirectX program. &lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~johnny/projects/wii/&#34;&gt;http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~johnny/projects/wii/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Business Models Matter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/why-business-models-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/why-business-models-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alex Osterwalder put together a breezy, easy to read deck on why business models matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;width:425px;text-align:left&#34; id=&#34;__ss_546052&#34;&gt;&lt;a style=&#34;font:14px Helvetica,Arial,Sans-serif;display:block;margin:12px 0 3px 0;text-decoration:underline;&#34; href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/Alex.Osterwalder/business-model-innovation-matter?src=embed&#34; title=&#34;Business Model Innovation Matters&#34;&gt;Business Model Innovation Matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object style=&#34;margin:0px&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;355&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://static.slideshare.net/swf/ssplayer2.swf?doc=businessmodelinnovationmatters-1218145513554762-9&amp;amp;stripped_title=business-model-innovation-matter&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;/&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowScriptAccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;/&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://static.slideshare.net/swf/ssplayer2.swf?doc=businessmodelinnovationmatters-1218145513554762-9&amp;amp;stripped_title=business-model-innovation-matter&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;355&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;font-size:11px;font-family:tahoma,arial;height:26px;padding-top:2px;&#34;&gt;View SlideShare &lt;a style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34; href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/Alex.Osterwalder/business-model-innovation-matter?src=embed&#34; title=&#34;View Business Model Innovation Matters on SlideShare&#34;&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; (tags: &lt;a style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34; href=&#34;http://slideshare.net/tag/osterwalder&#34;&gt;osterwalder&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34; href=&#34;http://slideshare.net/tag/alex&#34;&gt;alex&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34; href=&#34;http://slideshare.net/tag/alexander&#34;&gt;alexander&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34; href=&#34;http://slideshare.net/tag/telco&#34;&gt;telco&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;visibility:hidden;width:0px;height:0px;&#34; border=0 width=0 height=0 src=&#34;http://counters.gigya.com/wildfire/IMP/CXNID=2000002.0NXC/bT*xJmx*PTEyMTgyMjMwOTk2MzcmcHQ9MTIxODIyMzEwMjgxMyZwPTEwMTkxJmQ9Jm49Jmc9Mg==.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hat tip to Victor for the link.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://business-model-design.blogspot.com/2008/08/slideshare-contest-why-business-models.html&#34;&gt;http://business-model-design.blogspot.com/2008/08/slideshare-contest-why-business-models.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Talk to Non-Tech-Savvy Clients</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-talk-non-tech-savvy-clients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-talk-non-tech-savvy-clients/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://justcreativedesign.com/2008/07/06/how-to-talk-to-non-tech-savvy-clients/&#34;&gt;Jacob Cass offers some advice&lt;/a&gt; for freelancers in sussing out the technical savvy of potential clients and how to approach the project discovery discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may want to impress your client with the vast amount of knowledge that you have, however, if they do not understand it, then all of your effort is lost. &amp;hellip; [W]hen explaining a concept, slow down, provide examples and talk in familiar terms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://justcreativedesign.com/2008/07/06/how-to-talk-to-non-tech-savvy-clients/&#34;&gt;http://justcreativedesign.com/2008/07/06/how-to-talk-to-non-tech-savvy-clients/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions for IA/IM vendors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/questions-ia-im-vendors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/questions-ia-im-vendors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lou Rosenfeld shares the &lt;a href=&#34;http://louisrosenfeld.com/home/bloug_archive/2008/05/questions_for_iaim_vendors.html&#34;&gt;questions one should pose&lt;/a&gt; when engaging prospective consulting firms for information architecture and information management project work. This list of questions should be very valuable if you are on the customer end of a client-vendor relationship. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also seems like it would be an interesting list of questions to think about if you&#39;re a consultant and have never been on the customer end. As a consultant, you probably already ask many of these questions of prospective clients as well, as part of your first client interview about a new project. If you&#39;re on that end, this gives an idea of the kinds of things to be prepared to answer. &lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://louisrosenfeld.com/home/bloug_archive/2008/05/questions_for_iaim_vendors.html&#34;&gt;http://louisrosenfeld.com/home/bloug_archive/2008/05/questions_for_iaim_vendors.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>