<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Craft on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/craft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Craft on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/craft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Jiro Dreams of Sushi</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/jiro-dreams-sushi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/jiro-dreams-sushi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;343&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/I1UDS2kgqY8&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got around to watching David Gelb&amp;rsquo;s documentary, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magpictures.com/jirodreamsofsushi/&#34;&gt;Jiro Dreams of Sushi&lt;/a&gt; after seeing it making the rounds on the web repeatedly. I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a documentary kick lately, and this has made it into the category of films I&amp;rsquo;d re-watch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film looks at the life of celebrated sushi chef, Jiro Ono, whose small restaurant serves only sushi and requires a reservation 3 months in advance, and who is regarded as the most masterful sushi chef in Japan. After watching, I took a week to see what resonated with me, and there are a few topic that stick, related to the nurturing of one&amp;rsquo;s craft. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The themes I latched onto focussed on the conversations about Jiro&amp;rsquo;s craft. He holds steadfast to a strong work ethic, and the notion that perfection can only be achieved through years of rigor, experience, and apprenticeship. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chef has focussed his life on serving sushi only. Apparently master chefs around the world agree that his minimalist approach and focus have lead to a remarkable depth of flavor that is hard to match. Food writer, Yamamoto, interviewed extensively for the film, sums his work up saying, &amp;ldquo;Ultimate simplicity leads to purity.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s valuable to notice in this story is the excruciating attention to detail and rigor, especially as told by Jiro&amp;rsquo;s son and apprentice, Yoshikazu, who is to inherit his fathers restaurant. He talks about having talent (taste in this case), and says making a mark depends on how hard you work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re not trying to be exclusive or elite. The techniques we use are no big secret. It&amp;rsquo;s just about making an effort and repeating the same thing every day.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think in a way, he is selling himself short when he talks about talent, because I get the feeling he is talking about his father, not himself. But there is something in the depth of knowledge that Yoshikazu has acquired that interests me. It&amp;rsquo;s shown in a much simpler manner, as if he is the worker/doer behind the master, but to me this story steals the spotlight. In doing the work, he is completely subservient to and obedient to the discipline and to his teacher. Everything is taken seriously, and rules are stubbornly adhered to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like this idea of the acquisition of skill in the pursuit of being perfect, but there&amp;rsquo;s a sense of sadness, doubt, and feeling of inadequacy in Yoshikazu, until the punchline at the end. There are interesting and at times sad stories of parenting or lack of it, cultural and familial responsibility, and the struggle and drive that comes out of necessity and need to survive. Throughout the telling of this story, it felt like the hyper focus and obsession cost dearly in other ways. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think if anything, I feel humbled by the obsession with craft told in the story. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel compelled to be as extreme in my own pursuit of craft, at the cost of balance and life, but there is something positive in the message about showing up and doing the work that is told so much more completely here than in any clever and terse poster. Definitely worth the watch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.90percentofeverything.com/&#34;&gt;Harry Brignull&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magpictures.com/jirodreamsofsushi/&#34;&gt;http://www.magpictures.com/jirodreamsofsushi/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Realizing Empathy: An Inquiry into the Meaning of Making</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/realizing-empathy-inquiry-meaning-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/realizing-empathy-inquiry-meaning-making/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;360px&#34; src=&#34;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/800798301/realizing-empathy-an-inquiry-into-the-meaning-of-m/widget/video.html&#34; width=&#34;480px&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seung Chan Lim, better known as Slim, spent 10 years making software, working in computer science and interaction design at MAYA Design where he was the Assistant Director of Engineering. After some soul searching he began to ask why he was doing what he was doing, and at the suggestion of a mentor, he went out to do something different, something he didn&amp;rsquo;t understand. He went to art school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slim&amp;rsquo;s book explores how making works (as a process), what it means (to make something), and why it matters (to our lives). Through this exploration the book also investigates the ethics of our relationship to Computer Technology, and proposes a new direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the idea of learning something new and unfamiliar as a way of expanding one&amp;rsquo;s perspective. Two of my favorite articles/talks in recent years that relate to this topic are &lt;a href=&#34;bill-buxton-how-keep-innovating.html&#34;&gt;Bill Buxton&amp;rsquo;s article on how to keep innovating&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;paula-scher-gets-serious-ted.html&#34;&gt;Paula Scher&amp;rsquo;s Ted Talk on finding fun in the unfamiliar.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judging by the introduction video, the book looks to be substantial, exploratory, humble, and inspiring. I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to reading it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is being funded now, so if you want to see it happen like I do, you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://kck.st/whvn03&#34;&gt;back this project on Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/800798301/realizing-empathy-an-inquiry-into-the-meaning-of-m&#34;&gt;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/800798301/realizing-empathy-an-inquiry-into-the-meaning-of-m&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UP THERE and Appreciation of Craft</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/there-and-appreciation-craft/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/there-and-appreciation-craft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the glut of anti-craft sentiment I hear and read so often, I think it fitting to post an entry about the love of one&#39;s work, drawing from a  craft outside of our own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UP THERE&lt;/em&gt; is a beautiful documentary about the slow, laborious, and fading craft of hand-painted advertising murals. This is the NY I love. This is the type of appreciation of craft that I admire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;343&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=10562000&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=1&amp;amp;color=00ADEF&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=10562000&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=1&amp;amp;color=00ADEF&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;343&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like the humble young man towards the end that looks at it this way. The learning comes slow, but he&#39;s in it for the long haul and knows that the learning is a process of apprenticeship. One day he hopes to be able to teach someone else and give back. There&#39;s a respect there that I admire, for his craft, and for those that help him to acquire the skills. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uptherefilm.com/&#34;&gt;More about the film&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/10562000&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/10562000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design, the web, and craft</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/design-web-and-craft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/design-web-and-craft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m a little late on getting to this one, but wanted to post before I forgot because it is a great topic for early and mid-career web designers. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emenel.ca/post/407052566/design-the-web-and-craft&#34;&gt;Matt (emenel) reacted&lt;/a&gt; to Mark Boulton&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.markboulton.co.uk/journal/comments/on-designers-writing-html&#34;&gt;thoughts&lt;/a&gt; about whether or not designers needed to know html.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt summarizes what he believes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;As a designer there is a continuum you travel over the course of your career. It starts with making - crafting objects in your selected medium - and progresses through a point where you internalize your craft and can design without making. Even at that point, most designers continue to make things. It helps solidify design choices, and keeps you in touch with changes in the medium. Career wise, at this point you might be an art director, creative director, or design director… Before that point it is imperative that designers engage with their medium and craft - wether it be websites, clothes, telephones, chairs, or responsive environments.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt&#39;s post started with an observation of fashion designers, through watching Project Runway. These designers are judged not only on concept, but also on execution, or inability to execute. I think this is one profession in particular where the craft of constructing and prototyping are important. You see it when looking at process. Some designers make cartoonish sketches and others beautiful concept drawings. But in the end, the concept can&#39;t stand alone if they&#39;re judged equally on execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning html for Mosaic is one of the reasons I was drawn to the web. It was like taking a toaster apart only to learn how to put it back together. I took my first job basically to apprentice, even though I would be learning most of the HTML techniques on my own and through mailing lists like ALA. All that time and experience helps me every day that I draw a UI schematic. The immersion over time is what makes it become part of your language, and gives you the confidence to design without limitations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think that everyone needs to create production-quality html. I agree with Matt on the main point here. UX designers benefit from developing a working knowledge of the craft of html and css, and should at least put in some time working on prototypes to understand the capabilities of the medium. Even if new designers only work on personal projects, the experience helps them if they never use that skill in producing a deliverable. At best, it gives one the ability to personally demonstrate interactivity with a prototype resembling a working product if they have to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest point of contention may be whether they need to maintain this ability over time. I don&#39;t necessarily think that&#39;s true. I, like many other UX designers I know, are familiar enough with HTML to prototype, but are good enough at sketching or with using tools to demonstrate ideas so that someone better suited to building the interactive prototype can execute. That&#39;s not to say that we&#39;ll all let those skills drop by the wayside as our careers mature. I certainly try to prevent that from happening, which is one of the reasons I blog. But there are resources that can prototype faster and better once we select and refine an idea enough. In the end, execution for me means communicating a refined concept, and doing that doesn&#39;t always mean making html or writing code. But the process certainly is informed by understanding it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emenel.ca/post/407052566/design-the-web-and-craft&#34;&gt;http://www.emenel.ca/post/407052566/design-the-web-and-craft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Mornings: Physical Computing</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/creative-mornings-physical-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/creative-mornings-physical-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/creativemornings-arduino.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;At today&amp;rsquo;s excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.swiss-miss.com/weblog/2008/11/creativemorni-1.html&#34;&gt;Creative Mornings&lt;/a&gt; on physical computing, &lt;a href=&#34;http://10minchat.com/&#34;&gt;Zach Klein and Casey Pugh from Vimeo&lt;/a&gt; talked about tinkering with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arduino.cc/&#34;&gt;Arduino&lt;/a&gt;, an open-source electronics prototyping platform. They showed some simple circuit controls using the LEDs and Processing, and then demoed a Daft Punk helmet they created with LEDs, that could then be controlled/drawn on via a Flash UI. Neat stuff.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, I got to talk to Carl, a freelance developer/interaction designer who turned me onto &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nycresistor.com/&#34;&gt;NYC Resistor&lt;/a&gt;. NYC Resistor is a hacker collective with a shared space located in downtown Brooklyn where people meet regularly to share knowledge, and hack on projects together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a maker, I&amp;rsquo;ve been really interested in doing more to combine my craft hobbies with my techie and interface design interests. Resistor sounds like the kind of place I&amp;rsquo;d be able to do that, and I agree that more web people should play around in this area. Reminds me of some of the 1990&amp;rsquo;s fusion of art/tech in NYC, ala adaweb, JODI, and Eyebeam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resistor sounds pretty cool. I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a reason to play with Processing, and looks like some Processing workshops are going on at the space. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>