<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Store Announcements on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/store-announcements/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Store Announcements on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/store-announcements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireframe Icons Update v. 1.5 for OmniGraffle and EPS Versions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-icons-update-v-15-omnigraffle-and-eps-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-icons-update-v-15-omnigraffle-and-eps-versions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/collections/icons/products/wireframe-icons-for-omnigraffle?q=store/product/wireframe-icons-omnigraffle&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2241&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4b38cc24e3a46_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/collections/icons/products/wireframe-icons-for-omnigraffle?q=store/product/wireframe-icons-omnigraffle&#34;&gt;OmniGraffle Wireframe Icons&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/collections/icons/products/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons-royalty-free-eps-and-png&#34;&gt;Royalty Free EPS/PNG icons&lt;/a&gt; have been updated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the OmniGraffle version, all icons have been converted to vector format so they are editable in OmniGraffle. You can now modify the shapes and easily change their colors. The vector icons also reduce file size of OG documents. In both OmniGraffle and EPS/PNG versions, I&#39;ve cleaned up all existing icons for consistency and added new icons including: globe, wrench/screwdriver, lightning bolt, spaces, desktop, gun sight, cloud, bug, books, presentation, twitter bird, bullhorn, megaphone, rocket, windows, mac, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve purchased either of the icon sets in the past, you can re-download the updated versions by logging in and visiting your user profile. In your profile page, access the Files link below your username to download the new version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/collections/icons/products/wireframe-icons-for-omnigraffle?q=store/product/wireframe-icons-omnigraffle&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/product/wireframe-icons-omnigraffle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handmade 5.25&amp;amp;quot; Floppy Disk Sketchbooks Now in the Store</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/handmade-525-floppy-disk-sketchbooks-now-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/handmade-525-floppy-disk-sketchbooks-now-store/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/525-floppy-disk-sketchbook?q=store/product/525-floppy-disk-sketchbook&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1927&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4ae62169b90b1_1.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This one is for the retro computing kids—a 5.25&amp;rdquo; floppy disk sketchbook that&amp;rsquo;s sure to turn heads. It&amp;rsquo;s a hand-made, wirebound 5.25 inch square sketchbook with about 140-150 pages (70-75 sheets) of 70 pound white vellum paper printed with 1cm grids in warm gray ink. The cover is made from a 5.25 inch floppy disk, and inside you&amp;rsquo;ll find a floppy disk pocket, and a disk label and write-protection sticker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/525-floppy-disk-sketchbook?q=store/product/525-floppy-disk-sketchbook&#34;&gt;Pictures and more info on the product page.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/525-floppy-disk-sketchbook?q=store/product/525-floppy-disk-sketchbook&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/product/525-floppy-disk-sketchbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended License Agreement added for EPS Wireframe Icons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/extended-license-agreement-added-eps-wireframe-icons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/extended-license-agreement-added-eps-wireframe-icons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An Extended License Agreement option has been added for use on commercial web sites and web apps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Standard Royalty Free (RF) License allows for use on commercial web sites and print collateral. Purchase with this option if you plan to use the icons in Wireframes, personal, private use, and use on commercial sites. This license does not cover commercial web services and apps that utilize the icons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Extended Royalty Free (ERF) License permits use on commercial web apps and services. Purchase with this option for these uses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/collections/icons/products/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons-royalty-free-eps-and-png&#34;&gt;full license agreements&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/collections/icons/products/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons-royalty-free-eps-and-png&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/product/wireframe-icons-royalty-free-eps-and-png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireframe Icons, Royalty Free, EPS and PNG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-icons-royalty-free-eps-and-png/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-icons-royalty-free-eps-and-png/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/collections/icons/products/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons-royalty-free-eps-and-png&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1610&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4a1c631d647c1.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on demand to use the wireframe icons on web sites, and to use them in Adobe Illustrator and Visio, I&amp;rsquo;ve created &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/collections/icons/products/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons-royalty-free-eps-and-png&#34;&gt;EPS and PNG versions that include a Royalty Free license agreement&lt;/a&gt;. You may use them in your UX documents, but the license also permits you to use them in web sites. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are restrictions for use on commercial products or commercial applications that offer products&lt;br /&gt;
or services for sale or for fee-based usage, however. For details on the license and prohibited uses, please see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://konigi.s3.amazonaws.com/store/ROYALTY-FREE-LICENSE-AGREEMENT.txt&#34;&gt;Royalty Free License Agreement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/collections/icons/products/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons-royalty-free-eps-and-png&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/product/wireframe-icons-royalty-free-eps-and-png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireframe and Storyboard Notepads are Back: Now sold via Amazon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-and-storyboard-notepads-are-back-now-sold-amazon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-and-storyboard-notepads-are-back-now-sold-amazon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/paper-products?q=store/paper-products&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1589&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt49fb0a11193d7.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/paper-products?q=store/paper-products&#34;&gt;Wireframe and Storyboard notepads&lt;/a&gt; have been reprinted and are now selling exclusively via Amazon.com. The good news is, now that you ordered via Amazon, your order may qualify for Free Super Saver Shipping, and may be combined with other Amazon purchases in your cart. So if you spend $25 at Amazon, even by combining your purchase with other qualified products fulfilled via Amazon, your shipping will be free. Yay, you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more info about the note pads, &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/paper-products?q=store/paper-products&#34;&gt;see the product pages in the store&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/paper-products?q=store/paper-products&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/paper-products&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireframe Icons for Axure Updated (1.0.1)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-icons-axure-updated-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-icons-axure-updated-101/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Owners of the Wireframe Icons for Axure may re-download their icon set to get the latest maintenance release, which adds the 8 cursors which were accidentally omitted from the initial download file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To re-download, log in and click the Files link in your account page.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-icons-axure?q=store/product/wireframe-icons-axure&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/product/wireframe-icons-axure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchbook In Stock (Set 2)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/sketchbook-stock-set-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/sketchbook-stock-set-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small?q=store/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small&#34;&gt;sketchbooks are back in stock&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strike&gt;In this round, I&#39;ve also made a handful with white elastic bands, which I think looks pretty cool contrasting against the black covers.&lt;/strike&gt; I&#39;ve also started including a barebones option without elastic, inner pocket, or pencil. The standard option is $16 and the barebones option is $2 less. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The standard option is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/sets/72157613198002989/&#34;&gt;hand-crafted&lt;/a&gt; by me here in Brooklyn, so they&#39;ll sell out faster than the barebones options. This is essentially the same sketchbook I&#39;ve been making for myself for the past year, only now with the aid of printing and binding done by a printer. As you may know, the notepad production was done as a &#34;beta test&#34; product, with a few iterations before getting the design right. I&#39;m doing the same with these, which is why the product gets slightly tweaked each time it&#39;s sent out, until the grid and the packaging is right. For those interested, the graph paper storyboard and wireframe grid notepads are now being printed and will be available for purchase via Amazon next month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A note about shipping. If you are outside the US or Canada, I apologize, but there really aren&#39;t any options to ship outside the US that are affordable presently for the scale of production I&#39;m doing. In the past I shipped USPS First Class International, and some orders got lost in route. The only trackable option is Priority Mail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that some of these products are &#34;beta tests&#34; of the product idea, are produced in small quanitity, and may be hand crafted. If there is enough demand, I will seek better fulfillment options, as is being done for the wireframe and storyboard notepads. But for now, I can only ship affordably within the US and Canada. Sorry about that.&lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireframe Sketch Book Now Available</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-sketch-book-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-sketch-book-now-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small?q=store/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketchbook.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sketch book is &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small?q=store/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small&#34;&gt;finally available in the store&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a small 8.25 x 5.5 inch wirebound book that lays flat, has a 24 x 24 grid with note block on the front (landscape orientation) and 48 x 24 grid on the back (landscape or portrait). Includes 50 perforated sheets (100 pages) printed in non-photo blue ink, and an interior flap on the back cover. For the first set sold, I&amp;rsquo;m also including a Zebra 0.7mm mechanical pencil. Yay, you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may know, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a notebook with a grid that works well for a UI designer&amp;rsquo;s workflow, similar to the larger letter sized graphpaper, but made to be small and portable. I&amp;rsquo;m accustomed to doing initial sketches small and rough. The smaller sized paper lets you work more freely and loosely I find, so you can generate many ideas before selecting and refining. This sketch book is the one I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps with my workflow because I now have the small format for sketches, the larger format for refinement of ideas, and the OmniGraffle templates for deliverables. Each of these has the same number of grid columns and I&amp;rsquo;m continually working to improve the consistency between them so the flow makes the translation of ideas smooth from one format to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy using these as much as I do. They go on sale for $16 and I&amp;rsquo;ll be selling them in limited quantities for the time being. More info about the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small?q=store/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small&#34;&gt;in the store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small?q=store/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireframe Icons for Axure RP Pro</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-icons-axure-rp-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-icons-axure-rp-pro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-icons-axure?q=store/product/wireframe-icons-axure&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1550&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt49ca31f2f2dd8.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the great feedback from a few new readers and colleagues, and with a little help from Axure, the Konigi Store now offers the &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-icons-axure?q=store/product/wireframe-icons-axure&#34;&gt;wireframe icons for Axure RP Pro&lt;/a&gt;. This is the same set of icons offered in the OmniGraffle stencil, formatted as an Axure library that you can import into your widgets panel. As with the OG set, this is priced at a super low $10 with lifetime upgrades. Happy wireframing. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-icons-axure?q=store/product/wireframe-icons-axure&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/product/wireframe-icons-axure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireframe Icons Updated (v. 1.2)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-icons-updated-v-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-icons-updated-v-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/wireframe-icons-1-2.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons&#34;&gt;wireframe icons&lt;/a&gt; have been updated to add a bunch of new icons and crop the PNGs to 16 x 16 px. Still recession priced at $10, with lifetime free upgrades. If you own this set, go to your &lt;a href=&#34;../user.html&#34;&gt;account page&lt;/a&gt; and click the &amp;ldquo;Files&amp;rdquo; link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New icons: home, currency symbols, light bulb, hour glass, bell, rubber stamp, text tool, drawing tool, layout, calculator, medal, ribbon, puzzle piece/plugin, key, asterisk/new, wand/wizard, music, exit, pagination arrows,  mobile phone, iPhone, happy face, and sad face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those new to this icon set, the icons are meant for creating wireframes, grayscale user interface design schematics. The downloadable file gives you an OmniGraffle stencil and a folder of PNGs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons&#34;&gt;Find out more&lt;/a&gt; about the wireframe icons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/product/wireframe-icons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OmniGraffle Sketch Stencils Now Available</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/omnigraffle-sketch-stencils-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/omnigraffle-sketch-stencils-now-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sketches are often better tools for communicating designs than high fidelity illustrations or schematics. The purpose of the sketch style wireframe is to prevent the intended audience from thinking about visual design and focus on the functionality and behavior you are proposing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy to announce the &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/omnigraffle-sketch-stencils?q=store/product/omnigraffle-sketch-stencils&#34;&gt;release of this set of sketch stencils&lt;/a&gt; for OmniGraffle, based on the Wireframe Stencil. This set of user interface sketch stencils is designed for OmniGraffle 5.x. OG4 users are able to use the stencils by changing the .gstencil extensions to .graffle. The sketch kit contains all of the UI elements you&amp;rsquo;ll find in the free Wireframe Stencils we provide at Konigi, plus additional shapes and elements to make it easier for you to adjust to this style of wireframing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; As usual, I&amp;rsquo;m sticking to the goal of keeping the tools on this site inexpensive or free. Your $10 purchase of this stencil set entitles you to free upgrades forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;screens-thumbs clearfix mb1-5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-1.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; class=&#34;group&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;thumb&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-2.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; class=&#34;group&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;thumb&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-3.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; class=&#34;group&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;thumb&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-4.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; class=&#34;group&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;thumb&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-5.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; class=&#34;group&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;thumb&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-6.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; class=&#34;group&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-6.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;thumb&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-7.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; class=&#34;group&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-7.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;thumb&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-8.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; class=&#34;group&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketch-stencils-8.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;thumb&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/omnigraffle-sketch-stencils?q=store/product/omnigraffle-sketch-stencils&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/product/omnigraffle-sketch-stencils&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireframe Icons Updated (v. 1.1): PNGs and new icons added</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-icons-updated-v-11-pngs-and-new-icons-added/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-icons-updated-v-11-pngs-and-new-icons-added/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1482&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4989e95793069.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons&#34;&gt;Wireframe Icons&lt;/a&gt; have been updated. PNG versions and contact sheet has been added for all icons. New icons including User (silhouette  from front), Groups, Microphone, Clock, Phone, Printer, Power, TV Widescreen, Remote controls, Volume, alternate versions of Cart and Image, and much more have been added. Additionally, some icons have been modified for stylistic consistency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve previously purchased these icons, you can update your set by logging in and heading to your &lt;a href=&#34;../user.html&#34;&gt;Account page&lt;/a&gt; where you will see a &amp;ldquo;Files&amp;rdquo; link under your user name. Clicking the Files link will display your download. If you need assistance, please &lt;a href=&#34;../contact.html&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/product/wireframe-icons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OmniGraffle Wireframe Icons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/omnigraffle-wireframe-icons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/omnigraffle-wireframe-icons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/omnigraffle-wireframe-icons?q=store/product/omnigraffle-wireframe-icons&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/omnigraffle-wireframe-icons.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Konigi &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/omnigraffle-wireframe-icons?q=store/product/omnigraffle-wireframe-icons&#34;&gt;OmniGraffle Wireframe Icon Set&lt;/a&gt; is a set of grayscale cursors and icons that come in handy when designing wireframes, aka user interface schematics. This product includes a standard set of cursors, and many of the icons you need for the design of web-based user interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This set of icons is designed to work well with your wireframe stencils. You&amp;rsquo;ll find rich text editor controls, file system actions, social interaction symbols, ratings and voting, and a host of other icons for most of the behaviors you may want to communicate with an icon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your purchase of this icon set entitle you to free upgrades forever. If you have suggestions for icons you&amp;rsquo;d like to see included in this set, please feel free to suggest them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/omnigraffle-wireframe-icons?q=store/product/omnigraffle-wireframe-icons&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/product/omnigraffle-wireframe-icons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireframe Graph Paper V2 and a Basic Notepad Hit the Store</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-graph-paper-v2-and-basic-notepad-hit-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-graph-paper-v2-and-basic-notepad-hit-store/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-graph-paper-v2-notepad?q=store/product/wireframe-graph-paper-v2-notepad&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1393&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt491341b27ce08_0.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I added inventory for &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-graph-paper-v2-notepad?q=store/product/wireframe-graph-paper-v2-notepad&#34;&gt;Version 2 of the Wirefraframe Notepad&lt;/a&gt; to the store. This iteration simplifies the paper slightly towards a more minimal style. There is also a &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/basic-graph-paper-notepad?q=store/product/basic-graph-paper-notepad&#34;&gt;Basic Graph Paper Notepad&lt;/a&gt; that provides a 24 x 24 grid without gutters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/?q=store&#34;&gt;store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-graph-paper-v2-notepad?q=store/product/wireframe-graph-paper-v2-notepad&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/product/wireframe-graph-paper-v2-notepad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireframe and Storyboard Notepads are back in stock (10/2008)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-and-storyboard-notepads-are-back-stock-102008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-and-storyboard-notepads-are-back-stock-102008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/notepads-on-shelf.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have notepads back in stock! We&amp;rsquo;re shipping the original 2 wireframe and storyboard notepads, as well as 2 additional notepads with different grids that I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting tonight or tomorrow. Pads are now white vellum. You can place your order for the orginal pads today and new pads by tonight hopefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/?q=store&#34;&gt;at the store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>