<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interaction Design on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/interaction-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interaction Design on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/interaction-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>SIX UX: Transition and animation gallery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/six-ux-transition-and-animation-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/six-ux-transition-and-animation-gallery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sixux.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2637&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt51bbb49a4f492_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sixux.com/&#34;&gt;SIX UX&lt;/a&gt; is a gallery of transitions and animations shown as 6 second videos. Andreas Popp combined Vine app videos with tumblr to showcase otherwise ephemeral movements found around the web. Low fi and awesome. &lt;a href=&#34;http://sixux.com/&#34;&gt;Check it.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sixux.com/&#34;&gt;http://sixux.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meaningful Transitions: A collection of transition patterns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/meaningful-transitions-collection-transition-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/meaningful-transitions-collection-transition-patterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ui-transitions.com/#home&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2540&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4ea6d7abcd45e_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ui-transitions.com/&#34;&gt;Meaningful Transitions&lt;/a&gt; is the thesis project of Johannes Tonollo, an interface design student at the FH Potsdam, Germany. Johannes wrote his Thesis on &amp;quot;Transitions in the User Interface,&amp;quot; in which he analyzed how motion in the user interface can be a helpful extension to static elements to enhance the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collection of transitions is clustered into 6 different categories: Orientation, Spatial Extension, Awaking Controls (Awakening?), Highlight, Feedback, and Feedforward. His description of the effectiveness of each transition forms a pattern-like-library for motion in interface design. Each transition provides a short summary and abstract animation on the category overview. Be sure to click each item to view a detailed view that provides a description of the transition, explanation of when it can be useful, and a description of the benefits for using that transition as a design solution. Several items also provide a real-world example of the solution in use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excellent stuff, and impressive execution. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ui-transitions.com/&#34;&gt;Check it out.&lt;/a&gt; The thesis is also available in a downloadable &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.johannes-tonollo.com/mixed/Meaningful_Transitions_short.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF in German&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ui-transitions.com/#home&#34;&gt;http://www.ui-transitions.com/#home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiniAjax: Rich UI Showcase</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/miniajax-rich-ui-showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/miniajax-rich-ui-showcase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://miniajax.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2512&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4e1b018a5178a_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://miniajax.com/&#34;&gt;MiniAjax&lt;/a&gt; is a nice showcase of javascript libraries for rich interaction behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://miniajax.com/&#34;&gt;http://miniajax.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phonedoo: Dry erase iPhone sketching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/phonedoo-dry-erase-iphone-sketching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/phonedoo-dry-erase-iphone-sketching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cohdoo.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2833&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt52325efa68798_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cohdoo makes a nice iPhone UI sketching product called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cohdoo.com/&#34;&gt;Phone Doos&lt;/a&gt;. They are 6.8&amp;quot; by 3.5&amp;quot; dry erase iPhone surfaces with faint grid lines and magnetic backing. A pack contains 10 Phone Doos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like that these gives you a surface to work on that can be re-arranged easily on a table and presented on a metallic wall. They have some good screenshots using them arranged on a whiteboard with flow arrows pointing between them, which is another thing that&#39;s probably much easier with these as opposed to using paper. Dry-erase also saves paper, which is nice. You&#39;ll just have to photograph your work, or make sure you have enough of them to keep making more screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cohdoo.com/&#34;&gt;Cohdoo&lt;/a&gt; guys have web browser magnets planned as well. I&#39;m looking forward to getting my hands on those to review as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cohdoo.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.cohdoo.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Interaction Design Patterns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/android-interaction-design-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/android-interaction-design-patterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.androidpatterns.com/wiki&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2766&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt5230745639729_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Android Patterns is a community-contributed site with interaction patterns for Android app design. The site is created by the folks at Dutch interaction design firm, &lt;a href=&#34;http://unitid.nl/&#34;&gt;UNITiD&lt;/a&gt;, who also provide an &lt;a href=&#34;http://unitid.nl/tag/template/&#34;&gt;mobile wireframe templates&lt;/a&gt; for Android and Blackberry devices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.androidpatterns.com/wiki&#34;&gt;http://www.androidpatterns.com/wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1st Interaction Design Contest | Building the Internet of Things</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/1st-interaction-design-contest-building-internet-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/1st-interaction-design-contest-building-internet-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.interactiondesigncontest.com/?lang=en&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2451&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4cc03de25ea18_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;IDAT, the Institute of Design, Art and Technology of Barcelona is holding its &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.interactiondesigncontest.com/?lang=en&#34;&gt;1st Interaction Design Competition&lt;/a&gt; based on the theme of designing applications for the next generation Internet of Things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The competition calls for ideas of interfaces, interactions, and applications that can be designed with technologies such as embedded Radio Frequency Identification (RFID), short-range wireless communication, ubiquitous data networks, mobile devices, hardware prototyping tools and digital fabrication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deadline to submit projects is December 15, 2010, and the award is 16.000 euro. If you haven&#39;t already started tinkering with physical computing, this may be a good opportunity to start. ;) &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.interactiondesigncontest.com/?lang=en&#34;&gt;Find out more about entry details.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.interactiondesigncontest.com/?lang=en&#34;&gt;http://www.interactiondesigncontest.com/?lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LiveView for iPhone &amp; iPad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/liveview-iphone-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/liveview-iphone-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zambetti.com/projects/liveview/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2724&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt522ff0a27abca_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zambetti.com/projects/liveview/&#34;&gt;LiveView&lt;/a&gt; is a free remote screen viewing application created by Nicholas Zambetti to help designers create graphics for mobile applications, and for quick and dirty simulations, demos, and prototypes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visual Designers may use it to view artboard while you work. LiveView is compatible with both standard and Retina displays. Interaction Designers can use with iPhone or iPad tethered via WiFi, to interact with software prototypes and demos running on your Mac to communicate and iterate your concepts quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zambetti.com/projects/liveview/&#34;&gt;Download here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zambetti.com/projects/liveview/&#34;&gt;http://www.zambetti.com/projects/liveview/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ForeUI: Create Skinnable &amp; Interactive Prototype</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/foreui-create-skinnable-interactive-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/foreui-create-skinnable-interactive-prototype/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foreui.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2685&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt522fb29f56d0b_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;ForeUI is a handy UI prototyping tool. It can rapidly create skinnable and&lt;br /&gt;
  clickable UI prototype for your website or software, and run the interactive&lt;br /&gt;
  simulation in your web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.foreui.com/hl/img/dnd_editing.gif&#34; width=&#34;506&#34; height=&#34;366&#34; border=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ForeUI provides a set of predefined elements for creating mockup, you can drag&lt;br /&gt;
  them into the editing area and tweak them. You can also create your own elements&lt;br /&gt;
  and libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.foreui.com/hl/img/fce_create.gif&#34; width=&#34;385&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; border=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ForeUI makes prototype skinnable, by changing the UI theme, all elements in&lt;br /&gt;
  the prototype will change their look. Currently ForeUI provides four UI themes&lt;br /&gt;
  for prototyping, including Hand Drawing, Wireframe, Windows XP and Mac OS X&lt;br /&gt;
  themes. These UI themes cover the high, middle and low fidelity degrees, you&lt;br /&gt;
  can switch the UI themes at anytime, thus the fidelity of wireframe will be&lt;br /&gt;
  switched as well. The figures below is the same mockup rendered with different&lt;br /&gt;
  UI themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.foreui.com/images/ui_theme_handdrawing.gif&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;FrameBordered&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.foreui.com/images/ui_theme_wireframe.gif&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;FrameBordered&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.foreui.com/images/ui_theme_winxp.gif&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;FrameBordered&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
  &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.foreui.com/images/ui_theme_mac.gif&#34; width=&#34;150&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; class=&#34;FrameBordered&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can define the prototype behavior by creating the flow chart for handling&lt;br /&gt;
  specific events, it will work as you expected during the simulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.foreui.com/hl/img/behavior_tree.gif&#34; width=&#34;550&#34; height=&#34;402&#34; border=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can click the &amp;quot;Run Simulation&amp;quot; button to run the prototype in&lt;br /&gt;
  your web browser. All defined behavior will be converted to JavaScript and work&lt;br /&gt;
  in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.foreui.com/hl/img/simulation_sample.gif&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;295&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ForeUI works on Windows, Mac OS X, Linux and Solaris. You can choose the tool&lt;br /&gt;
  look and feel if you&amp;rsquo;d like. Here are some screen shots for ForeUI with various&lt;br /&gt;
  look and feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.foreui.com/images/ForeUI_EaSynth_Lnf_Thumb.gif&#34; width=&#34;350&#34; height=&#34;263&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;ForeUI with the default EaSynth look and feel&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.foreui.com/images/ForeUI_Win_System_Lnf_Thumb.gif&#34; width=&#34;350&#34; height=&#34;263&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;ForeUI with Windows XP native look and feel&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.foreui.com/images/ForeUI_Mac_System_Lnf_Thumb.gif&#34; width=&#34;350&#34; height=&#34;263&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;i&gt;ForeUI with Mac OS X native look and feel&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foreui.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.foreui.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Interaction Design a dead-end job?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/interaction-design-dead-end-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/interaction-design-dead-end-job/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Cooper Journal, Tim McCoy responds to Bill Moggridge&#39;s comment after a screening of Objectified. He paraphrases Moggridge as saying interaction design has become pervasive, that anyone and everyone can be an interaction designer, and so the role of professional interaction designer is (or is becoming) unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McCoy asks if &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cooper.com/journal/2009/04/is_ixd_a_dead_end_job.html&#34;&gt;interaction design is really dead&lt;/a&gt;. He goes on to point out a few factors that have allowed developers to build better interfaces without interaction designers. The main point I took away is that the need for the expertise and craft of interaction design is not dead, but the perception that the need for the role seems to be diminished given tools and awareness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awareness and tools alone, however, don&#39;t breed expertise. Clearly if it did, there&#39;d be a lot less awfully designed stuff out there. Or to take a craft like video editing as an example, we&#39;d see an awful lot more people doing much slicker looking stuff on YouTube. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a relevant point to make, however, that the tools and frameworks alone have enabled a lot of work to be done, especially in the building of web sites/apps, without need of an interaction designer. A lot of basic interactions can be implemented with design patterns. But not all needs are satisfied by a pattern, and isolated solutions can be implemented that don&#39;t relate to one another, or to the goals of the user. That&#39;s not to say that you need an interaction designer to design, but you do have to think of design in terms of the ecosystem, rather than of any solitary role within it. Any user experience designer that isn&#39;t doing that isn&#39;t worth his weight in business card titles. &lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cooper.com/journal/2009/04/is_ixd_a_dead_end_job.html&#34;&gt;http://www.cooper.com/journal/2009/04/is_ixd_a_dead_end_job.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Language We Use</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/language-we-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/language-we-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://davemalouf.com/?p=1560&#34;&gt;The language we use&lt;/a&gt;,&#34; David Malouf discusses how ideas about user interaction can become so ingrained in what we are familiar with, that our language begins to reflect that familiarity. That can lead to a natural tendency to explain away interaction without thought to what it means to the design of a thing. In this case a student describes the change of context in a sketch presentation by using the word &#34;click&#34; (as in clicks to go to the next screen). The absent minded use of the word &#34;click&#34; brings with it the connotations of a mouse click, and limits the possible set of interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David makes two great observations here. First, that the way we talk about interaction design is as important as the visual elements of the design solutions we produce. The language we use, and in particular the selection of meaningful words that convey behaviors, and the intellectual content and analysis of our design is a closely bound component of what we&#39;re providing when we do design work. It is productive, therefore, to write about interactions (e.g. in your spec) and deconstruct what you write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second great observation David makes is that there is danger in the use of loaded language when it comes to describing interaction. Words like &#34;click&#34; explicitly point to the use of one type of input behavior, whether it&#39;s a mouse input or finger touch, that carry with it the limitations or constraints of that behavior. The same might be true of using certain conventions or design patterns. The use of a specific, familiar interface element, like a tab for instance, might lead to known but perhaps limiting behavior for a given application, that would hold the designer back from considering better alternatives for the interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This discussion also reminds me of the thread started by Josh Kamler on &lt;a href=&#34;designing-writing.html&#34;&gt;&#34;Designing by Writing.&#34;&lt;/a&gt; It is extremely valuable to engage in writing and discussion about design through deconstruction. Even in the absence of a studio environment, we can learn to analyze what we design by paying particular attention to how we describe what we&#39;ve designed when we write specs and re-reading and deconstructing what we&#39;ve written, and actively engaging in regular critique of our work.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://davemalouf.com/?p=1560&#34;&gt;http://davemalouf.com/?p=1560&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Web Interfaces: 12 Standard Screen Patterns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/designing-web-interfaces-12-standard-screen-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/designing-web-interfaces-12-standard-screen-patterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://designingwebinterfaces.com/designing-web-interfaces-12-screen-patterns&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/12-standard-screen-patterns.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bill Scott and Theresa Neil&amp;rsquo;s new O’Reilly book, “Designing Web Interfaces: Principles and Patterns for Rich Interactions,” presents more than 75 design patterns for building web interfaces that provide rich interaction. They&amp;rsquo;ve shared the full &lt;a href=&#34;http://designingwebinterfaces.com/designing-web-interfaces-12-screen-patterns&#34;&gt;set of principles and patterns&lt;/a&gt; they use for RIA design in this article.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://designingwebinterfaces.com/designing-web-interfaces-12-screen-patterns&#34;&gt;http://designingwebinterfaces.com/designing-web-interfaces-12-screen-patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>patternBrowser</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/patternbrowser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/patternbrowser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.patternbrowser.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1447&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt496b396db60c1.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;patternBrowser is an amazing design pattern library produced by the Interface Design Team of the University of Applied Sciences Potsdam. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a little time looking through the interaction design category, and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of great examples there, and most importantly they&amp;rsquo;ve done the work of organizing and describing each problem/solution thoroughly. Check it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.patternbrowser.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.patternbrowser.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindle vs. iPhone/iPod Touch: Human/Machine Interaction &amp; User Experience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/kindle-vs-iphoneipod-touch-humanmachine-interaction-user-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/kindle-vs-iphoneipod-touch-humanmachine-interaction-user-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asktog.com/columns/074KindleVsiPhone.html&#34;&gt;Tog&#39;s comparison&lt;/a&gt; and analysis of the human computer interaction versus the user experience with both the Amazon Kindle and the iPhone/iPod Touch is excellent. The separation of HCI/UX in his analysis really drives the point home that good interaction and industrial design can make the experience, and a good experience isn&#39;t only about the design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t use a Kindle daily, so I can&#39;t comment personally on it, but the industrial design was a showstopper for me and kept me from wanting it. Truth be told, though, the kind of books I read are probably better on dead trees. The thing that impressed me most was the mobile connectivity and the screen. But when I held it in my hand and paged through, the buttons kept me paging through accidentally. I think the lack of back light for darkened rooms would also be a let down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the iPhone, I&#39;m not one of those people that dotes on it. Don&#39;t get me wrong. It&#39;s without a doubt the single most enjoyable device I use daily, and I wouldn&#39;t want to be without it. But many of the elements of the experience have frustrated me, and I still won&#39;t be convinced that typing on a touchscreen is a step forward from a physical keyboard. The Sidekick spoiled me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part of this article is that step back that tells the story of why we need to take a holistic approach to the product, from the interaction with the interface to every aspect that radiates from the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Companies that pay attention to both the mechanics of the interface and the subtleties of the user experience win. Explore websites like Bed, Bath &amp;amp; Beyond and see how good screen design and carefully-plotted user experience come together. Don’t just examine look and feel; set up a shopping scenario and experience every step from thinking about maybe buying a product to selecting it and checking out. Bed, Bath &amp;amp; Beyond has perfected a superior experience in their real-world stores, and they have translated it beautifully into the cyber world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no trade-offs here. Human/machine interaction is a subset of the user experience. Anything done to improve the mechanics of the interface will, by its very nature, improve the overall experience. Anything done to improve the user experience will amplify the good qualities of the human/machine interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must, however, research and design each of them separately—and to test each of them separately. They each require a specific frame of mind, and concentrating on just one will lead to the kind of uneven design that both the Kindle and the iPhone/iPod Touch have been offering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that last part strikes home most. These are separate activities, but require a holistic approach and frame of mind. Investing in research and design on both of them can be seen as either a luxury or a given depending on how and where you work. But the holistic approach ensures a better experience.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asktog.com/columns/074KindleVsiPhone.html&#34;&gt;http://www.asktog.com/columns/074KindleVsiPhone.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireframing Experiences and Applications with Flash Catalyst</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframing-experiences-and-applications-flash-catalyst/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframing-experiences-and-applications-flash-catalyst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://tv.adobe.com/Embed.swf&#34; quality=&#34;high&#34; bgcolor=&#34;#000000&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; name=&#34;AdobeTVPlayer&#34; play=&#34;true&#34; loop=&#34;false&#34; quality=&#34;high&#34; allowScriptAccess=&#34;always&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; pluginspage=&#34;http://www.adobe.com/go/getflashplayer&#34; flashVars=&#34;v=~b64~aHR0cDovL2Fkb2JlLmVkZ2Vib3NzLm5ldC9mbGFzaC9hZG9iZS9hZG9iZXR2Mi9tYXhfMjAwOF9kZXZlbG9wLzE1OTY3NDE2MTNfMjk0NjI0NzAwMV8yMDA0LWZseW5uLXdlZC05MzBhbS1kZXNpZ24tZGV2ZWxvcGVyLmZsdj9yc3NfZmVlZGlkPTE1Mzg0JnhtbHZlcnM9Mg==&amp;amp;w=600&amp;amp;t=http://tv.adobe.com/vi+f15384v1003&amp;amp;h=385&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peter Flynn gives a &lt;a href=&#34;http://tv.adobe.com/#vi+f15384v1003&#34;&gt;demo of wireframing in Adobe Flash Catalyst&lt;/a&gt;, aka Thermo. Every online demo I&amp;rsquo;ve seen of this product looks more and more exciting, and this is truly going to give Mac users a way to do easy interactive prototypes as our PC brothers and sisters can do with tools like Axure. I fully expect to be using this thing when it gets out of Preview release. It&amp;rsquo;s only slightly ironic that his first 5 minutes are talk about how wireframes are by definition, low fidelity, given my last post. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tv.adobe.com/#vi+f15384v1003&#34;&gt;http://tv.adobe.com/#vi+f15384v1003&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fear of the High Fidelity Wireframe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/fear-high-fidelity-wireframe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/fear-high-fidelity-wireframe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/fear-hifi-wireframe.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Twitter today, I posted a message that I need to resist putting rounded corners on boxes in wireframes. Then I got a few replies essentially saying that stylized elements shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be in wireframes. Context is everything. Taken out of context, it is very difficult to possibly critique a specific design technique without knowing the how and why you&amp;rsquo;re using it. Because of that 140 character constraint in Twitter, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really explain that this rounded corner example came from my hybrid high-fidelity wireframing and visual design document I was working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above is an element in a wireframe. It&amp;rsquo;s for a special kind of tag in Traction, the product I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on. They&amp;rsquo;re for todo tags actually, and the element also doubles as a checkbox. If you click the checkbox, the To Do becomes a Done tag. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m only posting this entry now so people understand just what the hell I&amp;rsquo;m talking about in Twitter, and get the bigger picture with regard to what I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing at, with going from sketches to UI specs, because very often I skip the rough wireframe stage these days, and go right to design comp-quality elements in UI specs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wireframe fast. Faster than I work in Illustrator or Photoshop. I also do all of our XHTML/CSS. But it&amp;rsquo;s still a hell of a lot faster for me to illustrate something in OmniGraffle. That&amp;rsquo;s its purpose after all&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s a drawing program. It&amp;rsquo;s for illustrating. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s static and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t illustrate everything well, but when I need interactivity, then I do it some other way. But there are times when I find it does a hell of a job at illustrating visual design too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My point is that there is a place for doing high fidelity in wireframes. The outie/innie distinction is good to point out here. In my situation, HiFi serves a purpose because I&amp;rsquo;m the one who goes from pencil sketch to implementation just short of hooking up the back end system functionality and AJAX. There are parts we do that go from sketch to implementation, or from discussion to implementation. But there are definitely parts where I do a HiFi wireframe because it&amp;rsquo;s a more efficient path. 99% of the time, I&amp;rsquo;m not specifying/presenting to communicate an idea to a customer/client, I&amp;rsquo;m creating to both test out an idea with a design/dev team and to prep the way for graphic production on a visual design that&amp;rsquo;s already been approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This discussion may seem out of left field, but it&amp;rsquo;s something I do pretty regularly actually&amp;ndash;go from Lo Fi at the onset of a project, to doing Hi Fi when visual design is there. So what&amp;rsquo;s your take. Do you have a similar experience or treat wireframes differently than the majority of IA/IXD pros out there?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>