<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Pace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/pace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/everything-in-its-right-pace/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2576&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt503901bbde9e1_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hannah Donovan&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/everything-in-its-right-pace/&#34;&gt;essay in A List Apart&lt;/a&gt; considers the issue of pace of delivery of information in web products. In a world where information is streamed constantly to us if we allow it, sometimes a slower pace, selective or scant data delivery, and better signal to noise is more appropriate and valuable. Context, medium, and place of use are important factors for determining delivery and pace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been interested in the slow movement in recent years, as it relates to sustainable living, slow design, slow food, and the 1K Movement. In the summer of 2011, I was fortunate enough to experience a very special meal on a very small farm/restaurant in Italy&#39;s Le Marche region. All the food and drink prepared is grown on the farm or sourced hyper-locally, from meat and vegetables, to wine—everything within 1 kilometer. It was the most profound eating experience of my life. Little bits and pieces of that day have made me think about how my approach to work and life have become more and more connected to each other, and how much of an impact one&#39;s production and consumption decisions have on the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a design and lifestyle perspective, I like to reference this summary of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slow_Movement&#34;&gt;philosophy of the Slow Movement&lt;/a&gt; by Professor Guttorm Fløistad, found on Wikipedia:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;The only thing for certain is that everything changes. The rate of change increases. If you want to hang on you better speed up. That is the message of today. It could however be useful to remind everyone that &lt;strong&gt;our basic needs never change&lt;/strong&gt;. The need to be seen and appreciated! It is the need to belong. The need for nearness and care, and for a little love! This is given only through slowness in human relations. In order to master changes, we have to recover slowness, reflection and togetherness. There we will find real renewal.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a bit touchy-feely, and lives entirely in the center of Maslow&#39;s Heirarchy of Needs. But the idea of taking a holistic approach to fulfilling needs in all things, provides the basis for actually satisfying them in other ways up the triangle. Specifically, I&#39;m thinking of the idea of fulfilling the needs for esteem and self-actualization as one example. In a scenario where speed and volume has become the norm, how has that situation impacted our lives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like how Donovan tells the story of learning from the experience at &lt;a href=&#34;http://last.fm/&#34;&gt;Last.fm&lt;/a&gt; to imagine &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thisismyjam.com/&#34;&gt;This is My Jam&lt;/a&gt;, a product that goes the other way, and focuses on the quality and value of the experience, using pace as the point of pivot. I like this approach. I have mostly stopped consuming from the firehose, and seek out the products that deliver a signal that I get more value from, more satisfaction, or that fulfill my basic needs with less fluff and noise. The decision to work with a product and team that follows those ideals is important to me as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beth Meredith and Eric Storm &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.create-the-good-life.com/slow_design.html&#34;&gt;summarize the concept of Slow Design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Slow Design is a democratic and holistic design approach for creating appropriately tailored solutions for the long-term well being of people and the planet. To this end, Slow Design seeks out positive synergies between the elements in a system, celebrates diversity and regionalism, and cultivates meaningful relationships that add richness to life.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Slow Movement is not just a lifestyle choice, but as designers, we can choose to have an impact on the world based on these ideals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/everything-in-its-right-pace/&#34;&gt;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/everything-in-its-right-pace/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aaron Koblin: Artfully visualizing our humanity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/aaron-koblin-artfully-visualizing-our-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/aaron-koblin-artfully-visualizing-our-humanity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2635/5765079290_93a160eff7_z.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ted.com/talks/aaron_koblin.html&#34;&gt;Aaron Koblin&amp;rsquo;s TED presentation&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Artist Aaron Koblin takes vast amounts of data &amp;ndash; and at times vast numbers of people &amp;ndash; and weaves them into stunning visualizations. From elegant lines tracing airline flights to landscapes of cell phone data, from a Johnny Cash video assembled from crowd-sourced drawings to the &amp;ldquo;Wilderness Downtown&amp;rdquo; video that customizes for the user, his works brilliantly explore how modern technology can make us more human.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash;copy and paste&amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;!&amp;ndash;copy and paste&amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;object width=&#34;446&#34; height=&#34;326&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://video.ted.com/assets/player/swf/EmbedPlayer.swf&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowScriptAccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;/&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;wmode&#34; value=&#34;transparent&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;bgColor&#34; value=&#34;#ffffff&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt; &lt;param name=&#34;flashvars&#34; value=&#34;vu=http://video.ted.com/talk/stream/2011/Blank/AaronKoblin_2011-320k.mp4&amp;su=http://images.ted.com/images/ted/tedindex/embed-posters/AaronKoblin-2011.embed_thumbnail_r.jpg&amp;vw=432&amp;vh=240&amp;ap=0&amp;ti=1152&amp;lang=eng&amp;introDuration=15330&amp;adDuration=4000&amp;postAdDuration=830&amp;adKeys=talk=aaron_koblin;year=2011;theme=a_taste_of_ted2011;theme=media_that_matters;theme=new_on_ted_com;theme=art_unusual;event=TED2011;tag=Arts;tag=Design;tag=Technology;tag=collaboration;tag=data;tag=visualizations;&amp;preAdTag=tconf.ted/embed;tile=1;sz=512x288;&#34; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://video.ted.com/assets/player/swf/EmbedPlayer.swf&#34; pluginspace=&#34;http://www.macromedia.com/go/getflashplayer&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; wmode=&#34;transparent&#34; bgColor=&#34;#ffffff&#34; width=&#34;446&#34; height=&#34;326&#34; allowFullScreen=&#34;true&#34; allowScriptAccess=&#34;always&#34; flashvars=&#34;vu=http://video.ted.com/talk/stream/2011/Blank/AaronKoblin_2011-320k.mp4&amp;su=http://images.ted.com/images/ted/tedindex/embed-posters/AaronKoblin-2011.embed_thumbnail_r.jpg&amp;vw=432&amp;vh=240&amp;ap=0&amp;ti=1152&amp;lang=eng&amp;introDuration=15330&amp;adDuration=4000&amp;postAdDuration=830&amp;adKeys=talk=aaron_koblin;year=2011;theme=a_taste_of_ted2011;theme=media_that_matters;theme=new_on_ted_com;theme=art_unusual;event=TED2011;tag=Arts;tag=Design;tag=Technology;tag=collaboration;tag=data;tag=visualizations;&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beautiful, incredibly creative use of user contributed hands for data-driven art. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ted.com/talks/aaron_koblin.html&#34;&gt;http://www.ted.com/talks/aaron_koblin.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>visualizing.org</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/visualizingorg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/visualizingorg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.visualizing.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2443&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4cab6879a13b1_large_1.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Visualizing.org looks like an exciting new community devoted to information design and sensemaking&amp;ndash;making sense of complex issues through data and design. An excerpt from their about page describes the site:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;It&#39;s a place to showcase work, get feedback, ensure that your work is seen by lots of people and gets used by teachers, journalists, and conference organizers to help educate the public about various world issues.  Visualizing is also a free resource to search for data. Use Visualizing to keep up with and be inspired by the latest work from other designers and design schools. You can learn about new visualization tools, blogs, books and other resources here.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://visualizing.org/&#34;&gt;visualizing.org&lt;/a&gt; and share your work or get data to start participating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.visualizing.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.visualizing.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should Design Be Held Back by a Tyranny of Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/should-design-be-held-back-tyranny-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/should-design-be-held-back-tyranny-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/05/10/business/10ping.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1599&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4a08334b160c4.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NYTimes &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/05/10/business/10ping.html?_r=2&amp;amp;adxnnl=1&amp;amp;adxnnlx=1242040513-Kke1lvsicTbH8SYjNFYe3w\&#34;&gt;interviewed Doug Bowman&lt;/a&gt; to talk about his departure from Google, which Bowman wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;http://stopdesign.com/archive/2009/03/20/goodbye-google.html&#34;&gt;on his blog&lt;/a&gt; in March. Bowman came onto Google as their first Visual Designer 3 years ago, and left in March. Some quotes from the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bowman on Google:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Data eventually becomes a crutch for every decision, paralyzing the company and preventing it from making any daring design decisions,”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bowman on Twitter, where he is now Creative Director:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;He has also found a new way to listen to customers: reading their tweets in reaction to the new design features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Using data is fundamental to what we do,” Mr. Bowman said. “But we take all that with a grain of salt. Anytime you make design changes, the most vocal people are the ones who dislike what you’ve done. We don’t just throw the numbers in a spreadsheet.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deborah Dunn, associate professor at the Stanford Institute of Design:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adhering too rigidly to a design philosophy guided by “Web analytics,” Ms. Dunn said, “makes it very difficult to take bold leaps.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is more from engaging with users, watching what they do, understanding their pain points, that you get big leaps in design,” Ms. Dunn said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/05/10/business/10ping.html&#34;&gt;http://www.nytimes.com/2009/05/10/business/10ping.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>