<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Podcasts on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/podcasts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcasts on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/podcasts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>IA Summit 10 Podcasts</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/ia-summit-10-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/ia-summit-10-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boxesandarrows.com/view/ia-summit-10-day-1&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2366&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4bd18f36d9c89_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t get to the IA Summit this year? Or went to IAS10, but didn&amp;rsquo;t get to see everything in all the tracks? Of course you didn&amp;rsquo;t unless you had Hermione&amp;rsquo;s Time Turner with you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that Jeff Parks did an amazing job of capturing the sessions and producing audio podcasts, which are &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boxesandarrows.com/view/ia-summit-10-day-1&#34;&gt;now available via Boxes and Arrows&lt;/a&gt; or by subscribing to the podcast &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/podcast/boxes-and-arrows-podcast/id275459507&#34;&gt;via iTunes&lt;/a&gt;. Currently the keynotes and all of the sessions from Day 1 are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boxesandarrows.com/view/ia-summit-10-day-1&#34;&gt;http://www.boxesandarrows.com/view/ia-summit-10-day-1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpoolCast with Todd Zaki Warfel: Prototyping Experiences</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/spoolcast-todd-zaki-warfel-prototyping-experiences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/spoolcast-todd-zaki-warfel-prototyping-experiences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2009/09/23/spoolcast-prototyping-experiences/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1901&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4ac36b004fcd8_0.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2009/09/23/spoolcast-prototyping-experiences/&#34;&gt;Jared Spool talks with Todd Zaki Warfel&lt;/a&gt; about his forthcoming &lt;a href=&#34;http://rosenfeldmedia.com/books/prototyping/&#34;&gt;Prototyping&lt;/a&gt; book to be published by Rosenfeld Media, and got him to talk about his 2 years of research while working on the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Todd&amp;rsquo;s firm, Message First, utilizes prototypes as a core element of the design process and has been giving a series of presentations and workshops recently to describe his research into the different prototyping practices of UX pros, and talk about the utility of the prototype. He engages clients early on in generating ideas, and uses the prototype to quickly get something in front of them that comes as close to the experience and behavior they might expect from their product. He provided a little bit of insight into their process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It may surprise you that they start with rough, black and white sketches which they share with their clients both early and often. Whereas some design shops may work hard on a prototype for three months before first showing it to their client, Todd thinks that’s a bad idea. There’s nothing worse than diving deep into a design direction only to have it unilaterally shot down in the first review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, you need to get your client to give you lots of feedback very early in the process, starting with basic and rough sketches. It will save both sides a lot of time, effort and frustration. Once the design direction is solidified, Todd and his team move their prototypes into color and interactivity. The Messagefirst crew is now often jumping straight to HTML, CSS and JavaScript for the higher fidelity mockups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I took away from this talk was that the best prototyping tool is the one that your most familiar with and know how to exploit to communicate the ideas. That said, there comes a point where the tool you use, whether it&amp;rsquo;s Visio or OmniGraffle, Powerpoint or Excel, shows its limitations at communicating well enough. And this is why so many people jump more quickly to HTML prototypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is essentially where I am today. I&amp;rsquo;m strong enough in the tools I use and have extended them beyond the capabilities they were created for. But what Todd and his team are doing makes sense. He engages clients early on with sketching exercises, and continues to ideate and refine on paper until they have a strong direction, and then they begin to demonstrate the ideas in a format that feels like the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2009/09/23/spoolcast-prototyping-experiences/&#34;&gt;Listen to the podcast on UIE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2009/09/23/spoolcast-prototyping-experiences/&#34;&gt;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2009/09/23/spoolcast-prototyping-experiences/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dan Klyn interview with Richard Saul Wurman</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/dan-klyn-interview-richard-saul-wurman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/dan-klyn-interview-richard-saul-wurman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IA instructor and author of the forthcoming book &#34;Now That I See It&#34; &lt;a href=&#34;http://danklyn.com/blog/?p=459&#34;&gt;interviewed Richard Saul Wurman&lt;/a&gt; to discuss architecture and design, IA roots in library and information work, and the work of making the complex clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that I latched onto is Wurman&#39;s contention that his success working with the design of information systems and structures comes as a result of acknowledging his ignorance. &#34;Grasp your life as an ignorant person,&#34; he says. Most of us, in our arrogance are unwilling to do that. He also notes that the importance of doing this was selfishly motivated by his desire to explore and find patterns that help with this need for making things clear, but it starts with acknowledging this knowledge gap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea resonates with me largely because that&#39;s how I feel approaching new projects every time, and that&#39;s why this blog exists--Konigi means &#34;to make known&#34;--to find what others have shared, understand them, and share that knowledge. Secondly, it seems similar to &lt;a href=&#34;paula-scher-gets-serious-ted.html&#34;&gt;what Paula Scher discusses&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ted.com/index.php/talks/paula_scher_gets_serious.html&#34;&gt;her TED talk&lt;/a&gt; about ignorance--that the ignorance of the new is what has led her to her most innovative moments. There&#39;s something powerful in that idea shared by these exemplars of design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out Klyn&#39;s blog for &lt;a href=&#34;http://danklyn.com/blog/?p=459&#34;&gt;the full interview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://danklyn.com/blog/?p=459&#34;&gt;http://danklyn.com/blog/?p=459&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The History &amp; Evolution of User Experience Design</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/history-evolution-user-experience-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/history-evolution-user-experience-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.teawithteresa.com/2009/03/history-evolution-of-user-experience.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1534&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt49b811b22fb50.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the Tea with Teresa podcast, Teresa Brazen interviews Adaptive Path&amp;rsquo;s Peter Merholz to talk about the history and evolution of User Experience Design. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;User experience design is, at its core, a philosophy that products and services should be designed so that they are pleasurable and easy for people to use. While that might seem an obvious design approach, it&amp;rsquo;s actually not the way many designers historically thought about making things. In fact, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until the 1990s that an industry came together around this particular approach to design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did some research to try uncover the history of this field, and, I didn&amp;rsquo;t find a lot - partly because it hasn’t been around for long. So, I had tea with Peter Merholz, who has been involved in the industry since its very early stages. We had a great conversation about what it was like when the industry started to come together and where he thinks it&amp;rsquo;s headed. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to the podcast at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.teawithteresa.com/2009/03/history-evolution-of-user-experience.html&#34;&gt;Tea with Theresa&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/jeepu/statuses/1312159478&#34;&gt;@jeepu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.teawithteresa.com/2009/03/history-evolution-of-user-experience.html&#34;&gt;http://www.teawithteresa.com/2009/03/history-evolution-of-user-experience.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UXDesignCast Podcast Series</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/uxdesigncast-podcast-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/uxdesigncast-podcast-series/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://uxdesigncast.com/&#34;&gt;UXDesignCast podcast&lt;/a&gt; series hosted by Karel Vredenburg provides the latest information about trends, technologies, and insights regarding User Experience Design from the leading experts in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uxdesigncast.com/&#34;&gt;http://uxdesigncast.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAKISSA - Podcasting Interface Design</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/dakissa-podcasting-interface-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/dakissa-podcasting-interface-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dakissa.blip.tv/#986656&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1309&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4857f2679cec5.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Victor Lombardi of Smart Experience and I begin DAKISSA, a podcast that looks at innovations in interface design. You can view the podcast on &lt;a href=&#34;../podcast/index.html&#34;&gt;Konigi&lt;/a&gt; or at &lt;a href=&#34;http://dakissa.blip.tv/&#34;&gt;dakissa.blip.tv&lt;/a&gt; where you can subscribe via your RSS reader or iTunes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dakissa.blip.tv/#986656&#34;&gt;http://dakissa.blip.tv/#986656&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>