<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Concept Design on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/concept-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Concept Design on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/concept-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Mozilla Labs Design Challenge: Reinventing Tabs in the Browser</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/mozilla-labs-design-challenge-reinventing-tabs-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/mozilla-labs-design-challenge-reinventing-tabs-browser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://design-challenge.mozilla.com/summer09/showcase.php&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1776&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4a48e03fa4372_0.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mozilla Labs together with IxDA and Johnny Holland presented the &lt;a href=&#34;http://design-challenge.mozilla.com/summer09/showcase.php&#34;&gt;Summer 09 Design Challenge&lt;/a&gt; as part of their Concept Series. The challenge theme is &amp;ldquo;Reinventing Tabs in the Browser - How can we create, navigate and manage multiple web sites within the same browser instance?&amp;rdquo; Voting on concept submissions ends on July 5. Will take a while to make it through the over 120 concepts!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://design-challenge.mozilla.com/summer09/showcase.php&#34;&gt;http://design-challenge.mozilla.com/summer09/showcase.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communicating Concepts</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/communicating-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/communicating-concepts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://noisebetweenstations.com/personal/weblogs/?p=2428&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1529&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt49b6bce584944.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Victor writes about some of the less obvious points when it comes to &lt;a href=&#34;http://noisebetweenstations.com/personal/weblogs/?p=2428#ixzz09NckdxRg&#34;&gt;presenting and communicating concept designs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I see concepts that are received well, the concept itself can usually only take a portion of the credit. Just as important is how the concept is communicated. Some of this is common knowledge: make it look good, choose the right level of fidelity, show it in context. Others are maybe not so obvious…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head to Noise Between Stations &lt;a href=&#34;http://noisebetweenstations.com/personal/weblogs/?p=2428&#34;&gt;for the low down&lt;/a&gt;, because your job doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop when you&amp;rsquo;ve shipped the doc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://noisebetweenstations.com/personal/weblogs/?p=2428&#34;&gt;http://noisebetweenstations.com/personal/weblogs/?p=2428&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shades of Gray: Wireframes as Thinking Device</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/shades-gray-wireframes-thinking-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/shades-gray-wireframes-thinking-device/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.semanticfoundry.com/2009/01/01/shades-of-gray-wireframes-as-thinking-device/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/wireframes-thinking-device.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Will Evans discusses &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.semanticfoundry.com/2009/01/01/shades-of-gray-wireframes-as-thinking-device/&#34;&gt;how he uses wireframes in his design process&lt;/a&gt;. The story is one you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard before. It&amp;rsquo;s a description of concept design, using wireframes as the tool for finding the right design. One could use sketching just as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s talking about that path we take as designers to frame the problem for discussion, extrapolate solutions from that discussion, and generate possible solution concepts. He calls his process one of divergence, transformation, and covergence. This maps to a common cycle in design where there is a lot of front-loaded generation of ideas and further and further reduction of solutions as the process unfolds. There&amp;rsquo;s a great diagram in Buxton&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;Sketching the User Experience&lt;/i&gt; on page 146 (based on Pugh&amp;rsquo;s 1990 work, &lt;i&gt;Total Design&lt;/i&gt;) which discusses the waves of expanding and contracting generation and reduction that happens as designers find focus. The right design emerges at the end of the process of ideation and selection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to read Evans&amp;rsquo; description of his thoughts during his design process, as it mirrors what Buxton and Pugh describe. We need to hear more detailed accounts like his, that fill in the picture for other practitioners, and hopefully impress upon some of us different ways for practicing our craft.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.semanticfoundry.com/2009/01/01/shades-of-gray-wireframes-as-thinking-device/&#34;&gt;http://blog.semanticfoundry.com/2009/01/01/shades-of-gray-wireframes-as-thinking-device/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you design? Ebook</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/how-do-you-design-ebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/how-do-you-design-ebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dubberly.com/articles/how-do-you-design.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/how-do-you-design-book.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hugh Dubberly has released a free &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dubberly.com/articles/how-do-you-design.html&#34;&gt;E Book on design and development models&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this book, I have collected over one-hundred descriptions of design and development processes, from architecture, industrial design, mechanical engineering, quality management, and software development. They range from short mnemonic devices, such as the 4Ds (deﬁne, design, develop, deploy), to elaborate schemes, such as Archer’s 9-phase, 229-step “systematic method for designers.” Some are synonyms for the same process; others represent differing approaches to design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dubberly.com/articles/how-do-you-design.html&#34;&gt;http://www.dubberly.com/articles/how-do-you-design.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working through Screens Book</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/working-through-screens-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/working-through-screens-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flashbulbinteraction.com/WTS_opening.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/flashbulb-working-screens.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Flashbulb Interactions&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flashbulbinteraction.com/WTS_opening.html&#34;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Working through Screens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an excellent, well-illustrated ebook on concept design for designers and product developers. The key point here is how to use design tools and methodologies to get the right design for the problem. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working through Screens is an online book for product teams creating new or iteratively improved applications for thinking work. Written for use during early, formative conversations, it provides teams with a broad range of considerations for setting the overall direction and priorities for their onscreen tools. With hundreds of envisioning questions and fictional examples from clinical research, financial trading, and architecture, this volume can help definers and designers to explore innovative new directions for their products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Product teams can make significant progress toward these aims by changing how they get started on designing their products — by beginning with an emphasis on getting to the right design strategy and design concepts long before getting to the right design details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There can never be enough discussion in the literature on this topic in my opinion, because understanding the problem and getting the right design is so important for success, especially when it comes to application design. The book is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flashbulbinteraction.com/WTS_opening.html&#34;&gt;free to download&lt;/a&gt;, so check it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flashbulbinteraction.com/WTS_opening.html&#34;&gt;http://www.flashbulbinteraction.com/WTS_opening.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concept Design Tools</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/concept-design-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/concept-design-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Victor Lombardi &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digital-web.com/articles/concept_design_tools/&#34;&gt;discusses concept design&lt;/a&gt; in Digital Web Magazine, pointing out that digital designers should take some inspiration from design processes for ideation and concept generation from the fields of architecture and industrial design. I think the main idea is to learn from the practices and methods from these fields, and use that as inspiration for what might be useful in your concept design practice. That is not to say that every project needs to result in a dozen concepts that need to be prototyped at high fidelity and therefore at significant cost. But by all means it could mean spending more time in ideation, sketching more alternatives, working from various perspectives and constraints and lack of constraints, and re-framing the problem/solution space&amp;#8212;practices that are inexpensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I take such inspiration from &lt;i&gt;Sketching the User Experience&lt;/i&gt; is because it is filled with these such examples of concept design from industrial design. The key take away for me from that book is that generating concepts loosely and in volume at the onset in what are noncommital gestures or ideas is probably 80% of the process. The sketch as a tool is the most important part as it relates the designer. On the flip-side, the refined prototype, or multiple and different prototypes as the case may be, is 80% of the importance when it comes to the decision makers and stakeholders who approve the design. So what we&#39;re talking about here in terms of concept design for digital designers is front-loading the design process in terms of ideation and concept generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Victor continues his investigation into concept design at &lt;a href=&#34;http://smartexperience.org/conceptdesign/&#34;&gt;Smart Experience&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digital-web.com/articles/concept_design_tools/&#34;&gt;http://www.digital-web.com/articles/concept_design_tools/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>