<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adobe Air on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/adobe-air/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adobe Air on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/adobe-air/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Sideline Twitter Search App from Yahoo!</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/sideline-twitter-search-app-yahoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/sideline-twitter-search-app-yahoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sideline.yahoo.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/sideline.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sideline.yahoo.com/&#34;&gt;Sideline&lt;/a&gt; is an Adobe AIR desktop application built with the Yahoo! User Interface Library (YUI) that allows users to create and group custom queries by topics of interest, as well as view topic trends. Very nicely done. Am looking at at how the advanced search works at the moment. Looks very easy to build up an seems like it might be the perfect app for a lurker or follower who doesn&amp;rsquo;t post much. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sideline.yahoo.com/&#34;&gt;http://sideline.yahoo.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DestroyFlickr</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/destroyflickr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/destroyflickr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.destroytoday.com/?p=Project&amp;amp;id=DestroyFlickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/destroyflickr.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://swissmiss.typepad.com/weblog/2008/06/destroy-flickr.html&#34;&gt;Tina pointed&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.destroytoday.com/?p=Project&amp;amp;id=DestroyFlickr&#34;&gt;DestroyFlickr&lt;/a&gt;, an excellent AIR application for viewing Flickr photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;DestroyFlickr explores alternative methods for viewing and sharing Flickr content. Its user interface provides an environment that benefits photos rather than hindering them. With the ability to look at a photo on a dark, neutral background, you can view it without the interference of a brighter surrounding. By using workspaces and canvases, DestroyFlickr is able to retain a constant history of where you have navigated, offering the ability to revisit an area without the need to reload the entire page. DestroyFlickr takes advantage of features provided by the Adobe AIR SDK that are unavailable to web-based RIAs. With the support of both drag and drop uploading and downloading, posting and saving photos is done in one easy motion. Now you can download the highest resolution version of a photo without having to see it first—just drag a thumbnail to the download menu and the download begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: DestroyFlickr does not intend to replicate or attempt to replace the essential user experience of Flickr.com.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.destroytoday.com/?p=Project&amp;amp;id=DestroyFlickr&#34;&gt;http://www.destroytoday.com/?p=Project&amp;id=DestroyFlickr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>