<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Heuristics on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/heuristics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Heuristics on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/heuristics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t Forget Heuristics</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/dont-forget-heuristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/dont-forget-heuristics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://theresaneil.wordpress.com/2009/07/10/6-tips-for-a-great-flex-ux-part-5/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1824&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4a5b394c9282a.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Theresa Neil continues her tips for designing great Flex UX&amp;rsquo;s showcasing interfaces that exemplify Jakob Nielsen&amp;rsquo;s 10 usability heuristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget the usability basics. Jakob Nielsen’s Ten Usability Heuristics are as relevant now as they were in 1999. I stress this because I looked at the Flex showcase recently, and it looks like many of the applications are not built with these best practices in mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://theresaneil.wordpress.com/2009/07/10/6-tips-for-a-great-flex-ux-part-5/&#34;&gt;Read more at Theresa Neil&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://theresaneil.wordpress.com/2009/07/10/6-tips-for-a-great-flex-ux-part-5/&#34;&gt;http://theresaneil.wordpress.com/2009/07/10/6-tips-for-a-great-flex-ux-part-5/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shneiderman&#39;s Eight Golden Rules of Interface Design</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/shneidermans-eight-golden-rules-interface-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/shneidermans-eight-golden-rules-interface-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ben Shneiderman&#39;s Eight Golden Rules of Interface Design are user interface design rules described in &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321197860?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=urlgreyhot-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0321197860&#34;&gt;Designing the User Interface: Strategies for Effective Human-Computer Interaction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=urlgreyhot-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=0321197860&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. Shneiderman proposed this collection of principles that are derived heuristically from experience and applicable in most interactive systems after being properly refined, extended, and interpreted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To improve the usability of an application it is important to have a well designed interface and these &#34;Eight Golden Rules of Interface Design&#34; are claimed to be a guide to good interaction design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Strive for consistency&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Consistent sequences of actions should be required in similar situations; identical terminology should be used in prompts, menus, and help screens; and consistent commands should be employed throughout.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Enable frequent users to use shortcuts&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;As the frequency of use increases, so do the user&#39;s desires to reduce the number of interactions and to increase the pace of interaction. Abbreviations, function keys, hidden commands, and macro facilities are very helpful to an expert user.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Offer informative feedback&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;For every operator action, there should be some system feedback. For frequent and minor actions, the response can be modest, while for infrequent and major actions, the response should be more substantial.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Design dialog to yield closure&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Sequences of actions should be organized into groups with a beginning, middle, and end. The informative feedback at the completion of a group of actions gives the operators the satisfaction of accomplishment, a sense of relief, the signal to drop contingency plans and options from their minds, and an indication that the way is clear to prepare for the next group of actions.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Offer simple error handling&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;As much as possible, design the system so the user cannot make a serious error. If an error is made, the system should be able to detect the error and offer simple, comprehensible mechanisms for handling the error.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Permit easy reversal of actions&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;This feature relieves anxiety, since the user knows that errors can be undone; it thus encourages exploration of unfamiliar options. The units of reversibility may be a single action, a data entry, or a complete group of actions.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Support internal locus of control&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;Experienced operators strongly desire the sense that they are in charge of the system and that the system responds to their actions. Design the system to make users the initiators of actions rather than the responders.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;Reduce short-term memory load&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;The limitation of human information processing in short-term memory requires that displays be kept simple, multiple page displays be consolidated, window-motion frequency be reduced, and sufficient training time be allotted for codes, mnemonics, and sequences of actions. &lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia contributors, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shneiderman&#39;s_rules_for_design&#34; class=&#34;cite&#34;&gt;&#34;Shneiderman&#39;s rules for design,&#34;&lt;/a&gt; Wikipedia, The Free Encyclopedia, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Plagiarism&amp;amp;oldid=5139350&#34; title=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Plagiarism&amp;amp;oldid=5139350&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Plagiarism&amp;amp;oldid=5139350&lt;/a&gt; (accessed January 17, 2008).&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321197860?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=urlgreyhot-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0321197860&#34;&gt;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0321197860?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=urlgreyhot-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=0321197860&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>