<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>99u Conference Notes: Quirky Studio Visit with Ben Kaufman</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/99u-conference-notes-quirky-studio-visit-ben-kaufman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/99u-conference-notes-quirky-studio-visit-ben-kaufman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A group of &lt;a href=&#34;http://conference.99u.com/&#34;&gt;99u attendees&lt;/a&gt; had a visit with Ben Kaufman, the CEO/founder of product development company &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quirky.com/&#34;&gt;Quirky&lt;/a&gt;, who gave us a look into how his company uses crowd-sourcing to deliver products. Here are some of my notes from that visit. More 99u notes to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kaufman got his start as an inventor in high school when he made a lanyard to hold an iPod shuffle. The company he started to ship this product later morphed into Mophie, the maker of the JuiceBox battery case. He later sold that company to start Quirky. His wanted to take all of the pain and learning he went through designing, developing and shipping a product to the masses, so that anyone with a great idea could become an inventor and let someone else handle the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their mission is to &amp;quot;Make invention accessible.&amp;quot; What they do beyond helping people see if their ideas are unique and viable, is provide an infrastructure and experts for the entire process of design, development, marketing, and fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kaufman began his talk with a story comparing the Empire State Building, which took 410 days to complete, with a potato peeler that took 3 years to complete. His point is that having more time to deliver a product doesn&#39;t always lead to better quality. Quirky works in 11 week sprints, and ships 3 new crowd-sourced products every week. To further make his point, he talked about the difference between invention vs. tweaking, and had us look back 100 years ago to the Model T, which gave us a 17mpg automobile in 1909. Fast forward to 2009, and the most popular truck, a Ford, is giving us 16 MPG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quirky makes it possible for anyone to submit ideas. They&#39;re known for helping a teenager bring Pivot Power, a flexing power strip, to the world and making the inventor over a million dollars. Now their intellectual property partnership with GE has allowed them to bring someone&#39;s idea about making air conditioners smarter to save the world&#39;s energy into a reality too. He gave us a look at how the company and their extensive community selects products for manufacturing using weekly community meetings, their web site to manage the decision-making and evolution of ideas. They have an open community-driven selection process. Somehow the Hollywood pitch in my mind is product development shop meets American Idol. They even use a bit of game mechanics to drive product name selection. The profits are shared among everyone who participates in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their founder&#39;s passion and company culture feel genuine. They believe in their people, and in no-bullshit core values. I can&#39;t recall what all of their 5 core values were, but among them were impatience, agility, and getting shit done. They actually use those for evaluation. It was great to get a peek into how they take ideas that we&#39;re familiar with in software development, and push them to the limit in manufacturing. They change the status quo and what&#39;s the most interesting part is not so much their output (and their fantastic prototyping facility), but how they&#39;re running a business with so many projects constantly running and so many products shipping given the real world obstacles in manufacturing, which accounts for the slow pace at which the world usually delivers products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the 11 week sprints, they have 3 blackout periods where they close the offices entirely and no one works. No one even answers the phones. They have a big office party the night before every blackout starts (blackout before the blackout I guess). They don&#39;t have set vacation day policies, but everyone is expected to take 3-4 weeks of time off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Takeaways:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilize constraints and speed to push product quality&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rely on the wisdom of community&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Believe and value your people—passion is intrinsic to culture&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See also these &lt;a href=&#34;http://99u.com/articles/6450/7-tips-for-rapid-iteration-aka-the-quirky-approach&#34;&gt;tips from Kaufman for rapid iteration&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;screens-thumbs clearfix mb1-5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/quirky-1.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; class=&#34;group&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/quirky-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;thumb&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/quirky-2.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; class=&#34;group&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/quirky-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;thumb&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/quirky-3.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; class=&#34;group&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/quirky-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;thumb&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/quirky-4.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; class=&#34;group&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/quirky-4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;thumb&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/quirky-5.jpg&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; class=&#34;group&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/quirky-5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;thumb&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quirky.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.quirky.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How might we...</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/how-might-we/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/how-might-we/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We know that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.startwithwhy.com/&#34;&gt;starting with why&lt;/a&gt; is important to product design, but what comes next? &#34;How&#34; would definitely come soon after. But there are many ways to propose how to begin exploring possibilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 99u &lt;a href=&#34;http://99u.com/workbook/20529/answer-these-6-questions-before-starting-a-project&#34;&gt;points to a number of questions to ask before starting a project&lt;/a&gt;, and how language matters. They refer to Warren Berger&#39;s article in the Harvard Business Review about one of the questions top innovators ask when confronted with a design challenge. It starts with the phrase &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.hbr.org/2012/09/the-secret-phrase-top-innovato/&#34;&gt;How Might We?&#34; (HMW)&lt;/a&gt;. It boils down to the selectivity and power of words, and in this case particularly with the choice of the word &#34;might&#34; rather than &#34;can&#34; or &#34;should.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s why the words make a difference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When people within companies try to innovate, they often talk about the challenges they’re facing by using language that can inhibit creativity instead of encouraging it, says the business consultant Min Basadur, who has taught the How Might We (HMW) form of questioning to companies over the past four decades. “People may start out asking, ‘How can we do this,’ or ‘How should we do that?,’” Basadur explained to me. “But as soon as you start using words like can and should, you’re implying judgment: Can we really do it? And should we?” By substituting the word might, he says, “you’re able to defer judgment, which helps people to create options more freely, and opens up more possibilities.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim Brown of IDEO talks about how the words carry meaning for problem solving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;[W]ithin the phrase, each of those three words plays a role in spurring creative problem solving. &#34;The &#39;how&#39; part assumes there are solutions out there — it provides creative confidence,&#34; Brown said to me &#34;&#34;Might&#39; says we can put ideas out there that might work or might not — either way, it’s OK. And the &#39;we&#39; part says we&#39;re going to do it together and build on each other’s ideas.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out how &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openideo.com/open&#34;&gt;IDEO are using the HMW phrasing at Open IDEO&lt;/a&gt; to get people thinking about and proposing how to solve challenges for social good. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been trying to do more to accentuate the positive, and keep conversations open to possibilities in my personal life and work, but it can be difficult to talk about solving problems without bias given agendas, missions, roadmaps, prior knowledge, and history. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing the word &#34;might&#34; feels like one way to begin early problem definition and solving without the weight  that comes from words like &#34;should&#34; or &#34;can.&#34; It&#39;s like the freedom in the tentative and erasable nature of a pencil rather than the indelibility of a pen. &#34;Might&#34; leads to conversation that is open to consider different directions rather than saddling you with choices that feel cemented too early. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Min Basadur&#39;s story about discovering the concept for Coast soap at Proctor and Gamble embodies this idea of opening up the conversation. The word &#34;might&#34; can lead to re-asking the question, and maybe even realizing that you&#39;re asking the wrong one. What I love most about that story is that ultimately asking &#34;How might we&#34; led back to asking &#34;Why?&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with the broader notions of starting with why, the HMW question seems a very powerful tool for facilitating design discussions and problem definition. I don&#39;t see very concrete, prescriptive techniques here, which is a good thing. The suggestion of asking the HMW question may be enough, but Brown warns that the size and types of design problem matter. HMW may not work for problems as big as &#34;How do we solve homelessness?&#34; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.hbr.org/2012/09/the-secret-phrase-top-innovato/&#34;&gt;Read more about HMW&lt;/a&gt; in the Harvard Business Review.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.hbr.org/2012/09/the-secret-phrase-top-innovato/&#34;&gt;http://blogs.hbr.org/2012/09/the-secret-phrase-top-innovato/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frontify: Design review, documentation, and specification app</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/frontify-design-review-documentation-and-specification-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/frontify-design-review-documentation-and-specification-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://frontify.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2850&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt5238f10c9c93d_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://frontify.com/&#34;&gt;Frontify&lt;/a&gt; looks like an interesting SaaS product for design teams. It provides collaborative features for getting design feedback, creating specifications, documentation and style guides, and linking pages together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commenting and linking features are what you&#39;d expect, but what I was really impressed with are the measures, colors, and typography tools for generating style guides. Very nicely done. There are additional capabilities for code export &amp;amp; integration with their API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://frontify.com/&#34;&gt;http://frontify.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macaw: Code-savvy web design tool</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/macaw-code-savvy-web-design-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/macaw-code-savvy-web-design-tool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://macaw.co/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2660&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt522e556ae08c0_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://macaw.co/&#34;&gt;Macaw&lt;/a&gt; is a forthcoming Mac application for designing pages for web browsers that are ready to use as web-native code. The app runs natively in html and css, and provides excellent export to clean html and css.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some great optimizations for nudging/pudging on a grid, and for setting properties that make sense for css—thinking of positioning and dimensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outline view is a nice way to browse through all the groups in the  document and adding container tags and/or classes for semantic html publishing. It&#39;s well matched to how you&#39;d think in html. It leap-frogs the heavier prototyping tools, but it&#39;s limited to creating static pages, like comps, for now. I&#39;m not sure what the graphics output options will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The html export is clean, maybe cleaner and more efficient than what I would write because it&#39;s a robot. Look really interesting, and is yet another approach to designing more directly for the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://macaw.co/peek/&#34;&gt;Watch the sneak preview video to learn more. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://macaw.co/&#34;&gt;http://macaw.co/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GoodUI Newsletter: Ideas for getting good conversion rates</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/goodui-newsletter-ideas-getting-good-conversion-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/goodui-newsletter-ideas-getting-good-conversion-rates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jakub Linowski, creator of &lt;a href=&#34;http://wireframes.linowski.ca/&#34;&gt;Wireframes Magazine&lt;/a&gt; just started writing a newsletter called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodui.org/&#34;&gt;Good UI&lt;/a&gt; on how to design sites that are easy to use and also yield high conversion rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He&#39;s looking at how to employ practical ideas that satisfy the business side as well as the people using it, which I&#39;m sure is something we all want to do on sites that sell a product or service. He plans to publish the newsletter monthly. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodui.org/&#34;&gt;Check it out.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodui.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.goodui.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPEVO Ziggi Review</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/ipevo-ziggi-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/ipevo-ziggi-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/tools/external/ipevoziggi1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Camera attached to computer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever done the dance of holding a sketch up to your computer&amp;rsquo;s webcam or taken pictures of them with your iPhone to email to yourself or to colleagues? I&amp;rsquo;ve done that sort of thing for all of the years that I&amp;rsquo;ve worked remotely on design and development teams, because scanners get tired real fast. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frustrated with this process, I had largely given up, until a few months ago when I was looking for tools to share work on paper between students and teachers. I stumbled upon the $89 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipevo.com/prods/IPEVO_Ziggi_USB_Document_Camera&#34;&gt;IPEVO Ziggi USB Document Camera&lt;/a&gt; and have been evaluating it for a few months now as a tool for design collaboration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been finding it easy to use for both shooting sketches for sharing in other apps, and for capturing and reviewing sketches with remote users using a screen-sharing tool like Skype. I now also believe it could be useful for other tasks including video capture for usability testing on mobile devices, and even presentations like one would do with an old school overhead projector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The compact camera folds down and fits in a small bag. It comes with a posable arm to adjust the camera height, a rotatable camera head, an anti-glare shield, and the P2V software is used to display the video on your screen or to a projector when in fullscreen mode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera includes buttons to adjust exposure, a focus button, and a switch to set autofocus on or off. These functions can also be controlled via the software interface. The software additionally provides a focussed mode for capture, a thumbnail view for review, and the fullscreen view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/tools/external/ipevoziggi2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Camera controls&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a closeup of the camera with the foldable anti-glare shield which can be used when capturing back lit devices like a smartphone or tablet screen. If you were to record an iOS device screen, you would keep this attached. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/tools/external/ipevoziggi3.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a low-resolution video I took of me sketching that you may have seen in a presentation I gave. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty low quality because of the movement and video compression since I used it in a presentation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/51043154?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;badge=0&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;419&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/51043154&#34;&gt;Sketch Basics&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/konigi&#34;&gt;konigi&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera itself has a 2.0-megapixel CMOS sensor with auto-focus and is capable of 30 fps live video capture (at 640 x 480). Still shots can be taken up to 12.2&amp;rdquo; x 9.1&amp;rdquo; (310 x 230mm) and offer resolutions up to 1600px x 1200px.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use the camera as an input for third party software like Skype or Google Talk, although you&amp;rsquo;ll lose some capture capabilities. If you&amp;rsquo;re capturing a test session you&amp;rsquo;re most likely want to screen capture the session with another app like Silverback or Screenflow. I&amp;rsquo;m also using the new Evernote page capture feature a lot with the Moleskine, but could see this device being a better alternative at a desktop. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;rsquo;m really pleased to have this as one of the few tools in my design arsenal. There are few that stay, but this one is turning out to be as useful as I&amp;rsquo;d hope it to be with little fuss. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipevo.com/prods/IPEVO_Ziggi_USB_Document_Camera&#34;&gt;http://www.ipevo.com/prods/IPEVO_Ziggi_USB_Document_Camera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your app is a collection of tiny details</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/your-app-collection-tiny-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/your-app-collection-tiny-details/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;t14&#34;&gt;&#34;Getting the details right is the difference between something that delights, and something customers tolerate.&#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8212;Jeff Atwood&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/05/this-is-all-your-app-is-a-collection-of-tiny-details.html&#34;&gt;Jeff Atwood&#39;s article about cat feeders&lt;/a&gt; right away, because it really is 90% about a cat product. It&#39;s also a terrific demonstration of what he&#39;s saying above. The first version of the product, a cat feeder, served a core need well enough for him to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satisficing&#34;&gt;satisfice&lt;/a&gt; with its shortcomings because the net return in time savings and improved quality of life, for him anyway, was absolutely worth it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The punchline is this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure you&#39;re first getting the primary function more or less right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the work of listening to users every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refine the details of your product based on their feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening to the opinions expressed by customers, obsessing over the details, and getting them right in the design is necessary and hard. But over time, if the points of pain are incrementally addressed and the design improved, the collection of those well-thought-out details embody a better experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get better slowly, but &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; get better. Suck it up and feel your users&#39; pain. Assure them that you&#39;re listening by sweating the details. &lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/05/this-is-all-your-app-is-a-collection-of-tiny-details.html&#34;&gt;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/05/this-is-all-your-app-is-a-collection-of-tiny-details.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Realizing Empathy: An Inquiry into the Meaning of Making</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/realizing-empathy-inquiry-meaning-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/realizing-empathy-inquiry-meaning-making/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;360px&#34; src=&#34;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/800798301/realizing-empathy-an-inquiry-into-the-meaning-of-m/widget/video.html&#34; width=&#34;480px&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seung Chan Lim, better known as Slim, spent 10 years making software, working in computer science and interaction design at MAYA Design where he was the Assistant Director of Engineering. After some soul searching he began to ask why he was doing what he was doing, and at the suggestion of a mentor, he went out to do something different, something he didn&amp;rsquo;t understand. He went to art school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slim&amp;rsquo;s book explores how making works (as a process), what it means (to make something), and why it matters (to our lives). Through this exploration the book also investigates the ethics of our relationship to Computer Technology, and proposes a new direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the idea of learning something new and unfamiliar as a way of expanding one&amp;rsquo;s perspective. Two of my favorite articles/talks in recent years that relate to this topic are &lt;a href=&#34;bill-buxton-how-keep-innovating.html&#34;&gt;Bill Buxton&amp;rsquo;s article on how to keep innovating&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;paula-scher-gets-serious-ted.html&#34;&gt;Paula Scher&amp;rsquo;s Ted Talk on finding fun in the unfamiliar.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judging by the introduction video, the book looks to be substantial, exploratory, humble, and inspiring. I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to reading it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is being funded now, so if you want to see it happen like I do, you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://kck.st/whvn03&#34;&gt;back this project on Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/800798301/realizing-empathy-an-inquiry-into-the-meaning-of-m&#34;&gt;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/800798301/realizing-empathy-an-inquiry-into-the-meaning-of-m&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Omnigraffle Stencil for Twitter Bootstrap 2</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/omnigraffle-stencil-twitter-bootstrap-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/omnigraffle-stencil-twitter-bootstrap-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.viget.com/advance/an-omnigraffle-stencil-for-twitter-bootstrap-2/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2695&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt522fc4ff89557_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The team at Viget have created a free &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.viget.com/advance/an-omnigraffle-stencil-for-twitter-bootstrap-2/&#34;&gt;OmniGraffle stencil for designing interfaces with Twitter Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.viget.com/advance/an-omnigraffle-stencil-for-twitter-bootstrap-2/&#34;&gt;http://www.viget.com/advance/an-omnigraffle-stencil-for-twitter-bootstrap-2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offscreen Magazine</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/offscreen-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/offscreen-magazine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.offscreenmag.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/offscreen-magazine.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.offscreenmag.com/&#34;&gt;Offscreen&lt;/a&gt; is a print magazine that takes an in-depth look at the life and work of people that create websites and apps. They&amp;rsquo;re interested in telling the less obvious human stories of creativity, passion and hard work that hide behind every interface.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first issue includes conversations with web standards wizard Dan Cederholm, all-round-talent Drew Wilson, former last.fm design lead Hannah Donovan, 37signals&#39; designer and product manager Ryan Singer, design entrepreneur Andrew Wilkinson and pixel-perfectionist Benjamin de Cock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.offscreenmag.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.offscreenmag.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design is the fundamental soul of a human-made creation</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/design-fundamental-soul-human-made-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/design-fundamental-soul-human-made-creation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/apple1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Apple I&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://adam-pritzker.com/post/11099896089/in-most-peoples-vocabularies-design-means&#34;&gt;Adam Pritzker&lt;/a&gt; deftly combined this image of an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_I&#34;&gt;Apple I&lt;/a&gt; and this &lt;a href=&#34;http://money.cnn.com/magazines/fortune/fortune_archive/2000/01/24/272277/&#34;&gt;Steve Jobs quote on design&lt;/a&gt; from an interview in 2000 that appeared in Fortune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In most people’s vocabularies, design means veneer. It’s interior decorating. It’s the fabric of the curtains of the sofa. But to me, nothing could be further from the meaning of design. Design is the fundamental soul of a human-made creation that ends up expressing itself in successive outer layers of the product or service.” - Steve Jobs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an expression of that soul of the creator, in the running failures and successes of the executed design, that attempts to make a connection with the user of the product. Some products are imbued with the soul of a passionate creative force, others become refined to the point of feeling somber. Underneath the surface of Apple products, there&amp;rsquo;s always been a sense of human connection, either in the literal early smiley Mac icons, or in the more polished and subtle interactions and connections we have with machines using our touch screens today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no way to understate how much Apple products have influenced what I do every day. I learned Basic and how to type in high shool on an Apple II. I played Tetris for the first time on a friend&amp;rsquo;s original beige Mac. The first computer I ever spent my own money on was a PowerBook 520c, the very one I learned HTML on. With each successive generation of polish, in every one of these machines I&amp;rsquo;ve touched, I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt that connection, and that desire to want to play with computers. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be doing what I do now if Jobs&amp;rsquo; Mac never existed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every product starts somewhere, but as with people, the soul is what sustains the connection. It&amp;rsquo;s heartening and inspiring to me to think back on this legacy of product design and where it started. It makes me feel like every naive notion I have about design is OK as long as I have a passion to improve and deliver something with soul.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letting Go</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/letting-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two great slides from Yiibu&#39;s presentation, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/yiibu/letting-go-9109114&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;Letting Go&lt;/a&gt;, a talk about design in an time of increasing disruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6170/6188891324_71eb68e152_z.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#34;Issuing your customers with something that is rough, incomplete, and possibly even substandard seems counterintuitive but there is growing evidence that people don&#39;t necessarily want the perfect product. They prefer to deal with something ragged around the edges that they can adapt or improve.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8212;  Martin Thomas in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Loose-Future-Business-Letting-Go/dp/0755361555&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&#34;Loose: The Future of Business is Letting Go&#34;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6127/6189715023_b5fc1f1b73_z.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#34;The best designs will set the stage, but stop short of fully defining the experience.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8212; Adam Silver, Frog Design&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awesome presentation deck. Would have loved to see and hear it in person. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/yiibu/letting-go-9109114&#34;&gt;See the full presentation here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Photo credits: &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/tiseb/13541804&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/hodac/2243470147&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/yiibu/letting-go-9109114&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/yiibu/letting-go-9109114&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why The Valley Wants Designers That Can Code</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/why-valley-wants-designers-can-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/why-valley-wants-designers-can-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jared Spool talks about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2011/05/31/why-the-valley-wants-designers-that-can-code/&#34;&gt;why designers who code are popular in Silicon Valley&lt;/a&gt; right now, and for the most part, it boils down to this. Small software and web startups value and are able to use a broader range of skillsets, because one of the highest priorities, especially for bootstrapped startups, is to ship while lean on resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jared notes that those who don&#39;t think designers should know how to code say this dilutes the designer&#39;s value. I think we&#39;re talking both interaction designers and visual designers here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main point for me is that particular organizations favor someone more M-shaped than T-shaped, which is to say, they need to be deeper in more than one set of skills. This is true of more types of organizations than just small startups, but the main idea is that multi-role people &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; valued in organizations that are open to having  a person who can execute on a diverse set of responsibilities, even if they&#39;re viewed as &amp;quot;diluted&amp;quot; in terms of being less deep in one area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll say this. I started out doing interface design and development work on databases in-house in a corporation. Early on in my career, I envied the people who got to work on the sexy, high-profile projects and made the switch to doing front end-development at an agency. Unsatisfied with that, I went back in-house doing both design and development, and then envied the design side, and went to a company to do interaction design only. I&#39;ve never been satisfied in a silo, and have been happiest being involved across a project. I&#39;ve found that working on both ends as a designer and developer to be ideal for me, even if the development is only front-end development and prototyping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I don&#39;t think it is particularly easy to find a home when you&#39;re more M than T-shaped. Certain types of organizations won&#39;t even let you interview for more than one type of role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve spoken to quite a few people looking to make a shift from one side to another over the years. It&#39;s kind of easy to recognize an M-shaped person. They may have worked in small organizations that gave them more room to flex their muscles outside of their role, or they may be freelancers that get to and maybe have to do design and development. For whatever reason, that varied experience can make it hard for them to find the right home and to convince hiring people to consider a cross-disciplinary role to fit them into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I think what Jared is talking about could be very helpful to both the budding UX designers out there, and those considering making a change in role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems obvious to say, but if you can already do some development and you want to use it, you might look for an organization that values it. Small startups or in-house positions with small development organizations where multi-role people are valued is a good start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can&#39;t do some kind of code, at least learn HTML5, CSS and a little Javascript, and maybe some other server-side scripting languages. If you can&#39;t convince your organization to use you in that capacity, then demonstrate your skill doing prototypes in code when the opportunity presents itself, and keep your skills sharp. When there seems like no way to flex your development muscles in your current job, work on personal projects continually to stay sharp and relevant!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2011/05/31/why-the-valley-wants-designers-that-can-code/&#34;&gt;Read more at UIE&lt;/a&gt;. Interested in learning to code for the web? There are &lt;a href=&#34;../wiki/learn-code.html&#34;&gt;some resources for that here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2011/05/31/why-the-valley-wants-designers-that-can-code/&#34;&gt;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2011/05/31/why-the-valley-wants-designers-that-can-code/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have a nice day</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/have-nice-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/have-nice-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;Don&#39;t let anyone tell you that the tools you choose are wrong or inappropriate. Find the right design and keep winning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally I&#39;m asked to provide an opinion about a topic that people think I should have some authority to comment on for some reason. That topic, as you might guess, is wireframing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy pointing people towards good resources, or helping them with a problem using a tool that I&#39;m familiar with. I also love to give my own design resources to peers, or to teach techniques that I think will help people perfect their craft. In the end, I benefit from that exchange the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked to comment on slanted opinions that throw a stake in the ground and tend to confuse and divide the community, I abstain. Navel gazing and defining the damned thing became an uninteresting use of time to me long ago. It took some time immersed in those conversations to know that I have nothing to contribute. I&#39;d rather be making stuff than talking about it. I just say call yourself whatever you like, and do whatever works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interface design tools are as good as you make them. When I started out, I had to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=michael+angeles+visio&#34;&gt;Visio&lt;/a&gt; to communicate UI specs. It wasn&#39;t awesome, but I made it work. Later I found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=michael+angeles+omnigraffle&#34;&gt;Omnigraffle&lt;/a&gt;. It was not designed specifically to enable interface designers, but we made it awesome. We learned how to use it to make our documents communicate design ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are the ones who determine what&#39;s useful for us after immersion in tools. We&#39;ve debated what we want in the ultimate IA tool, we&#39;ve found parallels in other industries and fields of practice and made them our own. We&#39;ve experimented with forward-looking low-fidelity prototyping projects like Denim, and pondered what the right suite of tools are for our work. Some of us built them and shared our work. Some of us are still building them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over years of working and watching others work, I&#39;ve noticed that some attributes are common among the people whose work I admire. The people who are the most effective seem to continue to study their practice, and perfect their craft. After long hours of use, they find the way to flow within any app at their disposal, and become as fast and effective as they can using it. The key is what they do with the app once they&#39;ve become expert at their craft, expert in finding the right design, expert in communicating, and expert in refining. There&#39;s some kind of maker/doer tenacity I see in people, and it doesn&#39;t have to do with any one tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no good or bad tools for finding the right design. Paper prototypes are your thing? Awesome. If you want to sketch and go right to building in HTML? Go for it! I&#39;ve done it. You want to craft gray box schematics in OmniGraffle, Photoshop, or Mockups? Godspeed you wireframer. Maybe I can help you with that. You want to use a tool that generates interactive prototypes? Have a nice day. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the side-taking is useless to me. If you&#39;ve ever interviewed people for an IA or IXD position, you know that beautiful documents and prototypes are meaningless if in the end they don&#39;t demonstrate good problem solving and good design decision making. I don&#39;t care what people use. They can use finger puppets and crayons if they help them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say use whatever makes sense or is at your disposal. Your tools are only as effective as you are at using them to accomplish goals. But don&#39;t let anyone tell you that what you choose is wrong or inappropriate. Find the right design and keep winning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring for designers</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/refactoring-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/refactoring-designers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2738-refactoring-for-designers&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2470&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4d2f00c650db8_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ryan Singer at 37signals &lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2738-refactoring-for-designers&#34;&gt;explains code refactoring to designers&lt;/a&gt; so that they can use it correctly in a design context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Designers sometimes use the word “refactor” in a loose way. I think they overhear the word from programmers without getting the precise meaning. This article will introduce the term to designers so they can gain the same advantages that programmers have from a clear understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do designers loosely understand refactoring? Many take it to mean “rearranging” a design or “adjusting without completely rethinking” it. Refactoring actually means something else. It means changing the way a design is built without changing the way it looks from the outside.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2738-refactoring-for-designers&#34;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt; at svn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2738-refactoring-for-designers&#34;&gt;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2738-refactoring-for-designers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>