<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Hugo: Konigi is now a Static Site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/hello-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/hello-hugo/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;After many years of being a Drupal user, from version 2 when I started iaslash.org to version 6 on this site, I&amp;rsquo;ve made the move from PHP/MySQL blog to full on static site. Here&amp;rsquo;s why and how I did it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;choosing-static-site-generators:559804b0a39dd16d2d1d1238c597145a&#34;&gt;Choosing Static Site Generators&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a few sites backwards from Drupal and WordPress into the age of static sites. In many ways, it feels like going back to the beginning of my career, when I used Perl and Shell scripts to generate sites in my first job, and later to more sophisticated site generation using MovableType as a middle man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As each of the small personal projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on became bigger, I started to miss how simple things used to be, and loathe how much I had to babysit my site or pay a lot for better cloud MySQL instances. In my day job, we also had to deal with the regular security patches on WP and Drupal, and it became a drag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started our first experiment by moving a site to Hammer, then shortly after moved it to become a grunt generated site. Those sites are happily chugging along, maintained by a team that generates the pages with grunt. Our main site at &lt;a href=&#34;http://balsamiq.com&#34;&gt;balsamiq.com&lt;/a&gt; is one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that year or so of being happy with how simple those site are to maintain, I started looking at more powerful &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/static-site-generator-directories/&#34;&gt;static site generators&lt;/a&gt; and finally migrated this site content off of Drupal so it can be used by a static generator. I now use &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; to generate the few thousand pages of this site in a few seconds and sync it to AWS S3 using their static site hosting options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; is a generator written in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; programming language. I chose Hugo over a few of the other great options out there like Jekkyl and Octopress because of its speed, support for taxonomies, and markdown support. I&amp;rsquo;m no programmer, so my implementation of Hugo is very simple and I put together my theme using only the examples in the docs, and a couple of questions to the discussion forum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten my head around how to do more complex things yet, and I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be the newb that inundates the forum with dense questions. If you happen to find yourself in that forum you&amp;rsquo;ll see how little I understand, despite reading docs. But for now, after a few weeks of work with only a few days of template building, it&amp;rsquo;s doing nearly everything I did in Drupal, with none of the overhead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;migrating-content-off-drupal:559804b0a39dd16d2d1d1238c597145a&#34;&gt;Migrating Content Off Drupal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started, I created a modified version of my Drupal theme that exports all of my content to text files. I removed all the views and only exported the actual node contents. Each node includes Hugo&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;front matter&amp;rdquo; at the top of each page. This is the metadata that describes title, tags, permalink slug, and publish date. I pared down my taxonomy use on this site to one tag taxonomy for the time being to simplify things. I had taxonomies for people, company, color, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After testing to see that what I output was formatted to properly get read by Hugo, I then used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.httrack.com/&#34;&gt;httrack&lt;/a&gt; to download all of the nodes of content to my machine. Each file was downloaded into a subfolder for the corresponding sections used by the global nav and the url paths on the site. I ran the files all through a file renamer to add .md (markdown) extensions. I use &lt;a href=&#34;http://manytricks.com/namemangler/&#34;&gt;Name Mangler&lt;/a&gt; on the Mac for renaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These articles helped with figuring out the export part of the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lullabot.com/blog/article/sending-drupal-site-retirement&#34;&gt;Sending a Drupal Site Into Retirement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.drupal.org/node/27882&#34;&gt;Creating a static archive of a Drupal site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;building-it-in-hugo:559804b0a39dd16d2d1d1238c597145a&#34;&gt;Building it in Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next step was to install Hugo and generate a basic Hugo site with the .md files I downloaded. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/overview/introduction/&#34;&gt;Hugo docs&lt;/a&gt; show you how to create a Hugo site and install a theme. I did this first to test out the content. Then I started learning how templates work and built my own straight from the docs, looking at a few examples to figure out how to create taxonomy views. I started with a skeleton template that just spits out a nav and bodies, then made some section views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next was CSS/JS asset management. I copied over my SASS files and JS. I also decided to switch from the Bootstrap grid to Foundation, so I stripped down a lot of styles and the layout. After years of changing layout ideas, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to trim the SASS layout files down to nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To manage the pre-processing, minifying and building of JS and SASS/CSS I had to set up a task manager. I decided to learn how Gulp handles this compared to Grunt, and I like how simple and clean my Gulpfile.js is. It works about the same as Grunt, so there was little to learn there. &lt;a href=&#34;http://markgoodyear.com/2014/01/getting-started-with-gulp/&#34;&gt;This post on getting started with gulp&lt;/a&gt; is good if all you&amp;rsquo;re interested in is processing Sass. There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of StackOverflow articles on processing JS. I only run gulp whenever I make a change to JS or SASS which is rare, and the minified files get included with the Hugo build command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My process for writing new content now is to start up Atom, create a new .md file in the appropriate directory, then run &amp;ldquo;hugo server &amp;ndash;watch&amp;rdquo; to test it. When I&amp;rsquo;m happy with my writing, I run &amp;ldquo;hugo&amp;rdquo; to build files into my /public directory and I&amp;rsquo;m ready to deploy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last step is a command that uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://s3tools.org/s3cmd&#34;&gt;s3cmd&lt;/a&gt; to sync only the changed pages to the generated public directory, removing deletions. See the options in the docs for doing this. There are many blog posts with different suggestions for how to deploy, but I found all I needed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.programblings.com/2013/07/12/hosting-a-website-on-s3/&#34;&gt;in this one on Programblings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve done to date and it&amp;rsquo;s working well. My next steps are to get everything on Git and hooked up to a middleman that will automate the deploy part of the process. So far I&amp;rsquo;m very happy, and after a few years of trying different tools, this set feels right&amp;hellip; until the next change. The older I get, however, the less I want to waste time on stuff like this, so it feels like a keeper. Huge thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://spf13.com/&#34;&gt;Steve Francia&lt;/a&gt; for creating Hugo and to everyone who contribute to it. If a simple-minded UX designer like me can use it, that&amp;rsquo;s saying a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Site Generator Directories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/static-site-generator-directories/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/static-site-generator-directories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are the 2 main directories listing generators that you can use to build a static site. Each offers a sortable lists to browse by user rating or language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.staticgen.com/&#34;&gt;StaticGen&lt;/a&gt; - Lists the top Open Source static site generators only. Filter by language. Sort by rating, issues, forks, titles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://staticsitegenerators.net/&#34;&gt;Static Site Generators&lt;/a&gt; - Lists Open Source and Commercial static site generators. Sort by rating, license, and language.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nulo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/music/nulo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/music/nulo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve hinted at starting to play with music for a little while now. I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten past the point of just being overwhelmed and uncertain about whether I can learn to create music, and am now immersed in learning. Here&amp;rsquo;s the story, and why you may start to see me blog about music now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2013 I committed to teaching a mixing (DJing) workshop to a group of colleagues, having rediscovered mixing with digital music. I mixed house and electronic music as a teenager (because Filipino) and college student, and then bedroom DJ through the years until I settled into an IA/IXD career, had kids, etc. I returned to bedroom DJ status when I acquired Traktor, and that&amp;rsquo;s rekindled the love I have for electronic music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the year since I started mixing again, I&amp;rsquo;ve rediscovered a love for deep house, techno, ambient, and electronic music in general. I found a wonderful piano teacher where I live and have been taking piano lessons and learning music production. This year I made a commitment to start making my own music with the goal of putting it on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s something gratifying about the beginning of a new project. Learning a new skill from zero feels daunting. I have some history and references to draw upon. I&amp;rsquo;ve begun to study and do research to become steeped in the language and tools of the craft. I&amp;rsquo;ve started to read everything I can find about creators in that field, and yearn to know how they create. I realize with excitement that there is a lot to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think some people find it odd that I&amp;rsquo;m starting this new pursuit this late in life. The best way I know how to deal with an itch is to scratch it. So I&amp;rsquo;m starting this music blog to share my thoughts in this new pursuit. I&amp;rsquo;m already finding a lot of spillover into other creative work as I do this, so maybe that will be interesting to others. For some, this may be a reason to stop following this blog, and I fully understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those that stick around, thanks for taking the time to read this and explore with me. -Michael&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balsamiq Mockups Version 3 Released</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/balsamiq-mockups-version-3-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/balsamiq-mockups-version-3-released/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.balsamiq.com/product/2015/03/10/b3/&#34;&gt;released version 3 of Balsamiq Mockups today&lt;/a&gt;! There&#39;s plenty to see including an updated interface, new file format (single packaged project files), better asset and symbols management, the addition of &lt;a href=&#34;http://fortawesome.github.io/Font-Awesome/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;FontAwesome&lt;/a&gt; icons, and plenty of improvements under the surface. We point out some of the highlights in the video below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-Zz8EYPhEew?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s plenty more under the hood, and lots of new stuff on deck. You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.balsamiq.com/product/2015/03/10/b3/&#34;&gt;read all about it in the announcement&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s a free update to existing users. &lt;a href=&#34;http://balsamiq.com/download/&#34;&gt;Download it here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to all of the great customers giving us feedback over the years, and particularly those who we talked to in our forum, in our Beta group, our usability test sessions, and in the hallways at Interaction 15 this year. Much more to come!&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.balsamiq.com/product/2015/03/10/b3/&#34;&gt;http://blogs.balsamiq.com/product/2015/03/10/b3/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astropad: Use iPad as Mac Graphics Tablet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/astropad-use-ipads-mac-graphics-tablet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/astropad-use-ipads-mac-graphics-tablet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;853&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ouwCHT3rGRY&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://astropad.com/&#34;&gt;AstroPad&lt;/a&gt; turns your iPad into a Mac graphics tablet, mirroring a section of your Mac&amp;rsquo;s screen when connected via WiFi or USB. Once connected you can sketch/draw on the tablet with an iPad stylus or finger. It will operate pretty much like a Wacom graphics tablet when you&amp;rsquo;re using a Desktop graphics app with a drawing tool like Pixelmator, Photoshop, or Sketchbook Pro. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://astropad.com/&#34;&gt;http://astropad.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAPERPROTO</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/paperproto/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/paperproto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://paperproto.com/&#34;&gt;PAPERPROTO&lt;/a&gt; is a 3D printable model to use for paper prototyping mobile applications, in the style of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifestyle.howstuffworks.com/crafts/seasonal/winter/theatre-activities-for-kids7.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;story scroll&lt;/a&gt;. You can download the file or buy the model for printing on demand directly from Shapeways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;http://zekefranco.com/&#34;&gt;Zeke Franco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://paperproto.com/&#34;&gt;http://paperproto.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinterest Mobile Radial Menus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interface/pinterest-mobile-radial-menus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interface/pinterest-mobile-radial-menus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pinterest&#39;s mobile app displays a radial menu if you tap on an image. The menu items are for functions that are also available using the icons and buttons in the top of the UI for allowing you to pin, like, or send the image.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;caption aptureNoAutolink&#34;&gt;Screencast / Video&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-object&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/jeGkxfY_UOM&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pinterest.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.pinterest.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinterest Tag Search and Suggestions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interface/pinterest-tag-search-and-suggestions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interface/pinterest-tag-search-and-suggestions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pinterest&#39;s search feature shows tag and board suggestions in the auto-completion list. Select terms/tags to display, and a horizontal list (accordion) of correlating tags to refine or narrow your your search are displayed below the search box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;caption aptureNoAutolink&#34;&gt;Screencast / Video&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-object&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/JpIEOVTY-a8&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pinterest.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.pinterest.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tumblr Fave Animation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interface/tumblr-fave-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interface/tumblr-fave-animation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a small animation of the  heart/broken heart that is shown when favoriting or unfaving a Tumblr post in the mobile app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;caption aptureNoAutolink&#34;&gt;Screencast / Video&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-object&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/8bxvrHabfLA&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tumblr.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.tumblr.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX Check</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/ux-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/ux-check/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uxcheck.co/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2894&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt54b5949b0d995_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uxcheck.co/&#34;&gt;UX Check&lt;/a&gt; is a Google Chrome extension for reviewing web sites and apps against &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nngroup.com/articles/ten-usability-heuristics/&#34;&gt;Jakob Neilsen&amp;rsquo;s Usability Heuristics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tool opens the heuristics in a side panel next to the website you enter. You select a problem area on the screen, related to one of the usability heuristics and a callout appears for you to add notes and recommendations. When you&#39;re done a report is available with screenshots and your notes for each issue. You can download the report as HTML or in Word .docx format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looks like a nice tool for evaluating web sites in Chrome, as long as the pages you&#39;re reviewing have selectable DOM elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uxcheck.co/&#34;&gt;http://www.uxcheck.co/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Accessibility Project</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/accessibility-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/accessibility-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a11yproject.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2892&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt54aef2f5871cc_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://a11yproject.com/&#34;&gt;A11Y project&lt;/a&gt; is a community-driven effort to make web accessibility easier. They provide articles on best practices for doing front end development with accessibility in mind. The site includes an &lt;a href=&#34;http://a11yproject.com/checklist.html&#34;&gt;accessibility checklist&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://a11yproject.com/patterns/&#34;&gt;a pattern library&lt;/a&gt; for accessible widgets, and a list of resources for diving deeper into web accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a11yproject.com/&#34;&gt;http://a11yproject.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mention Call To Action</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/interface/mention-call-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/interface/mention-call-action/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mention.com&#39;s Success Stories section  uses this great phrase to introduce the Proof in the drip pan at the bottom of the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;They also started with a free trial.&amp;quot; Short and persuasive copy that makes an otherwise common CTA more compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div id=&#34;screens-full&#34; class=&#34;clear&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;1. Intro text, subdued company logos for the proof (so as not to compete with the CTA), and bold red call to action button to create your first alert and start a free trial.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;fullimg clear&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/interface/mention-cta-1.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;1. Intro text, subdued company logos for the proof (so as not to compete with the CTA), and bold red...&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/interface/mention-cta-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.mention.com/success-stories&#34;&gt;https://en.mention.com/success-stories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX Project Checklist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/ux-project-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/ux-project-checklist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/tools/external/ux-project-checklist.png&#34; class=&#34;bluga-thumbnail custom&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://uxchecklist.github.io/&#34;&gt;UX Checklist&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sovesove&#34;&gt;Andrea Soverini&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; is a nice overview of potential UX-related tools and techniques that you could use for product design. It provides a layered visualization of a design process, like an extension of JJG&#39;s layers, with links to articles on the technique. Would make a good poster for a workspace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uxchecklist.github.io/&#34;&gt;http://uxchecklist.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Songs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/music/songs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/music/songs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing like the exquisite pain of starting something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; frameborder=&#34;no&#34; src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/playlists/94505333&amp;amp;color=499bd7&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RemoteIE: Remote Testing for Internet Explorer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/remoteie-remote-testing-internet-explorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/remoteie-remote-testing-internet-explorer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://remote.modern.ie/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2888&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt5457d9055ee6c_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://remote.modern.ie/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Remote Desktop app&lt;/a&gt; lets you use Azure RemoteApp to test your site on IE (on Windows 10 Technical Preview from anywhere). After you download the app for Mac, Windows iOS or Android, you can connect to their cloud-based version of IE.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://remote.modern.ie/&#34;&gt;https://remote.modern.ie/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>