<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wiki on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/categories/wiki/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wiki on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/categories/wiki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/wiki/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/wiki/quotes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;book-body&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the quotes I&#39;ve collected from artists and designers that have some relevance to doing business in web and software product design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Art and Design Movie Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve made it a habit to try and find documentaries about an art/craft to watch whenever I fly, so it made sense to take notes as I would in my journal and put them up here for inspiration. You&#39;ll find quotes from the following movies here:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc0&#34;&gt;Sound City (2013)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2306745/&#34; title=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2306745/&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2306745/&#34;&gt;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2306745/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://soundcitymovie.com/&#34; title=&#34;http://soundcitymovie.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://soundcitymovie.com/&#34;&gt;http://soundcitymovie.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc1&#34;&gt;Keith Olsen, producer engineer, on the role of the producer.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;He is the vehicle to get the artist&#39;s creativity on the tape in a way that is accessible to the marketplace. What you have to do is get the listener to claim what you&#39;ve done as theirs.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
00:36:18&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc2&#34;&gt;Trent Reznor on digital tools and starting with a message.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Now that everyone is empowered with these great tools to create stuff has there been a lot more great shit coming up? Not really. You have to have something to do with those tools. You should really try to have something to say.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
01:29:00&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc3&#34;&gt;Dave Grohl / James Brown on constraints.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;One of the things that I think makes good music is some sort of restriction. ... That&#39;s where 24 track mentality comes in. You commit to what it is. With Pro Tools you can always come back to it, or you can change it, or you can add to it to try and make it work, because you&#39;re being forced to make choices--creative ones.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc4&#34;&gt;Dave Grohl on creativity.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Do it. Make it simple. Make it fast. Don&#39;t overthink it. Let it come straight out of you and do it.”&lt;br /&gt;
01:33:30&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc5&#34;&gt;Watch:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Sound-City-NEIL-YOUNG/dp/B00B4Z5J92/&#34;&gt;On Amazon Instant Play (free for Prime)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/movies/details/Sound_City?id=MX1A-H_lrTk&#34;&gt;On Google Play&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/movie/sound-city/id587612681&#34;&gt;On iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc6&#34;&gt;Side by Side (2012)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sidebysidethemovie.com/&#34; title=&#34;http://sidebysidethemovie.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sidebysidethemovie.com/&#34;&gt;http://sidebysidethemovie.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2014338/&#34; title=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2014338/&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2014338/&#34;&gt;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2014338/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc7&#34;&gt;Director Danny Boyle on the evolution of movie watching from the movie theater to computer and mobile devices.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You gotta go with it, and if you become unable to deal with it, then thats fine because it means your time is finished and it&#39;s time for othe people to take it on. &lt;br /&gt;
01:22:34&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc8&#34;&gt;Vittorio Storaro, cinematographer on accepting change.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you are participating in the revolution, we will be lost in past. We can’t count ourselves out and say, “We don’t care. It’s up to you guys.” No. So we have to be in.&lt;br /&gt;
01:34:20&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc9&#34;&gt;Michael Ballhause, cinematographer, on creativity and medium.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything comes down to one thing. If you do something with your heart. If you do something you&#39;re convinced of and feel about it, it doesn&#39;t matter what you&#39;re using. &lt;br /&gt;
01:35:43&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc10&#34;&gt;Watch:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Side-Derek-Ambrosi/dp/B0090EJZA8/&#34;&gt;On Amazon Instant Play&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/movies/details/Side_by_Side?id=jxovgnr3ODY&#34;&gt;On Google Play&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/movie/side-by-side/id550069703&#34;&gt;On iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;On Creativity&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Secret to creativity is knowing how to hide your sources.&lt;br /&gt;
–Albert Einstein&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything you can imagine is real.&lt;br /&gt;
–Pablo Picasso&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience is the name everyone gives to their mistakes.&lt;br /&gt;
–Oscar Wilde&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In order to be irreplaceable one must always be different.” &lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://aconversationoncool.tumblr.com/post/556377546/in-order-to-be-irreplaceable-one-must-always-be&#34;&gt;Coco Chanel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just as Steve loved ideas, and loved making stuff, he treated the process of creativity with a rare and a wonderful reverence. You see, I think he better than anyone understood that while ideas ultimately can be so powerful, they begin as fragile, barely formed thoughts, so easily missed, so easily compromised, so easily just squished.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/nPUsuY8JZJI&#34;&gt;Jonathan Ive at the Steve Jobs Tribute&lt;/a&gt; on the Apple campus. His talk starts around 47:17 right after Tim Cook introduces him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d like to talk about the one thing that&#39;s been consistent over the years—the genesis and power of creativity. ... It’s all about how you’re putting what you do together. The elements you’re using don’t matter. Purity of human expression and experience is not confined to guitars, to tubes, to turntables, to microchips. There’s no right way, no pure way of doing it—there’s just doing it.&lt;br /&gt;
– From Bruce Springsteen&#39;s inspiring &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/2012/03/16/148778665/bruce-springsteens-sxsw-2012-keynote-speech&#34;&gt;2012 SXSW Keynote Speech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rumble, young musicians, rumble. Open your ears and open your hearts. Don&#39;t take yourself too seriously, and take yourself as seriously as death itself. Don&#39;t worry. Worry your ass off. Have unclad confidence, but doubt. It keeps you awake and alert. Believe you are the baddest ass in town-and you suck! It keeps you honest. Be able to keep two completely contradictory ideals alive and well inside of your heart and head at all times. If it doesn&#39;t drive you crazy, it will make you strong.  And stay hard, stay hungry and stay alive. And when you walk on stage tonight to bring the noise, treat it like it&#39;s all we have-and then remember it&#39;s only rock &#39;n&#39; roll.&lt;br /&gt;
– From Bruce Springsteen&#39;s inspiring &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/2012/03/16/148778665/bruce-springsteens-sxsw-2012-keynote-speech&#34;&gt;2012 SXSW Keynote Speech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;On Product Design&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good design is as little design as possible. &lt;br /&gt;
-Dieter Rams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simplest way to achieve simplicity is through thoughtful reduction.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://lawsofsimplicity.com/2006/07/23/law-1-reduce-3&#34;&gt;John Maeda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working on the right thing is probably more important than working hard.&lt;br /&gt;
–Caterina Fake&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You spend so much more time to make it less conspicuous, less obvious. And if you think about it, so many of the products we&#39;re surrounded by, they want you to be very aware of just how clever the solution was. &lt;br /&gt;
-Jonathan Ive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we do the job of those 6 parts as one?&lt;br /&gt;
–Jonathan Ive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very important turning point for me was the term &#39;obsessive sketch&#39; by Takama Kyoshi, the haiku master. When the poet&#39;s sentiments are overly visible, the audience may become uncomfortable. By writing simply and only about what is there, the audience is drawn into the poet&#39;s world. Their imagination is stimulated, and a silent connection is established. I believe this is where the most important aspect of the Japanese sense of beauty lies. &lt;br /&gt;
-Naoto Fukasawa&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had to summarize our learnings in three words: &amp;quot;simple trumps complete.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quora.com/What-types-of-things-does-Netflix-A-B-test-aside-from-member-sign-up&#34;&gt;Neil Hunt on Netflix A-B testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t need every customer. I’m primarily in the business of selling a product for money. How much effort do I really want to devote to satisfying people who are unable or extremely unlikely to pay for anything?…&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marco.org/2011/04/28/removed-instapaper-free&#34;&gt;Marco Arment, Instapaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people argue software should be agnostic. They say it&#39;s arrogant for developers to limit features or ignore feature requests. They say software should always be as flexible as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think that&#39;s bullshit. The best software has a vision. The best software takes sides. When someone uses software, they&#39;re not just looking for features, they&#39;re looking for an approach. They&#39;re looking for a vision. Decide what your vision is and run with it.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://gettingreal.37signals.com/ch04_Make_Opinionated_Software.php&#34;&gt;Jason Fried, Getting Real&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you build an app always look out for the non-essential features. Make sure they don’t make it into your v1.0. They slow down your release, they dilute your focus, they require resources that pull you away from perfecting the core of your app, and they open the door to more bugs at launch.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/archives2/essential_vs_nonessential.php&#34;&gt;Jason Fried&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best designers and the best programmers aren’t the ones with the best skills, or the nimblest fingers, or the ones who can rock and roll with photoshop or vim, they are the ones that can determine what just doesn’t matter. That’s where the real gains are made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time you spend is wasted time on things that just don’t matter. If you can cut out the work and thinking that just doesn’t matter you’ll achieve productivity you’ve never imagined. It’s there if you just don’t pay attention to the things that don’t matter.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/archives2/it_just_doesnt_matter.php&#34;&gt;Jason Fried&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Minimum Viable Product”. MVP, if you aren’t familiar, is an idea from the Lean Startup scene. In a nutshell, it means to do as little as possible so you can learn if you did the right thing or not.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2963-what-happens-to-user-experience-in-a-minimum-viable-product&#34;&gt;Jason Fried&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you know when it&#39;s done? The question is: when is it good enough?&lt;br /&gt;
Good enough, for those that seek perfection, is what we call it when it&#39;s sufficient to surpass the standards we&#39;ve set. Anything beyond good enough is called stalling and a waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&#39;t like your definition of &#39;good enough&#39;, then feel free to change that, but the goal before shipping is merely that. Not perfect.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/06/how-do-you-know-when-its-done.html&#34;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Good design, when done well, should be invisible.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2008/10/01/uietips-communicate-quick/&#34;&gt;Jared Spool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;So much complexity in software comes from trying to make one thing do two things.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2316-so-much-complexity-in-software-comes-from&#34;&gt;Ryan Singer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;When the form changes, so does the underlying business model, which of course changes the function as well. … The question that gets asked about technology, the one that is almost always precisely the wrong question is, &amp;quot;How does this advance help our business?&amp;quot; The correct question is, &amp;quot;how does this advance undermine our business model and require us/enable us to build a new one?&amp;quot; … When a change in form comes to your industry, the first thing to discover is how it will change the function.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/10/form-and-function.html&#34;&gt;Seth Godin on how to react to change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;When discussing any product, technology, or idea, it’s easy to focus only on its value, what problem it is trying to solve for the user. This is a good start, and has historically been the only consideration. Recently however, people have started to realize that it also has to be well designed; it can’t be painful to use. &lt;br /&gt;
…&lt;br /&gt;
What’s most important is their relationship: as long as value is greater than pain, you’ll be ok.&lt;br /&gt;
…&lt;br /&gt;
Just because value &amp;gt; pain doesn’t mean that you’re done, it just means that it’s good enough to ship.&lt;br /&gt;
…&lt;br /&gt;
As pain goes down, people will use a product more often for less valuable tasks. Value is still &amp;gt; pain but now it takes much less value to trigger usage. … [R]educing pain, not improving the value of a product in any way, can significantly affect usage.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://designmind.frogdesign.com/blog/mobile-apps-must-die.html&#34;&gt;Scott Jenson on Mobile Apps and value versus pain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Making something obvious has a cost. You can’t make everything obvious because you have limited resources. I’m not talking money–although that may be part of it too. I’m primarily talking screen real estate, attention span, comprehension, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making something obvious is expensive because it often means you have to make a whole bunch of other things less obvious. Obvious dominates and only one thing can truly dominate at a time. It may be worth it to make that one thing completely obvious, but it’s still expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obvious is all about always. The thing(s) people do all the time, the always stuff, should be obvious. The core, the epicenter, the essence of the product should be obvious.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3047-the-obvious-the-easy-and-the-possible&#34;&gt;Jason Fried on designing The Obvious, the Easy, and the Possible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;If we limit ourselves to what we envision at the outset, we&#39;ll miss opportunity. If we had stopped at what the Wright Brothers could envision, we wouldn&#39;t have gotten very far.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(In 1910, Wilbur Wright didn&#39;t believe planes would be able to carry large numbers of people as trains did, or would be ever able to carry freight. The first air cargo was in 1913.)&lt;br /&gt;
–Brock Rumor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there’s a benefit to being one of six people that no one knew. No VCs would return our calls and we were broke and bootstrapping it and operating under the radar so we could focus on the most important things: the product, the users, what we were building. There’s all this noise, the tech-crunch, which you have to tune out if you want to build a good product. None of that stuff is additive; it all takes away from building a product.&lt;br /&gt;
-Caterina Fake on developing in obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not embarrassed by the first version of your product, you’ve launched too late.&lt;br /&gt;
-Reid Hoffman, quoted in Mark Goldenson’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://venturebeat.com/2009/04/29/10-lessons-from-a-failed-startup/&#34;&gt;10 lessons from a failed startup&lt;/a&gt;, found &lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/1718-if-you-review-your-first-site-version-and&#34;&gt;via svn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any intelligent fool can make things bigger, more complex, and more violent. It takes a touch of genius–and a lot of courage–to move in the opposite direction.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://rescomp.stanford.edu/~cheshire/EinsteinQuotes.html&#34;&gt;Albert Einstein&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designers prune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Left to its own devices, the mob will augment, accessorize, spam, degrade and noisify whatever they have access to, until it loses beauty and function and becomes something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tragedy of the design commons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems democratic and non-elitist to set it and forget it and let the users take over. But the tools we use (Wikipedia) and the brands we covet (Nike or Ducati) resolutely refuse to become democracies.&lt;br /&gt;
-&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/08/a-tacky-mess-the-masses-vs-great-design.html&#34;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to get people to do what you want them to do is to start with people who want what you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identify, organize and excite people who are already predisposed to achieve what you had in mind and you&#39;re much more likely to have the outcome you seek. It&#39;s far easier (but less compelling) than turning strangers or enemies into customers/voters/supporters/colleagues. Over time, an engaged and motivated base of followers is the single best way to earn more followers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You used to be stuck with whoever walked in the door or opened your mail. Today, you change minds indirectly, by building a tribe that influences via connections to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/10/the-easiest-way-to-get-people-to-do-what-you-want-them-to-do.html&#34;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;On Running a Design Business&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;My model for business is The Beatles: They were four guys that kept each other&#39;s negative tendencies in check; they balanced each other. And the total was greater than the sum of the parts. Great things in business are not done by one person, they are done by a team of people.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
–Steve Jobs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insulate yourself…&lt;br /&gt;
from anonymous angry people&lt;br /&gt;
Expose yourself to art you don&#39;t yet understand&lt;br /&gt;
Precisely measure the results that are important to you&lt;br /&gt;
Stay blind to the metrics that don&#39;t matter&lt;br /&gt;
Fail often&lt;br /&gt;
Ship&lt;br /&gt;
Lead, don&#39;t manage so much&lt;br /&gt;
Seek out uncomfortable situations&lt;br /&gt;
Make an impact on the people who matter to you&lt;br /&gt;
Be better at your baseline skills than anyone else&lt;br /&gt;
Copyedit less, invent more&lt;br /&gt;
Give more speeches&lt;br /&gt;
Ignore unsolicited advice&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/12/insulate-yourself.html&#34;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two elements of successful leadership: a willingness to be wrong and an eagerness to admit it.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/01/i-was-wrong.html&#34;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;80 percent of success is just showing up.&lt;br /&gt;
–Woody Allen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are what we repeatedly do. Excellence, therefore, is not an act, but a habit.&lt;br /&gt;
-Aristotle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my walks, every man I meet is my superior in some way, and in that I learn from him.&lt;br /&gt;
-Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Light</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/wiki/go-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/wiki/go-light/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;book-body&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started keeping a journal in 2011 about a personal project I had undertaken towards simplifying aspects of my life. The impetus came after downsizing homes, having children, and realizing that things I had accumulated began to require more space, maintenance, and attention than I was willing to give. Possessing things began to cost more than the enjoyment they provided in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife is an un-clutterer, and easily lets go of things. I on the other hand, with my taste for electronics, hand-crafted goods, and toys, am quite the opposite. Going down this path has been a challenge, and writing about it has helped me overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have read a good deal about the topic, from ideas about attachment and its relationship to suffering, to the more practical aspects of uncluttering and living a minimalist lifestyle. I began with the easy stuff first, beginning by giving up many of my possessions and changing my consumer behavior and lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an ongoing series of essays I am writing for myself about aspirations to live lighter, from becoming a more conscientious and responsible consumer, to living a more pragmatic and simple lifestyle. I&#39;ve found that writing about it has helped me reflect on how to apply the ideas to my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael Angeles&lt;br /&gt;
16 August, 2013. Fairfax, CA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Beginning. Learning What Lightness Means to Me.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve begun to feel an increased urgency to live a more meaningful life as I&#39;ve gotten older. This is not uncommon. The urgency intensifies as each year brings one closer to death, statistically speaking. As a young adult, I thought the pursuit of meaning might be spiritual and would begin early in my life. It has come slowly. Starting a career, falling in love, and starting a family have been important events that have contributed to the palpable urgency I now feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a paragraph in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thecleanestline.com/2011/05/big-boy-and-the-pink-tape-route-.html&#34;&gt;an article on the blog, &amp;quot;The Cleanest Line,&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; that explains  what happens to people in terms of this type of maturity once they hit their 30s. I think this explains the shift I&#39;m experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;[T]he frontal lobe of their brain completes its development, becomes fully attached to the brain, and in so doing, completes the process of ‘growing up.’ People start to look at the world with a perspective that’s no longer so ego driven, it becomes easier to see the beauty in things, and they open up to feelings like compassion and empathy in ways that are just plain beyond the ability of younger folks to understand.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll buy that. Makes sense in terms of my experience anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The urgency to find meaning feels more real now. I think it began with the handful of Buddhist books I chose to read in my 20&#39;s and 30&#39;s, who I chose to marry, and my part in living with someone who studies Buddhism. It has evolved into an approach to life that is based around living compassionately, largely informed by my wife who I consider the more enlightened partner to my pragmatist beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently my personal interests have included martial arts and the connection that awareness of body and mind provides. That link is the simplest path for someone as simple-minded as me to understand. For others this connection is similarly found in Yoga. It feels appropriate to have this parallel of learning something new in martial arts, because as I put on a white belt and gi, I feel free&amp;amp;#8212;free as old dude who is trying to learn and move slowly and purposefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I&#39;m being influenced by new ideas, my life is also now inching towards action in pursuing an enlightened attitude regarding my role as a consumer, and experimenting with minimalism in life. When I refer to minimalism, it&#39;s the ideological model for making life choices that interests me most, and not simply the aesthetic outcome of living a minimalist lifestyle. As I learn what my opinion is of these ideas for how to live, I also feel the influence on my ideas for how to design with the same intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The welcome part of this confluence of ideas with the knowledge I&#39;ve acquired in the first 20 or so years of my professional career is that I feel like I am starting over again. But this time, as I empty my cup, I feel equipped to actually begin working with intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;More, More, MOAR!&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Contentment consists not in adding more fuel, but in taking away some fire, not in multiplying wealth, but in subtracting from desires.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;amp;#8212;Thomas Fuller&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;I&#39;ve had enough&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not religious or particularly spiritual, but Thomas Fuller&#39;s sentiment on contentment is at once appealing as a goal to strive for and frustrating as something to actualize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a phrase that you&#39;ve probably heard if you watch American TV. &amp;quot;Go big or go home.&amp;quot; I should stop watching so many home improvement shows, because those in particular reflect the American obsession with big homes and stuff. Go big is a common phrase barked on TV shows, suggesting that making or buying things bigger and having more can make anything better.  It&#39;s one of those expressions that makes me cringe every time I hear it. What does having this attitude really do to benefit or harm us?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;American culture seems obsessed with procuring more than we have. To an outsider looking in, it would seem that consumerism is among the most valued of our core values as a nation. It&#39;s something I&#39;ve been accustomed to all of my life. It&#39;s only in the last 10 years or so that I&#39;ve had any serious thoughts about what it means to participate in this society as a consumer, and what it could mean to challenge and change my role as a consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corporations and the media are constantly telling us that more is better, and when I look around me, it&#39;s easy to believe that most of us have bought in to this idea. I&#39;ve lived most of my life consuming without thought, consenting to the idea that newer, more fully featured, and bigger is better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem of acquiring more doesn&#39;t end with things. We live in a world where information flow has gone from the seemingly unctrollable force of a fire hose to what Richard Saul Wurman called an Information Tsunami. The force of the tsunami threatens to bury every meaningful bit in site, and the struggle of designers and information architects has been to create the systems that function with this increasingly tremendous force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the place where I find myself today. Things have taken up too much space, and information has become too voluminous. I&#39;ve had enough, but more to the point, I have too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The burden of carrying more&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I&#39;m silently crying over the overwhelming need to deal with this glut of stuff more and more, and I&#39;m finding tremendous comfort in places I didn&#39;t look. I have an understanding of both the philosophical and spiritual ideas associated with living simply, removing attachment, and controlling the mind&#39;s desire. It wasn&#39;t until I felt the need to start with the basics of uncluttering my stuff that I felt the gelling of ideas into something I can believe and practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uncluttering and carrying less refers both to the reduction or removal of both the physical and mental stuff we accumulate. The desire for, acquisition, and maintenance of physical objects create a cycle that weighs us down and uses up energy. It fills the spaces of a person&#39;s home, and the stuff leaves little room for much else over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mental clutter is the collection of repeated desires, tasks, and thought patterns that invade our mind and interrupt every moment. These days, the constant notification and tickling of your iPhone and the incessant ping of email and social networking apps contributes to mental clutter. These kinds of things burden our experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cat Li Stevenson has a nice, &lt;a href=&#34;http://thinksimplenow.com/happiness/simplify-your-life&#34;&gt;short article discussing her strategy&lt;/a&gt; for dealing with both the mental and physical clutter. The act of decluttering one&#39;s environment and mind are closely connected to freeing up space to find deeper, more meaningful experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But before dealing with the mind, I wanted to first deal with the burden of physical stuff. Considering the clutter of physical things is the most obvious path for novices&amp;amp;#8212;people like me. This is what I began with, and continue to struggle with daily, because it&#39;s practical and real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Carrying less out of necessity&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve found a lot of inspiration from adventure sports athletes who approach issues around carrying less pragmatically. Alpine climbers, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.backpackinglight.com/cgi-bin/backpackinglight/index.html&#34;&gt;ultralight backpackers&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Randonneuring&#34;&gt;Randonneurs&lt;/a&gt; who do long-distance cycling carry the minimum necessary gear out of necessity when they venture out on adventures alone and unsupported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy Gilbert, a cyclist and the sustainable design program director at Minneapolis College of Art and Design wrote about the freedom of traveling with less during a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.core77.com/blog/sustainable_design/ride_the_talk_freedom_from_stuff_20477.asp&#34;&gt;2.5 week, 4 state, 1000 mile cycling ride&lt;/a&gt; she took from Montana to Minneapolis.  During the trip she learns about what she is willing to give up to lighten her load. She ponders the positive effect of focussing on what one needs, and questioning the value of acquiring everything one wants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;I thought about the potential freedom I would feel to not have, want, buy, care for, protect, and use as many things. I think I am starting to understand why the retired folks in my life are offloading their stuff on me. Physical and emotional freedom from stuff costs nothing and it weighs nothing. Now that&#39;s something I am prepared to carry with me.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea of giving up the burden of one&#39;s things is at the core of what I&#39;m trying to get at. There&#39;s freedom lying beneath the pile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Choosing to live with less&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dave Bruno, who started the &lt;a href=&#34;http://guynameddave.com/100-thing-challenge/&#34;&gt;100 Thing Challenge&lt;/a&gt; and who wrote a book about his challenge to reduce his posessions to 100 items talks about consumerism and how we become prisoners to it. In his book he writes how early consumerism for young people comes of necessity to begin your life and equip yourself. But the problem we run into after we start acquiring things is that we never stop. We continue to collect what we don&#39;t need or sometimes even want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that having more doesn&#39;t necessarily result in a higher quality of life or better experience. Acquiring more has gotten us into dire economic and environmental straits. If you look at some of the &amp;quot;professional&amp;quot; software that we use, the accretion of features has rendered them overwhelming and difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What it comes down to is that sadly, for many people, more is actually less in terms of overall experience. The more we become a society hell-bent on acquiring and becoming attached to things, the greater the burden those attachments become to carry. It&#39;s can be a burden in one&#39;s personal life as well as in one&#39;s work. Giving up attachment frees you to focus on what&#39;s important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean exactly?  Barry Schwartz, who wrote &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;../notebook/barry-schwartz-paradox-choice.html&#34;&gt;The Paradox of Choice&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; believes that more choice leads to paralysis rather than happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been trapped in the cycle of attachment and consumerism for years, and wasn&#39;t until the last 5 or so years living in New York that I had been able to do something about it. As my family had grown, so too had our acquisitions, but the decent-sized Brooklyn apartment we lived in had not grown. This is the point where people get creative about storage, upgrade to bigger spaces, or move to the suburbs. I decided to go the other way and remove things instead. My wife is a constant unclutterer (thank goodness) and follows the rule that as things come in, other things have to go out. This is the rule I try to keep to now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my second son was born, I decided it was time that I start uncluttering as well, and had been going through the process of reducing my possessions, starting with my closets and book shelves. I&#39;ll write more on this later, because I really am a complete beginner when it comes to living simply and I have felt like I fail more than succeed at doing it. I&#39;m no hoarder, by any means, but I know that I have too many things that I don&#39;t need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years after starting this experiment, we have moved out of New York to a suburb in California, but we made the conscious decision to find a place that was roughly the same square footage as our place in New York. That is helping keep me honest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing to me is that I started, and made the conscious choice to draw a line, and say enough is enough. I find it terribly difficult to do this without rules and arbitrarily picked numbers of items like 100. The funny thing is that as I was doing this, I found myself cheating, by spending time researching what I can use as lasting replacements for the things I have. This is a beginning for me, and it starts with taking small steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It doesn&#39;t have to be this way. By making choices that are appropriate to task, we can simplify, improve, and live more satisfying, meaningful lives. Slowly, I think, internalizing these goals through everyday practice, has started to influence my thought in other areas as well, the key one being how I evaluate products that fit with these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Pragmatic Minimalism&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Trend Towards Less&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There appears to be a trend among affluent young professionals in the opposite direction, with some minimalists who espouse simple living and others who choose a more extreme direction (although some on the illusion of austerity.  Some of the stories I read feel legitimate and tied to real concern for finding meaning by removing clutter in one&#39;s life, while other stories seem shallow on the surface, and more akin to Luddite rebellion. In any case, I am attracted to and motivated by the idea of removing clutter and focussing on making meaningful choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why do people choose a minimalist lifestyle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People choose a minimalist lifestyle different reasons. For me, the need for a more minimalist lifestyle came first out of a few desires and needs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A need to unclutter because of the confines of a small space and a growing family. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A desire to exercise control over my life, to pursue a life of meaning free from the burdern and attachment to things.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A desire to break the cycle of wasteful and meaningless consumerism, in order to acquire primarily items that are built to last, that have meaning, or are worthwhile in terms of the pleasure and utility they provide.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From other people&#39;s writing, I&#39;ve gathered some great reasons to choose a life of less clutter and more meaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minimalism is sometimes associated with Zen Buddhism. I do not follow Zen Buddhism, but I find the ideas of attachment/non-attachment confusing. I understand the idea in Buddhism that non-attachment means knowing that one is not separate from the world outside one&#39;s skin, and that doesn&#39;t necessarily require a life of ascetism. But maybe the idea is that acquisition of things in the world become less important because the pursuit of enlightenment is a journey of the mind. Maybe reducing the objects you possess is a natural by-product of this pursuit or maybe it is part and parcel of the journey--having less is more proportional with this pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some feel like prisoners to consumerism and the act of choosing to own as little as possible is a conscious choice to free oneself from this. They needn&#39;t be &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anti-consumerism&#34;&gt;anti-consumerist&lt;/a&gt; to make this choice. I don&#39;t categorize myself as such, but I like some of the ideas associated with anti-consumerism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot say that I am drawn to the idea of complete austerity. There&#39;s something just-short of minimalism that might value reduction, without removing that which makes something interesting and more than just minimally useful. Less can be more, but really what I&#39;m interested in is &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.frankchimero.com/post/2831408736/your-shit-my-stuff-goldilocks-and-making-the-bed-you&#34;&gt;what Frank Chimero picked up&lt;/a&gt; in Merlin Mann&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/hotdogsladies/status/29683157687&#34;&gt;idea of Appropriatism&lt;/a&gt; and what I awkwardly think of as Just Enoughism. Terrible, I know. Maybe a pragmatic minimalist is what I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What it comes down to is that I value minimalist ideals, but realistically, I go only as far as I need to before the reduction gets in the way of getting the right things done at the right time. The problem is that needs shift over time, or with the needs at any time. So that makes it difficult to arbitrarily select a maximum number of items or features at your disposal, whether they&#39;re items of clothing or menu items, to get things done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Uncluttering&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be honest with you, I don&#39;t consider myself a minimalist. Not yet anyway. Minimalism may be a goal in terms of where I want to be, but appropriateness is more likely what I live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t make new years resolution, but to mark 2011 I set one goal for the sake of the new year: unsubscribe from every mailing list and catalog that I can. Since then I&#39;ve been on an unhoarding spree, concerned with how to selectively save and delete with impunity. My experiment with email was interesting to me, and I&#39;m keeping it up so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 23 Feb. 2010, I tweeted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;quot;After years of using GMail&#39;s convention of saving everything with archive, I feel like the virtual equivalent of a hoarder.&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/konigi/status/40429513573670912&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 5 May 2010, I tweeted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;quot;I&#39;ve canceled all my mag subs. Will try to buy all books on iBooks or Kindle iPad.&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/konigi/status/13422237666&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;quot;My next exercise in simplifying... trying to cut wardrobe down to 5 items of every category of clothing. Will be hard but I want less stuff.&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/konigi/status/13422635770&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;quot;I wont replace much, but I do want things that last. I&#39;m happy to donate all the cheaply made gear. Gap clothes can suck it.&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/konigi/status/13425549853&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;quot;Once you get in the mode of reducing and selecting in one area of life, other, bigger ideas become possible.&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/konigi/status/13425634990&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The self-imposed challenge was on. I needed to kick my butt into action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deleting email and unsubscribing has been the easiest and most successful exercise so far, because it&#39;s really not hard to do, and you feel the benefits immediately. I didn&#39;t do it one fell swoop. It&#39;s gradual, and I&#39;m still doing it. I looked at what was coming in, and took action whenever something new invaded my inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Being realistic and figuring out what&#39;s worth keeping&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Buy better. Buy less.&amp;quot; I don&#39;t know who originally coined that phrase, but it&#39;s like a mantra for anti-consumerists and pragmatic minimalists alike. I read it in Yvon Chouinard&#39;s book, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Let-People-Surfing-Businessman-ebook/dp/B000SEGEVC/&#34;&gt;*Let My People Go Surfing*&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve adopted a new approach towards what I keep for sentimental value, and I can&#39;t see any reason to be attached to items like clothing for sentimental value. Those silver boots that I wore when I was 21 and had blonde hair? The t-shirt I bought at Lacrosse camp that finally fits me again? I don&#39;t need them to conjure memories of those times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way the media covers some stories about minimalists can make some of the drastic steps they take seem like crazy-making. There&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-10928032&#34;&gt;a story on the BBC about modern day minimalists&lt;/a&gt; like software engineer, Kelly Sutton, who documented his effort to reduce his physical possessions to nearly nothing on his site, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cultofless.com/&#34;&gt;Cult of Less&lt;/a&gt;. Just as interesting is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boingboing.net/2010/08/17/the-nitty-gritty-of.html&#34;&gt;discussion about Sutton&lt;/a&gt; on Boing Boing. I don&#39;t have a personal opinion of his effort because I don&#39;t know him or what his motives are. Maybe that&#39;s because the media don&#39;t really take the time to dive deeper into their reasons for choosing to live this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some, choosing an arbitrary number and announcing the goal of what number you want to reduce your possessions down to can make it real. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://guynameddave.com/about-the-100-thing-challenge/&#34;&gt;100 Thing Challenge&lt;/a&gt; is an example of this. It&#39;s like announcing to your friends and family that you plan to run a marathon or do a 100 mile bike ride. Once you put it out in the world, you&#39;re making a contract with yourself that you&#39;ll have a better chance of completing. Event athletes know about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not dogmatic about creating rules for myself, but I feel like drawing a line or setting an intention is useful. But, if there is something that so vividly captures a memory that I want to keep it, I keep it. For me the idea is to be selective, and remember that these are just things. Allowing things to accumulate and clutter is what I&#39;m against. While sentimental items may remind me of something I hold fond every few years that I come across them,  they can easily disrupt the balance of daily living in my small and well-defined space if they become clutter. For me, journaled memories and photos serve better and take up less physical space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patrick Rhone, has some interesting thoughts about how you can approach purchases. The first is on making final and lasting choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;quot;My desired goal is this. Anywhere I can make a buying choice that I, with proper care and maintenance, will never have to make again for the rest of my life, I do. In those cases, I’m willing to pay far more for an item if I know it will last a lifetime and, even more importantly to me, I will never have to spend the mental energy making a choice again.&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;http://patrickrhone.com/2010/11/05/final-choices/&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second idea has to do with deciding what your defaults are for things you use repeatedly, whether it&#39;s the the pen you write with, the clothes you wear, or the software you use. Research carefully, make your decision, and don&#39;t waste time staring at the wall of choices in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&amp;quot;Sensible defaults can reduce friction and provide simplicity anywhere one can think to apply them. They are the bedrock of minimalist practice and a quiet mind.&amp;quot; &lt;a href=&#34;http://patrickrhone.com/2010/11/08/sensible-defaults/&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&#39;ve reduced your possessions, looking at the world this way going forward, you can apply the ideas for buying less and buying better to how you consume. But more importantly, you can take the next steps to apply them not just to the physical things you possess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next I&#39;m going to explore the ideas as they are beginning to relate to the features I select in the design of software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analog Tools</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/wiki/analog-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/wiki/analog-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;My analog tools don&#39;t change much. I&#39;ve bought many, but in reality I use only a handful. These are the ones I now stick with.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sketching Pens and Markers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/wiki/pens.jpg&#34; style=&#34;width: 700px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetpens.com/Pilot-Hi-Tec-C-Gel-Ink-Pen-with-Grip-0.4-mm-Black/pd/2796&#34;&gt;PIlot Hi-Tec-C 0.4mm (black)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is the black gel pen I carry in my pocket. Always with me, and unforgivingly hard and fine. It&#39;s my preferred tool for small thumbnail sketching in my pocket sketchbook and on my 8-up sheets, where I work in small areas on mostly abstract boxes and arrows. I like it for general sketching (non-work related) because the fine line makes me work light and loose in the beginning to capture an essence, but then work up details around that. On my desk, I have the Hi-Tec-C in CW&amp;amp;T&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.cwandt.com/products/pen-type-a&#34;&gt;Pen Type A&lt;/a&gt; aluminum housing. If you&#39;re looking for an inexpensive, smooth-rolling, medium point pen for writing, I also like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Pilot-EasyTouch-Retractable-Point-Black/dp/B0006HUHHI&#34;&gt;Pilot Easy Touch Fine 0.7mm point&lt;/a&gt;. That&#39;s the one I use in the kitchen and for filling out forms and such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetpens.com/Pentel-Sign-Pens/ct/1838&#34;&gt;Pentel Sign Pen (black)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
These are an overlooked gem. I was a user of these for close to ten years when I lived in Park Slope, Brooklyn, until the stationery store that carried them around the block from me closed. They&#39;re soft and flow smoothly, like a 2b pencil. I love these because unlike Sharpies, they don&#39;t bleed through the thinner weight of sketchbook papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sharpie.com/enUS/Pages/fine-point-marker.aspx&#34;&gt;Sharpie Fine Point Permanent Marker (black)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is the standby that almost everyone I know uses. It&#39;s great because the lines are broad and perfect for rough thinking. When I sketch with one, I imagine being something like a 3-5px tool or very fat 2-3b soft pencil.  They bleed through most normal notebook/sketchbook paper that&#39;s under 70#. I like that using it forces you to go forward and restart if you make mistakes rather than get fussy. My Sharpie is topped with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://more-real.com/&#34;&gt;More/Real capacitive tip cap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sketch Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../tools/sketchbooks-diy.html&#34;&gt;DIY Sketchbooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I mostly &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/tools/sketchbooks-diy/wirebinding-thumb.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34;&gt;make my own&lt;/a&gt; because I like making a smaller book with my own paper, and with a ring cover that can fold over onto the back. I use these for most of my design sketches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.moleskine.com/en/collections/model/product/squared-notebook-pocket&#34;&gt;Moleskine Pocket Squared Notebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I still use the squared notebook when I&#39;m not using my own. Since they&#39;re available at stationers everywhere, and are the perfect size for desk and bag, it&#39;s an easy choice, and well made. I prefer the hard covers over the soft ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.midori-japan.co.jp/tr/&#34;&gt;Midori Traveler&#39;s Notebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This one is a luxury, and one of those objects that I feel like I will carry for my lifetime. It&#39;s beautiful and simple—one piece of leather over a squared book inside. My only wish is that the porportions were exactly to the Moleskine Cahiers so I could replace with those. It&#39;s a little narrower and taller, which I like, but it means having to get the exact replacements. I have it in two sizes and have been using it lately for my &lt;a href=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7447/9303739801_13f0855e53.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34;&gt;sketchnotes&lt;/a&gt;. If you are in New York City or San Francisco, you can get them locally at Kinokuniya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../tools/graph-paper.html&#34;&gt;Loose Graph Papers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you&#39;ve been following along on this site, you know I love minimalist papers made for the job. The Wireframe and 8-up sheets are the hardest working of the graph papers I use when I&#39;m at a desk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conferences and Events</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/wiki/conferences-and-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/wiki/conferences-and-events/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;ul id=&#34;filter&#34; class=&#34;inline mt0 strong&#34;&gt;
&lt;li class=&#34;current&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;All&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;UX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table id=&#34;filterlist&#34;&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://99u.com/conference&#34;&gt;The 99U&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;New York, NY&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://99u.com/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sigchi.org/conferences&#34;&gt;ACM SIGCHI Conference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dl.acm.org/event.cfm?id=RE151&amp;amp;CFID=429753542&amp;amp;CFTOKEN=93999681&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ux-intensive.com/&#34;&gt;Adaptive Path UX Intensive Workshop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ampersandconf.com/&#34;&gt;Ampersand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Brighton, UK; New York, NY&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/channels/ampersandconf&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design ux development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://beyondtellerrand.com/&#34;&gt;Beyond Tellerand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Düsseldorf, Germany&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/beyondtellerrand/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux design development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bigdesignevents.com/conference/&#34;&gt;Big Design Conference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dallas, TX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://brooklynbeta.org/&#34;&gt;Brooklyn Beta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Brooklyn, NY&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://buildconf.com/&#34;&gt;Build&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Belfast, Northern Ireland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/build/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://businessofsoftware.org/&#34;&gt;Business of Software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Boston, MA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://businessofsoftware.org/category/video-2/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://chicagocamps.org/&#34;&gt;Chicago Camps&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chicago, IL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://circlesconference.com/&#34;&gt;Circles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Grapevine, TX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://circlesconference.com/2013/videos/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://convergese.com/&#34;&gt;ConvergeSE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Columbia, SC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/convergese/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.conveyux.com/&#34;&gt;ConveyUX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Seattle, WA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cooper.com/training/&#34;&gt;Cooper Workshops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;San Francisco, CA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dconstruct.org/&#34;&gt;dConstruct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Brighton, UK&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.dconstruct.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://delight.us/conference/&#34;&gt;Delight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Portland, OR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://delight.us/category/videos/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.euroia.org/&#34;&gt;Euro IA Summit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design ux development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aneventapart.com/&#34;&gt;An Event Apart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aneventapart.com/news/tag/video&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://eyeofestival.com/&#34;&gt;eyeo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Minneapolis, MN&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/eyeofestival/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ffwd.pro/&#34;&gt;ffwd.pro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Zagreb, Croatia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/ffwdpro/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fluxible.ca/&#34;&gt;fluxible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kitchener, Ontario&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fluxible.ca/category/videos/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fromthefront.it/&#34;&gt;From the Front&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bologna, IT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/fromthefront/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://futureofwebdesign.com/&#34;&gt;Future of Web Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/fowd/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux design&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gelconference.com/&#34;&gt;Gel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;New York, NY&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/gelconference/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux design&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://giantconf.com/&#34;&gt;Giant Conference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charleston, SC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hybridconf.net/&#34;&gt;Hybrid Conf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cardiff, Wales&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/zedonkey/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uxsummersummit.eventbrite.com/&#34;&gt;Idean UX Summit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Menlo Park, CA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/idean/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leanuxdenver.com/&#34;&gt;Lean UX Denver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Denver, CO&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://leanuxnyc.co/nyc/&#34;&gt;Lean UX NYC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;New York, NY&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://midwestuxconference.com/&#34;&gt;Midwest UX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Grand Rapids, MI&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mobx2012.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;MobX: Mobile Experience Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Berlin, Germant&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/user/MobXCon/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://iasummit.org/&#34;&gt;IA Summit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://library.iasummit.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://interaction.ixda.org/&#34;&gt;Interaction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/ixdaglobal/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux design&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://interlinkconference.com/&#34;&gt;Interlink Conference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vancouver, BC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/interlink/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sensible.com/workshops.html&#34;&gt;Steve Krug&amp;rsquo;s Usability Testing Workshops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Boston, MA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lessconf.lesseverything.com/&#34;&gt;LessConf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Panama City, FL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://madisonpl.us/&#34;&gt;Madison+&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Madison, WI&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mxconference.com/&#34;&gt;Managing Experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;San Francisco, CA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mxconference.com/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://conference.mindtheproduct.com/&#34;&gt;Mind the Product&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;London, UK&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mindtheproduct.com/tag/video/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://newadventuresconf.com/&#34;&gt;New Adventures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Nottingham, UK&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://northern-user-experience.org/&#34;&gt;Northern User Experience (NUX)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Manchester and Leeds, UK&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow development ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://prototypecamp.com/&#34;&gt;Prototype Camp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Chicago, IL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.redesignconference.com/conferences/uxd/&#34;&gt;RE:DESIGN/UX Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Menlo Park, CA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://inspireconf.com/&#34;&gt;Ready to Inspire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Leiden, The Netherlands&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/channels/inspireconf/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://remixsouth.com/&#34;&gt;Remix South&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Atlanta, GA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/channels/remixsouth/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rosenfeldmedia.com/events/&#34;&gt;Rosenfeld Media Workshops&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://smashingconf.com/&#34;&gt;Smashing Conference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Freiberg, Germany&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/channels/smashingconf/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sudweb.fr/&#34;&gt;Sud Web&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Avignon, France&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/sudweb/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sxsw.com/interactive&#34;&gt;SXSW Interactive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Austin, TX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sxsw.com/video/interactive&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/events/uiconf/&#34;&gt;User Interface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uxaustralia.com.au/&#34;&gt;UX Australia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Melbourne, Australia&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uxbrighton.org.uk/&#34;&gt;UX Brighton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Brighton, UK&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/uxbrighton/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freshtilledsoil.com/uxfest/&#34;&gt;UX Fest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Boston, MA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/events/ux_immersion/2013/&#34;&gt;UX Immersion - Mobile (UIE)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Seattle, WA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2014.uxlausanne.com/&#34;&gt;UX Lausanne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lausanne, Switzerland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.uxlondon.com/&#34;&gt;UX London&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;London, UX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/tag:UX+london&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uxscotland.net/&#34;&gt;UX Scotland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Edinburgh, Scotland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uxweek.com/&#34;&gt;UX Week&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;San Francisco, CA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/tag:UX+Week&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uxcampottawa.org/&#34;&gt;UXcamp Ottawa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ottawa, Canada&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uxcampeurope.org/&#34;&gt;UXcamp Europe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Berlin, Germany&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ux-lx.com/&#34;&gt;UXLx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lisbon, Portugal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ux-lx.com/videos.html&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://upaboston.org/upa-boston-events/user-experience-conference/&#34;&gt;UXPA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Boston, MA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uxpadc.org/userfocus&#34;&gt;UXPA User Focus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Washington DC area&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uxstrat.com/&#34;&gt;UX STRAT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Atlanta, GA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design development&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://valiocon.com/&#34;&gt;Valio Con&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;San Diego, CA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/user/drewwilsonn/search?query=valio+con&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design development ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webvisionsevent.com/&#34;&gt;Web Visions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webvisionsevent.com/portland/videos/&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow ux&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://worldiaday.org/&#34;&gt;World IA Day&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/user/WorldIADay/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr class=&#34;frow design&#34;&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://xoxofest.com/&#34;&gt;XOXO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Portland, OR&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/user/xoxofest/videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ss-icon ss-standard&#34;&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;See also:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/designoutloud/lists/ux-conferences&#34;&gt;Phillip Hunter&amp;rsquo;s UX Conferences Twitter List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nickfinck.com/blog/entry/user_experience_conferences/&#34;&gt;Nick Finck&amp;rsquo;s UX Conferences List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lanyrd.com/topics/user-experience/&#34;&gt;Lanyrd UX Conferences and Events&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
td:second-child {
  width: 24px;
}
&lt;/style&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn to Code</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/wiki/learn-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/wiki/learn-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc0&#34;&gt;The Debate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The debate about whether or not designers need to learn to code is essentially about knowing enough HTML and CSS, and maybe some Javascript to be able to prototype web views.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mastery and the ability to produce production code is not something most interaction designers and information architects will have the opportunity to achieve, but being capable enough to communicate design on web products requires some basic skills that you can learn in a few days or months to start. Here are some resources for designers looking to get started with basic markup and light scripting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc1&#34;&gt;Start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great places for beginners to learn basic web markup, stylesheets and programming.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://learn.shayhowe.com/html-css/&#34;&gt;A Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to HTML and CSS&lt;/a&gt; - Shaye Howe&amp;rsquo;s guide for beginners outlines the fundamentals of front-end design and development with HTML and CSS.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codecademy.com/&#34;&gt;Code Academy&lt;/a&gt; - Free. Start with HTML Fundamentals and Javscript intros. Move on to Jquery to add interaction.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.learnstreet.com/&#34;&gt;LearnStreet&lt;/a&gt; - Free. JavaScript for beginners is a good start. Ruby and Python are also offered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc2&#34;&gt;Go further&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Read some articles on &lt;a href=&#34;http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/html-css-techniques/30-html-best-practices-for-beginners/&#34;&gt;good practices and habits&lt;/a&gt; to get into as you to start. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://sass-lang.com/&#34;&gt;SASS, Syntactically Awesome Stylesheets&lt;/a&gt; - Stylesheet language with some scripting capabilities that compiles into CSS. There are even light PHP SASS compilers that work with WordPress if you go that route.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc3&#34;&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/MarkUp/Guide/&#34;&gt;W3C Markup Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.w3.org/MarkUp/Guide/Style&#34;&gt;W3C CSS Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noticeability Evaluation</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/wiki/noticeability-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/wiki/noticeability-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc0&#34;&gt;Definition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A research technique for learning whether people notice key elements in your design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An exercise during which users are asked to re-create a screen based on their memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/tsharon/what-ux-research-can-you-do?slide=49&#34;&gt;What UX Research Can You Do with 5 Users in 1 Hour?&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;quot; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://about.me/tsharon&#34;&gt;Tomer Sharon&lt;/a&gt;. Asbury Agile 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc1&#34;&gt;How to do it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Create an evaluation kit&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Print any screen&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Cut the screen into elements (leave some out)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Also print/cut some elements that weren&amp;rsquo;t on the screen&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Mix the pieces up&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Sharpie and some extra paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. Give user a task to perform on a web site or app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. After the user performs the task, give them an evaluation kit. Tell them that the kit includes elements of the screen, and that they can also use the paper and pen to draw elements that are missing. Ask them to re-assemble the screen and observe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc2&#34;&gt;Questions to ask&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Did they put the key elements in place?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Did they leave out what doesn&amp;rsquo;t belong?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Did they draw elements that weren&amp;rsquo;t there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sketch Book</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/wiki/sketch-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/wiki/sketch-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;book-body&#34;&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;center p1 mb1-5 gborder&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/title.png&#34; alt=&#34;Sketch&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;This is a small journal and mini book about the approach I take when sketching for interface and interaction design. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m writing this as I enter what I think may be my 17th year making web sites. The only thing I can say with each passing year is that what I know is still so very little compared to what I have yet to learn. Each time I learn of a new way of working I feel energized and excited about the work I do. This is how I&#39;ve felt about sketching as part of the design process, and why I decided to capture what I was thinking in this journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started this project to publish the speaking notes from a talk I gave at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asburyagile.com/&#34;&gt;Asbury Agile&lt;/a&gt; in October 2012. The plan is to continue to update it as I learn more, become more experienced with sketching software and web products, and modify my approach. On the surface, it will seem to most like the message is overly simplistic and the points obvious. I&#39;m a simple person, but I have an easy time complicating things. Having a set of guidelines to keep me focussed on what&#39;s important keeps me from falling into that trap. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re interested in the presentation deck, you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/jibbajabba/sketching-interfaces&#34;&gt;View the Slides on Slideshare&lt;/a&gt;. The deck is missing several videos that I used in the presentation, but they&#39;re reproduced in the pages found here on Konigi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy, and if you have any feedback please &lt;a href=../contact_.html&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mike Angeles&lt;br /&gt;
Mill Valley, CA, 10 Oct. 2012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Also given at General Assembly, User Experience Immersive 7/10/13&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Starting Over&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/confession.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/confession.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sketching and drawing is something I&#39;ve been passionate about for a long time. This journal is about sketching interfaces and interaction, but I want to start out with a story about sketching that isn&#39;t at all related to web sites and software. I think it might help to understand why I wrote this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Confession&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a confession to make. Most of my life I&#39;ve really thought that I sucked at sketching and drawing. But I&#39;ve always wanted to do it, and I&#39;ve always wanted to be better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I was always drawing and making things with my hands all the time. I wanted to be able to accurately and realistically draw what I saw with my eyes, and draw the ideas in my mind. I really wanted my drawings to look like those things. But I&#39;ve always felt like I sucked at that, and I think that&#39;s really blocked me for a long time from being successful at using sketching as one of my design tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When desire is greater than ability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there&#39;s something interesting about having a desire that&#39;s much greater than your ability. Something about that equation creates a tension and possibility to grow that can be delicate to handle. It&#39;s easy to find yourself unable to meet your passion and give up. If you&#39;re lucky, if you have guidance, or something or someone who influences you and pushes you forward, however, it&#39;s possible to discover a path to satisfying the desire, unexpected as the path may be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/finjake.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Drawing by my 11 year old son.&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/finjake.jpg&#34; class=&#34;fright gborder ml1 mb1&#34; style=&#34;width: 200px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m regularly provided with interesting life lessons seeing the world through my children, and trying to see them through challenges. The unique position of wanting to help, but knowing you need to do so carefully makes me think about responding to those challenges in a way that doesn&#39;t discourage, but offers possibilities and paths for consideration. I haven&#39;t always approached things this way, but when I do, I find it can be less effort pushing one&#39;s self forward. Getting spoon-fed every solution in life only gets you so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My son is 11 as I write this. He&#39;s a kid like I was who seems to have always loved making things with markers, or photoshop, and that sort of thing. Talking with him about his artwork one day helped me to understand what was blocking me in my own design work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day when he was about 6 or 7 years old, he was doing his usual thing, drawing pictures and characters. I&#39;m sitting in the same room with him and I hear him say, &#34;I suck at this.&#34; Of course my heart breaks a little because I want my kids to feel awesome about themselves. I went over to see what was up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw that he was drawing a character. He was trying to copy a picture of an anime character he likes. He&#39;s focussing on the details and trying to make his face and hair look right, and he&#39;s really looking closely and working meticulously, trying to make this thing look &#34;right&#34; to him—to match the image he has in his mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&#39;s kind of blocked. And all the time leading up to this point, I&#39;ve never really seen him express frustration over not being able to have the thing in his mind match the thing he created. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already thought that his drawings were great, but at this point I think I started to talk to him about the idea of maybe taking a break and stepping back. We talked about what it was he wanted to do. He told me that when we made books together, he would get frustrated that the characters didn&#39;t look the same from cell to cell, page to page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At some point during this conversation I told him that I loved how hard he worked on his drawings and asked him, &#34;What if you focussed on the story you want to express, because maybe the thing that&#39;s important to you might be getting this idea out without having to make it look exactly like what you&#39;re trying to copy.&#34; I knew this wasn&#39;t the answer he wanted. So I also introduced him to some techniques I had learned to give him something to hang onto while he worked, but I think the first message was the important one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Empty your cup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/kensuke.gif&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Kensuke&#39;s basic expression drawings&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/kensuke.gif&#34; class=&#34;fright gborder ml1 mb1&#34; style=&#34;width: 200px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had taken a class with this guy a few years prior. His name is &lt;a href=&#34;http://kensukeokabayashi.tumblr.com/&#34;&gt;Kensuke Okabayashi&lt;/a&gt;. He&#39;s a manga illustrator who taught a class on the Lower East Side of New York for people who wanted to to draw manga. His class helped me to break down the drawing of faces by looking at the basic elements that go into each expression, from happy and surprised, to sad and totally devastated. Until that point, I was never able to see what I needed to do to draw in all the traditional figure drawing classes I had taken. But somehow I started to see differently, and my eyes were breaking down what I saw into forms I could sketch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By repeatedly practicing drawing the basic set of expressions Kensuke introduced, I had tools to tell a story&amp;#8212;the starter kit version anyway. I began to believe that it&#39;s not learning how to represent the human form accurately and showing all the details that I should be concerned with, but thinking about what it is I want to tell in my story, and knowing how to do that with a few basic techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t know if my son really took all my messages to heart, nor do I think it was my talking to him that changed things directly. But, shortly afterwards he did kind of let go of this idea of having to be perfect. And when I look at some of his drawings, there&#39;s a lot of emotion and humor there. It&#39;s very rough and loose, but there&#39;s nothing wrong with having that character in your drawing and not being &#34;perfect&#34; at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In retrospect I think we had similar problems, although I spent much more effort and time trying to be &#34;good,&#34; whereas, I think he&#39;s moved on much sooner. I also learned eventually to let go when doing my own work and accepted that sketching should be a something that&#39;s loose and free. And I embraced sketching over drawing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/letgo.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Less sucky sketches after taking Kensuke&#39;s Class&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/letgo.jpg&#34; class=&#34;fright gborder ml1 mb1&#34; style=&#34;width: 200px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think when you focus on the message and the story you want to tell, when over time you give up this need to be technically correct and just practice doing the basic things to tell your story, that you get progressively better. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some sketches from my sketch book in recent years, post-Kensuke. I think my sketches which used to be really tortured became fun and started to look more like things in my mind. I look at these now and I feel like I&#39;ve come a long way from really sucking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really had to start over. I didn&#39;t realize it at the time, but this struggle was happening in my work as a designer as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Is A Sketch?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/what.png&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;What is a Sketch?&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/what.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Starting again as a designer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a connection between the story of my son and I and our struggle to sketch, and my own work as a designer. This is relevant to my work because I had this same kind of block for some time, but I wasn&#39;t aware of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, I was doing a lot of sketching in private, but what was missing for me was the bigger picture about how sketching fit into the design process. I kept seeing the mentions of the books and watched the presentations of these 2 guys and they started to influence my thinking. I had picked up both books and they really put me on the path to starting over again with sketching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/buxtonroam.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Buxton and Roam&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/buxtonroam.jpg&#34; class=&#34;fright gborder ml1 mb1&#34; style=&#34;width: 200px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan Roam&#39;s book kind of democratized sketching as a tool that anyone can use to communicate visually. He shows you how effective and simple it can be. Nobody needs to be afraid of sketching because there&#39;s a basic language you can learn, and once you do, your power to communicate grows. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bigger influence for me was Bill Buxton&#39;s book on sketching user experience. Buxton talked from both a high level and a detailed point of view about how sketching as a part of design process is valuable as a tool because it&#39;s cheap and fast, and it&#39;s the right level of fidelity that lets you make bad decisions early, and fail early so you can make those mistakes before you code. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He gives you a way of using sketching successfully by allowing you to maximize this tool at the right time so that you&#39;re not making assumptions that are wrong and going down a path that leads you to needing to pivot when you&#39;re in code, which is much more costly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is a sketch?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All lot of ideas were floating around in my head about starting over on my own personal artistic sketching. And while this is happening I&#39;m thinking about Roam and Buxton. At this point I&#39;m starting to question how I&#39;m using sketching in my own practice as a designer. Am I doing things the right way, the wrong way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around this time i had also started seeing people posting pictures of their sketches, and some of them were beautiful works from people I really admire and respect. But then, some of that has the effect of making me feel like, maybe I&#39;m doing it wrong. My work looks like garbage compared to some of these guys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I think back at this, what I was seeing were drawings not sketches. They were more like visual designs or pretty wireframes done in pen and pencil, rather than sketches that were being used to demonstrate thinking and problem solving. At least that&#39;s what most of these looked like to me. Compared to my sketches, these were polished, clean drawings in all the colors of the rainbow. It reminds me of when I occasionally had to interview people for IA jobs where I would sometimes be presented with beautiful portfolios of work for big brands, but when it came time to show the sketches or describe the problem solving that went into producing the work, there was nothing to show and no explanation of the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s when I started to figure out for myself what I wanted my approach to be, and to decide what&#39;s important to me. I stepped back and kept coming back to the ideas I found in Bill Buxton&#39;s book and talks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sketching != Drawing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/notdrawing.jpg&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 gborder center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first decisions I made for myself was that I can&#39;t look at polished design drawings and let them influence my own thinking about sketching. I need to think about sketching in a different way. I also need to look around more, learn a little more, capture what I was thinking, and then be able to express it so I could make my ideas and approach something I could describe to others and repeat. And the approach had to be super simple, because I&#39;m a simple-minded guy that needs things put plainly if I wish to have any hope of acting on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this came my first, rather obvious statement. Sketching is not drawing. It&#39;s a completely different action that is rough and loose and meant to be fast and disposable. The artifacts are meant to show the process involved in arriving at the sketch as much as it is meant to demonstrate the final concept. It&#39;s great when used in teams, but can be used individually if you&#39;re thinking about them as part of the design process that Buxton describes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To act on the decision to approach sketching with a newfound purpose in mind, I had to think back to that idea I wrote about with my son. I needed to step back and think about why I should be sketching at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why We Sketch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/why.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Why We Sketch&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/why.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to think a lot about why we sketch. I began asking, &#34;how am I making sure that the ideas I&#39;m reading about and agreeing with are informing the way I work.&#34; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at what other creative people are doing, and I picked this handful of things that are important to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m using sketching:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to think about problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to document the solutions and the intention of the design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to experiment with things that are maybe unfamiliar or unconventional in terms of my own knowledge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to communicate and explain the solutions and decisions I&#39;m proposing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And these last 2 are most specific to product design. I&#39;m using sketching:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to fail faster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to find the right solution and design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples I was finding from other fields that demonstrate why we sketch as part of the creative process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&#34;noprint&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We sketch to think&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/tothink.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;To Think (Frank Gehry)&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/tothink.jpg&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Frank Gehry&#39;s sketch. They&#39;re squiggles showing how he&#39;s exploring the concept for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walt_Disney_Concert_Hall&#34;&gt;Disney Concert Hall&lt;/a&gt; in Los Angeles. It&#39;s just rough lines that represent all these undulating and curving forms that are going to make up the facade of this building in metal. He&#39;s also figuring out the relationship of the curvy metal building to the smaller rectilinear forms, and the proportion and scale with the landscape and trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also see in the prototype or model that the elements in the sketch are carried through to the final building. What we&#39;re seeing here is sketching as a tool to begin to think about the design problem of sculpting a metal architectural skin over a box until they&#39;ve arrive at this main concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arcspace.com/architects/gehry/disney2/&#34;&gt;Arcspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&#34;noprint&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We sketch to document&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/todocument1.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;To Document (Richard Serra)&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/todocument1.jpg&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documentation is probably a common reason for all of us to put something down on paper, if just to capture the idea for other people to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is sculptor Richard Serra, who is using this sketch as a way to document how he wants this installation to be laid out, indicating with sketches and notes how he wants each piece to be positioned in this room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Sources: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.depont.nl/en/collection/artists/artist/werk_id/344/kunstenaar/serra/&#34;&gt;Depont&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://zigzagbluesblog.blogspot.com/2012/05/richard-serra-1939.html&#34;&gt;zigzagblues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;hr class=&#34;noprint&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We sketch to document&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/todocument2.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;To Document (Dieter Rams)&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/todocument2.jpg&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Dieter Rams documenting the cutting element of the Braun razor. The sketchs shows the detail of the blades insidde the razor that clip the facial hair and capture the stubble in the rounded metal of the cutting end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Sources: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Less-More-Design-Ethos-Dieter/dp/3899553977&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Less and More: The Design Ethos of Dieter Rams&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.domusweb.it/en/from-the-archive/alessandro-mendini-interviews-dieter-rams&#34;&gt;&#34;Alessandro Mendini interviews Dieter Rams&#34; on Domus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&#34;noprint&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We sketch to experiment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/toexperiment.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;To Experiment (Josef Albers)&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/toexperiment.jpg&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is painter Josef Albers who is known mostly for these minimalist paintings of color fields in his &#34;Homage to the Square.&#34; work. He doesn&#39;t start from painting these clean lines, he starts with testing these colors, and how they work together and against each other with these rough sketches in paint and color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://albersfoundation.org/Albers.php?inc=Galleries&amp;amp;i=J_1&#34;&gt;Albers Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&#34;noprint&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We sketch to communicate &amp;amp; explain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/tocommunicate.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;To communicate and explain (Gene Lu)&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/tocommunicate.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the things most of us are familiar with, which is the use of sketching as a tool to come to an understanding about how a product is going to function. This is the kind of sketching I do most, which is a sketch that communicates the behaviors of an interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Gene Lu&#39;s sketches of the filtering interface, for the Nike Air Force 1 Facebook app. And you see him exploring the filtering mechanism in the middle, and how he&#39;s showing how the different characteristics of a shoe can be selected to refine search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://genelu.com/2012/07/nike-air-force-1/&#34;&gt;Portfolio of Gene Lu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&#34;noprint&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sidebar: The Design Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real turning point for me had to do with where sketching fits in with product design. And this is where we come back to Buxton in this diagram talking about design process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/buxtondesignprocess.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Design Process (Buxton)&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/buxtondesignprocess.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This expanding and narrowing chart shows the growth of ideas you generate at the beginning of a project at the left. What you&#39;re trying to do is come up with as many ideas as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then there&#39;s a narrowing of the flow, where ideas are being selected. And when decisions are made, you expand a little bit to explore more of the ideas  in each iteration and refine them. And you keep doing this iteratively until you arrive at the final concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the sketches are looser and lower fidelity at the beginning and have higher fidelity at the right end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&#34;noprint&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We sketch to fail faster&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/failfaster.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Fail Faster&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/failfaster.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Failing is the point. This process has a lot to do with mitigating risk. You make all the mistakes now in paper, where it&#39;s quick and cheap, and when you can do it with a much lower risk factor than when you&#39;re working in code. Making changes on paper costs you only time, and in the end saves you time if you&#39;ve discover problems along a line of thinking before you&#39;ve coded it. Pivoting once you&#39;re dealing with working code is much more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class=&#34;noprint&#34; /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We sketch to find the right design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/findrightdesign.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Find the Right Design&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/findrightdesign.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final point to investing in this activity up front is this. You are expressing a lot of ideas so you can eliminate the ones that don&#39;t work, and select that ones that are right, and solve the problem you&#39;re supposed to be solving—the optimal solution. This final, &#34;right&#34; concept declares the intent of the product you will build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How Do We Do It?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/how.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;How do we find the right design?&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/how.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the &#34;whys&#34; are what I focussed on when I was starting over. It may seem like a lot of torture to think about all these things when on the surface, sketching seems like something you should just do without much thought. But, I had to understand why I was feeling like I wasn&#39;t using sketching with intent. I wanted to know how I could use sketching in a way that is helpful in creating successful products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I really started to think about how to do this in a repeatable way every day. I needed to put it on paper, and be able to describe what I was doing to others I worked with. I needed to be able to test the idea with others as I tested the practice on projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up with a small set of guidelines that were easy enough for me to follow, and it may come off as being obvious, and perhaps stated simplistically, but I&#39;m a simple guy, and I need a clear and easy approach if I&#39;m to have any hope of sticking to it. It&#39;s much harder to do these things every day in practice. Believe me, it&#39;s easy to get seduced by tools and the details rather than see the bigger picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I want to talk about the pre-requisites to my guidelines, starting with the basics. What follows afterward is the approach I&#39;ve laid out for myself that I have been practicing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Anyone Can Sketch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/51043154?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&amp;amp;loop=1&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;If video above doesn&#39;t load, you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/51043154&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;view it here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with this basic idea that anyone should be able to do this, and how can we simplify sketching using a basic set of elements and language that anyone can use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some ideas that I found from Dan Roam, John Landay, and Dave Gray. The idea being that once you have these basic elements, a few forms, and some arrows and lines for flow, then you have the tools you need to express any idea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is all you need to learn to start to communicate visually with a sketch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Work Fast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/workfast.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/workfast.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the first guideline that I created for myself to follow, and the one I work hardest at. So the idea is to sketch faster, produce more, and to not stop and think too much about what I was doing when I was starting a design, but to get the ideas out, make them flow, and produce more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to start to try to come up with as many ideas as possible for any one problem that I&#39;m trying to solve, because more is really better at this stage than diving deep into details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working fast and generating more is fantastic if you&#39;re working in a design studio or any size team. Anyone can participate from designers and developers to business analysts and stakeholders. There are several great techniques that work well for eliciting more ideas that you can look to for inspiration. The idea with these techniques is that you gather around a group of people to work on one idea, with each person sketching a number of solutions for a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the team-based design concept that I&#39;ve heard Tod Zaki Warfel discuss. His &#34;6-8-5&#34; exercise works something like this. If each person in a group of 5 people got together and were given 5 minutes to to sketch 6-8 ideas for an interface, at the end of that 5 minutes, you&#39;d have a pool of 30-40 ideas you can review. It&#39;s a fantastic idea for rapidly exploring concepts in a team. See the links below for resources to help you incorporate these exercises into your process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leah Buley&#39;s sketchboard technique is discussed in her &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ugleah.com/ux-team-of-one/&#34;&gt;&#34;UX Team of One&#34; talk&lt;/a&gt;. Leah&#39;s 6up templates are also available for download on her site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tod Zaki Warfel&#39;s 6-8-5 is discussed in his &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/5381949&#34;&gt;Rapid Design Techniques&lt;/a&gt; talk. He summarized approach in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quora.com/Design/Why-does-Adaptive-Path-say-that-sketching-a-design-should-take-5-minutes-and-6-iterations/answer/Todd-Zaki-Warfel&#34;&gt;this Quora discussion&lt;/a&gt;. See also his &lt;a href=&#34;http://rosenfeldmedia.com/books/prototyping/&#34;&gt;Prototyping&lt;/a&gt; book.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Konigi, you can also &lt;a href=&#34;../tools/graph-paper.html#8up&#34;&gt;download a free 8-Up Sketch Template&lt;/a&gt; to use in rapid design sketching exercises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Capture The Essence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/capture.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Capture the essence and move on&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/capture.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The act of capturing the essence is something I remember and love from figure drawing classes. In a figure drawing class, the 1 minute and 3 minute pose are warm up exercises you do at the beginning of a session, where the purpose is to get you to loosen up and freely and loosely capture the figure, usually on newsprint, and usually as a way to get you ready to begin the real work. With speed and brevity in mind, one tends to look more at the whole form and the bigger picture and capture the character, gesture, and energy efficiently in as few lines as possible. In 1-3 minutes there&#39;s no time to focus on details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figure drawing sketch epitomizes for me what the quick thumbnail sketch is about. Capturing the essence when I&#39;m exploring ideas for the first time and then forcing myself to move on is a point that I try to remind myself of every time I approach a sketch book. When you&#39;re working fast you need to do only what&#39;s necessary to express the idea and keep moving on to the next idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of each iteration of idea generation we&#39;re concerned with volume. We&#39;re concerned with trying to get as many ideas out as possible. We&#39;ll come back to refine when we select the ideas with merit, and to refine further in the next round of iterations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ugly Is The Point&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/uglyispawesome.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Ugly is pawesome&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/uglyispawesome.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next idea I had for myself was to stop fussing over the details because at this point of the process, the important thing isn&#39;t representing the reality of how a button is going to be visually rendered and designed. But right now, I need to focus on representing the function and intention of the design before I actually work on the details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/uglyisthepoint.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Ugly is the point (sketch)&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/uglyisthepoint.jpg&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a sketch that we worked on in Balsamiq during a kitchen table discussion. We were discussing how we wanted to evolve the Spartan interface of an advanced feature that a small percentage of our users used regularly, to make it friendlier. To look at this mess of crossed out words, squiggles, and messy lines, you&#39;d think nothing of it. What a mess, right? But this is what happens when you&#39;re working out a solution to a problem. There will be mistakes. There will be adjustments in direction, and there will be exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ugly is the point when you&#39;re sketching. When we&#39;re capturing ideas at the speed of thought, the ideas will come faster than our hands can sketch them. So the messiness of though&amp;#8212;the uncertainty of the evolving idea&amp;#8212;is reflected in the sketch. However, while this sketch is not pretty, it does reflect the problem solving process. Although it may be difficult for those outside the conversation to see, the arrows and words represent the behaviors we want to trigger, and the controls that will be used in the interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Embrace Constraints&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/contstraints1.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Jack White on constraints&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/contstraints1.jpg&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Source: &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Under_Great_White_Northern_Lights&#34;&gt;Under Great White Northern Lights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://makinads.blogspot.com/2010/04/jack-white-on-creativity.html&#34;&gt;&#34;Jack White on Creativity&#34; in Makin Ads&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of using constraints to your advantage is important to me because it forces me to not care about how something looks, but force myself to focus on how something functions. I also like to call this the less is better rule. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Jack White talking about the power of constraints and using them to your advantage. What he&#39;s talking about is that all the tools and money in the world can actually prevent you from being creative if you end up thinking about tools more than coming up with the ideas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea also reminds me of an interview I once read. I think it was either an interview with fashion designer Michael Koors or with Tim Gunn. Sadly I can&#39;t recall where I read it. But the gist was that fashion guru in question was asked why he wears nothing but black suits. He said something like wearing simple and black means I don’t have to bother with making decisions about what I wear every day, so I can focus on the harder decisions about what other people are going to wear. I love this idea. Barry Schwartz&#39;s &lt;em&gt;Paradox of Choice&lt;/em&gt; also talks about this idea of removing choices might be one way to help focus on the important problems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are lots of ways you can put this guideline to work in how you sketch, or in anything you do as you make products. To put it in simpler terms, I&#39;ve thought of this as &#34;Less is Better&#34; when it comes to reducing tools and devices in the periphery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/constraints2.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;My constraints&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/constraints2.jpg&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of one expression of the idea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked this constraint. To capture ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pick one tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pick one color&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forget about the rest, because you&#39;re just trying to get the idea from here down to paper. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For you it could be something else. Take the example of Twitter. It&#39;s amazing that something as overlooked as imposing a constraint on the number of characters in a message can be so powerful, but the constraint leads to a very different form of communicating and a different way of framing ideas compared to longer, and often less edited messages. The constraint can come from anywhere, but for the technique of sketching, I focussed on the pen I use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1-2 Levels Of Fidelity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/fidelity.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Stick to 1 to 2 levels of fidelity&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/fidelity.jpg&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I talk about fidelity, I&#39;m talk about I&#39;m just talking about starting at a really abstract point, because when you&#39;re working really fast in thumbnails, you&#39;re just throwing down squares and squiggles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there once you need to add more information, that&#39;s when you get to making the boxes bigger, adding controls and words. And then you&#39;re also adding a lot of description to fill in the picture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ideas Come At Any Time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/ideasanytime1.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Always carry&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/ideasanytime1.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is more of a tip than a guideline, but a lot of ideas will come when you don&#39;t expect them, because once you start working on a problem, your brain can be working on the solution and then you might passively come up with the idea somewhere when you you&#39;re doing something else and are not ready for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me that happens a lot in the shower. I do a lot of foggy glass sketches in the shower while my mind is focussed on shampooing for some reason. When I used to drive to work, it used to happen in the car. Or in New York it happened in the subway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something that is common for a lot of designers and artists. Austin Kleon&#39;s book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.austinkleon.com/steal/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Steal Like an Artist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; talks about the artist David Hockney, who had suits and pants tailored to have pockets to hold sketchbooks so he was always ready when an idea came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/ideasanytime2.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Stuff I carry&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/ideasanytime2.jpg&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I carry paper in all sizes from sketchbooks to the little Field Notes books and the pocket Moleskine notebooks, and Levenger business card-sized cards that I keep in my wallet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also work on real and imagined projects to practice. While I’m on the subway, out at a cafe, anywhere, I practice my shapes and lettering, and take lots of notes to myself. I also take lots of screenshots and keep a swap file of things to steal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doodles are also important. I think of the doodling I do as my bonsai. It’s something I do repeatedly in my sketchbook with no real purpose, but sometimes the random doodles lead to real ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Discussion Over Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/discussion.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Discussion / Documentation&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/discussion.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is really in the same spirit of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://agilemanifesto.org/&#34;&gt;Agile Manifesto principle&lt;/a&gt;, “Individuals and interactions over processes and tools” and “Working software over comprehensive documentation.“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hate documentation when it’s done in isolation, when it’s costly, when it means less discussion between team members. This is a point I make a lot when I speak to people about design. The goal should be to discuss ideas, make decisions based on discussion, and to favor discussion over huge decks of documentation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people don&#39;t want to work with specs. I like to work with people to solve a problem, and in an iterative design, the point is to use sketching to figure out the design you&#39;re going to work on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a perfect world, we’d all have extra sensory perception and communicate telepathically what we imagine. But we don’t have that, so we rely on talking to each other, and explaining with pictures and models, doing what&#39;s necessary to find the idea that works—focus on talking to each other and getting to some consensus fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Explain Or Ideas Will Die&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/explain.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Explain or Die&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/explain.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you work fast and loose, one thing that&#39;s easy to neglect is the explanation. I find that I have to remember to describe everything with text. I have these sketches sometimes where I&#39;ll just make a few boxes that point to each other, and I&#39;ll come back and think, what I was thinking? I&#39;ll have no idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sketch is useless to you unless you can come back and recall the details of your idea. It&#39;s even more useless when it&#39;s time to come back and pass that idea to someone else. Sometimes a high level of abstraction can only go so far in helping to sell your idea without detail, because most likely your idea needs to be picked up, understood, and acted on by someone else.  Words are important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I look at messy sketches with words all over them and arrows criss-crossing between boxes, I&#39;m reminded of the algebra teacher that repeatedly said &#34;SHOW YOUR WORK.&#34; Showing your work in math is important to showing that you understand and can trace back how you arrive at a solution. Using annotation and markup is as important in sketching. It explains what&#39;s going on, and helps you visualize a path of interaction, and go back and retrace the steps when you reach dead ends. I&#39;ll take ugly sketches that show your thinking over pretty sketches that do little more than put lipstick on the pig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Know When To Stop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/stop.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Stop&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/stop.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this is easier to say to some people than others. If working on an agile team, you have no problem with this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There does come a point where you can stop and leave the sketches behind. Maybe you can use them as a reference to remind yourself what you were thinking. But you don&#39;t necessarily need to rework or update them—and the same with wireframes—the purpose of them is to help you think, make decisions, and pick the solution you&#39;re going to design. Then you build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem I have selling this idea is that for a lot of people, especially in in the agency scenario, the document is the deliverable they&#39;re selling. In an agile team you would have no problem with this since many product teams start their working code. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This goes along with the discussion over documentation argument. If the situation allows, you build when the expression of the interface is good enough that everyone understand what to build. Then that expression gets validated or disproved with a working product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve done you’re work of picking the right design, and solving the right problem, then the risk has already been mitigated in a huge way, so you hopefully need only to make smaller changes rather than disruptive pivots. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Do&#39;s &amp;amp; Don&#39;ts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/dodont.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Do and Don&#39;t&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/dodont.jpg&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To recap...  I guess the purpose of me getting in front of people to talk about this seems silly, but it&#39;s really easy to get into this cycle of thinking about your tools and documents rather than thinking about your product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reminders I have at the end of this are to really not worry about focussing on the details and getting precious about your work at this stage—the early idea generation stage. Keep stepping back and keep putting the bigger picture in mind as you go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Final Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/finalword.jpg&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Bruce on doing the work&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/finalword.jpg&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center gborder&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought a great way to end this message is to let someone much larger than myself make this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creativity is never really about the tools or what you&#39;re using to get your idea. As Bruce says here, &#34;there&#39;s no right way, no pure way of doing it—there&#39;s just doing it.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The act of thinking and solving problems is what&#39;s important, and I just happen to believe that sketching is one really powerful tool to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really believe there&#39;s a way to do it that should feel easier, and you shouldn&#39;t have to struggle with the feeling that you suck at it, because this is one case where sucking is not a bad thing, if you&#39;re doing it with the right intent of solving the problem in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thanks. Make Great Stuff.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/make.png&#34; class=&#34;group&#34; rel=&#34;group&#34; title=&#34;Make Great Stuff!&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/make.png&#34; class=&#34;block mb1-5 center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can&#39;t get enough? Here are a few more great resources not mentioned, if you want dig deeper into Sketching user interfaces and interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/articles/why_sketching/&#34;&gt;&#34;Why We Sketch,&#34;&lt;/a&gt; by Jared Spool. User Interface Engineering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://52weeksofux.com/post/346650933/sketch-sketch-sketch&#34;&gt;&#34;Sketch Sketch Sketch,&#34;&lt;/a&gt;  by Joshua Brewer. 52 Weeks of UX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.davegrayinfo.com/2008/04/08/forms-fields-and-flows/&#34;&gt;&#34;Forms, Fields and Flows,&#34;&lt;/a&gt; byDave Gray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://braindoodles.net/&#34;&gt;Brain Doodles&lt;/a&gt;, Visual Thinking Tutorials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://davidbarneswork.posterous.com/think-you-cant-draw-here-are-6-artists-whose&#34;&gt;&#34;Think You Can&#39;t Draw? Here Are 6 Artists Whose Work Will Help!&#34;&lt;/a&gt; by David Barnes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../notebook/tags/sketching.html&#34;&gt;Konigi articles on Sketching&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossaries</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/wiki/glossaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/wiki/glossaries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nathan.com/ed/glossary/&#34;&gt;Experience Design Glossary&lt;/a&gt;. Nathan Shedroff.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.archive.org/web/20070417104203rn_1/www.iawiki.net/action=browse&amp;amp;id=GlossaryOfTerms&amp;amp;oldid=IAGlossary&#34;&gt;IA Glossary&lt;/a&gt;. IAWiki (via Internet Archive).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://argus-acia.com/white_papers/iaglossary.html&#34;&gt;Information Architecture Glossary&lt;/a&gt;. Kat Hagedorn. Argus Associates. March, 2000. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thoughtsoninteraction.com/glossary.html&#34;&gt;Interaction Design Glossary&lt;/a&gt;. Thoughts on Interaction Design.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.interaction-design.org/encyclopedia/&#34;&gt;Interaction Design Glossary&lt;/a&gt;. Interaction-Design.org.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.usabilitybok.org/glossary&#34;&gt;Usability Glossary&lt;/a&gt;. Usability Body of Knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.usabilityfirst.com/glossary/&#34;&gt;Usability Glossary&lt;/a&gt;. Usability First.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac Apps for an Easily Distracted Mind</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/wiki/mac-apps-easily-distracted-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/wiki/mac-apps-easily-distracted-mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/14895848441&#34; title=&#34;Desktop 20140812 by Michael Angeles, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5590/14895848441_5c0942e657_c.jpg&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;Desktop 20140812&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;Ping, ping, ping. Software should stay out of the way so I can get stuff done.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have trouble focusing on certain types of work and need to turn notifications off and use alarms and timers to stay on task. I&#39;ve written about my &lt;a href=&#34;../notebook/finding-focus-while-trying-work.html&#34;&gt;constant pursuit of focus&lt;/a&gt;. To give you an idea of how obsessive I am about this, take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/14895848441/&#34;&gt;what my desktop looks like&lt;/a&gt;. The desktop wallpaper is by &lt;a href=&#34;http://dizzyup.co.uk/wallpapers/&#34;&gt;Hector Simpson&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the apps I use to put the blinders on. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://notational.net/&#34;&gt;Notational Velocity&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://brettterpstra.com/project/nvalt/&#34;&gt;nvALT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Notational Velocity is my do-it-all notebook. It functions as my commonplace book and stores ideas and notes I want to recall later. I love this tool above all other note-taking tools because it&#39;s a minimal text editor with virtually no interface--the flow from launch to search/open or create/edit is a seamless text-only experience. It syncs with Simplenote, so I can access/edit on my iPhone and iPad. I also use &lt;a href=&#34;https://evernote.com/&#34;&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; for longer text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/app/id439623248&#34;&gt;iA Writer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I love the simplicity of the iA Writer and that is has some simple text formatting using Markdown. The focus mode is nice, although I rarely use it. Uses Markdown and can sync with DropBox and the iPad version. See also &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ommwriter.com/en/download.html&#34;&gt;OmmWriter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mailplaneapp.com/&#34;&gt;Mailplane&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I use Mailplane so I never have to have a Gmail window open in a browser tab. I can turn notifications on and off, switch between email accounts, and drag and drop attachments into messages. Best of all, it feels more like a single-purpose mail app than a web app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Productivity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alfredapp.com/&#34;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Quicksilver was my launcher for years. Alfred has replaced it. Minimal and there when I need it, and does much more than I expect it to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pomodoro.ugolandini.com/&#34;&gt;Pomodoro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This is an unobtrusive Pomodoro timer that sits in the menubar so you can set it when you start a task. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pomodorotechnique.com/&#34;&gt;Pomodoro Technique&lt;/a&gt; uses 25 minute increments for focusing on tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://todotxt.com/&#34;&gt;Todo.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Todo.txt is a shell script for managing a simple text file-based task list. There&#39;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ginatrapani/todo.txt-cli&#34;&gt;command line interface&lt;/a&gt; that you can use with the &lt;A href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/todo.txt-touch/id491342186?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&#34;&gt;iPhone App&lt;/a&gt; if you&#39;re saving your file to Dropbox. Super simple and does all I need it to do, including handling projects, priorities and dates.  I&#39;ve been adding tasks with this &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/benignoc/alfred-todotxt&#34;&gt;Alfred workflow&lt;/a&gt; so I never have to open an app or terminal window most of the time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mizage.com/divvy/&#34;&gt;Divvy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I&#39;m a single-application mode Mac user. I use Cmd-Opt-Click to view apps in single app mode, so when I do, I like to position app windows front and center, or sometimes pinned to one side or expanded to full screen. Divvy lets me click Cmd-Shift-Space to do this in a split second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macbartender.com/&#34;&gt;Bartender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I like to hide as much as possible on my screen when I&#39;m in &#34;focus mode.&#34; Bartender let&#39;s you make the menubar quiet without having to use apps in full screen mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stclairsoft.com/DefaultFolderX/&#34;&gt;Default Folder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When I save something, I usually want to quickly navigate to my most recent, most used, or favorite locations. This utility makes it a piece of cake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://unclutterapp.com/&#34;&gt;Unclutter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It makes me happy to see nothing on my desktop. Unclutter tucks away my desktop files into a drawer that I can access with a 2-finger downward swipe gesture at the top of my screen. It can hold files, a multi-clip clipboard, and a scratchpad for notes. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storyboards</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/wiki/storyboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/wiki/storyboards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc0&#34;&gt;Definitions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storyboarding is the technique interaction designers and information architects have adopted from film and animation to specify interaction in user interfaces. Storyboards in interaction design typically show a sequence of key frames that depict when a change in state occurs in the interface. They are often illustrated with a linear, multi-cell diagram, often accompanied by annotations to describe the actions taken by the user, and the responses or behavior of the system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc1&#34;&gt;In Interaction Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storyboards were originally conceived at Disney Studios about seventy years ago. They are a sequential series of illustrations or rough sketches, sometimes including captions of events. Storyboards provide a synopsis for a proposed story (or a complex scene) involving its action and characters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storyboards transfer well into the world of the user interface. With a storyboard we can present as frames each step in a sequence of user interactions. Viewing the interaction in a story format helps to refine the interaction and provide feedback for user testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boxesandarrows.com/view/storyboarding_rich_internet_applications_with_visio&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Storyboarding Rich Internet Applications with Visio,&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; by Bill Scott. Boxes and Arrows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc2&#34;&gt;In Film&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;a sequential series of illustrations, stills, rough sketches and/or captions (sometimes resembling a comic or cartoon strip) of events, as seen through the camera lens, that outline the various shots or provide a synopsis for a proposed film story (or for a complex scene) with its action and characters; the storyboards are displayed in sequence for the purpose of visually mapping out and crafting the various shot divisions and camera movements in an animated or live-action film; a blank storyboard is a piece of paper with rectangles drawn on it to represent the camera frame (for each successive shot); a sophisticated type of preview-storyboard (often shot and edited on video, with a soundtrack) is termed an animatic&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://filmsite.org/filmterms18.html&#34;&gt;AMC Film Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See also &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Storyboard&#34;&gt;definitions from Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc3&#34;&gt;Examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/wiki/storyboard.png&#34; title=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/wiki/storyboard.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/wiki/storyboard.png&#34; alt=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/wiki/storyboard.png&#34; title=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/wiki/storyboard.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interface and Interaction Notation</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/wiki/interface-and-interaction-notation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/wiki/interface-and-interaction-notation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc0&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resources for annotating interfaces and interaction. Includes notation techniques for systems using input devices or gestural recognition for interpreting human body movement and other attribute recognition for input.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc1&#34;&gt;General&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linowski.ca/sketching.php&#34;&gt;Interactive Sketching Notation&lt;/a&gt;. Jakub Linowski&amp;rsquo;s techniques for specifying interaction. &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/43869717&#34;&gt;See Video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/1926-a-shorthand-for-designing-ui-flows&#34;&gt;A shorthand for designing UI flows&lt;/a&gt;. Ryan Singer&amp;rsquo;s technique for illustrating flow.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jjg.net/ia/visvocab/&#34;&gt;Visual Vocabulary&lt;/a&gt;. Jesse James Garret&amp;rsquo;s system for diagramming information architecture and interaction design.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Wireframes Magazine. See examples of &lt;a href=&#34;http://wireframes.linowski.ca/tag/annotation/&#34;&gt;Annotation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://wireframes.linowski.ca/tag/user-flow/&#34;&gt;User Flow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc2&#34;&gt;Touch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/design/patterns/gestures.html&#34;&gt;Android Gestures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.apple.com/kb/HT4721&#34;&gt;Apple OS X Lion: About Multi-Touch gestures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://somerandomdude.com/work/cue/&#34;&gt;Cue, by P.J. Onori&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.rongeorge.com/design/gesturcons/&#34;&gt;Gesturcons, by Ron George&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://gesturecons.com/&#34;&gt;Gesturecons, by Ryan Lee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi-touch#Multi-touch_gestures&#34;&gt;Multi Touch Gestures, in Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://gestureworks.com/features/open-source-gestures/&#34;&gt;Open Source Gesture Library, by Gesture Works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lukew.com/ff/entry.asp?1071&#34;&gt;Touch Gesture Reference Guide, by Luke Wroblewski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lukew.com/ff/entry.asp?1073&#34;&gt;Touch Gestures List, by Luke Wroblewski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://mattgemmell.com/2010/07/14/touch-notation/&#34;&gt;Touch Notation, by Matt Gemmel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kickerstudio.com/blog/2008/12/touchscreen-stencils/&#34;&gt;Touchscreen Stencils, by Kicker Studio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ee220920.aspx&#34;&gt;Using Gestures in Windows Mobile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc3&#34;&gt;Kinetic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.xbox.com/en-US/kinect/body-tracking/body-controller&#34;&gt;XBox Kinect Gestures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc4&#34;&gt;See Also&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.interaction-design.org/encyclopedia/formal_methods.html&#34;&gt;Formal Methods for Specification&lt;/a&gt;, Interaction Design Foundation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lorem Ipsum</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/wiki/lorem-ipsum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/wiki/lorem-ipsum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc0&#34;&gt;Definition&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorem Ipsum refers to the meaningless text used as placeholder or filler in visual design to suggest where text should be placed for layout. Other terms for this filler include Greeking, Placeholder Text, and Dummy Text. The text starting &amp;quot;Lorem ipsum dolor...&amp;quot; was traditionally a Latin passage by Cicero with words altered, added and removed that make it nonsensical in meaning and not proper Latin. &lt;br /&gt;
Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lorem_ipsum&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc1&#34;&gt;Text Generators&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc2&#34;&gt;Traditional&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://lipsum.com/&#34;&gt;Lipsum&lt;/a&gt; - Standard Lorem Ipsum that lets you set number of paragraphs, list items, etc.  Also available as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/o9wvR&#34;&gt;Google Chrome Extension&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;../tools/submissions/html-ipsum.html&#34;&gt;HTML Ipsum&lt;/a&gt; - HTML marked up standard Lorem Ipsum&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://littleipsum.com/&#34;&gt;Little Ipsum&lt;/a&gt; - Menubar app for Mac to copy greeked words, sentences or paragraphs as plain text or HTML.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://lorem-ipsum.me/&#34;&gt;Lorem Ipsum Me&lt;/a&gt; - Copy Blog or Essay length lorem ipsum passages to clipboard. Provides an API to use with curl or Ruby.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pakapaka/id423792431&#34;&gt;PakaPaka&lt;/a&gt; - Mac greeking app. Generate Greek, Classical Greek, German, Hebrew, Hindi, Old French, and of course, Bla- blah. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc3&#34;&gt;Non-Traditional&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://baconipsum.com/&#34;&gt;Bacon Ipsum&lt;/a&gt; - A meatier Lorem Ipsum generator.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://johndoesdesign.com/british-ipsum/&#34;&gt;British Ipsum&lt;/a&gt; - Gettin&amp;rsquo; cheeky wit it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://cupcakeipsum.com/&#34;&gt;Cupcake Ipsum&lt;/a&gt; - Sugar coated Lorem Ipsum generator.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; Corporate Ipsum &lt;a href=&#34;http://doubleforte.net/widgets/corporate/&#34;&gt;Mac Widget&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/mqIYF&#34;&gt;Google Chrome Extension&lt;/a&gt; - Business Bullshit generator.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fillerati.com/&#34;&gt;Fillerati&lt;/a&gt; - Literary ipsum. Select an author and title, and choose an excerpt rendered in html or plain text.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://goo.gl/YCKXc&#34;&gt;Futureipsum&lt;/a&gt; - Futurama style filler, Google Chrome Extension&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lorizzle.nl/?feed=1&#34;&gt;Gangsta Ipsum&lt;/a&gt; - Gangsta style ipsum.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://slipsum.com/&#34;&gt;Samuel L. Ipsum&lt;/a&gt; - Samuel L. Jackson style ipsum.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://socialgoodipsum.com/&#34;&gt;Social Ipsum&lt;/a&gt; - A socially conscious text generator.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://hipsteripsum.me/&#34;&gt;Hipster Ipsum&lt;/a&gt; - Williamsburg style hipster dump.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc4&#34;&gt;See Also&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;../tools/tags/placeholder-images.html&#34;&gt;Placeholder Image generators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/05/the-eternal-lorem-ipsum.html&#34;&gt;The Eternal Lorem Ipsum, Coding Horror&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Interface Galleries</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/wiki/user-interface-galleries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/wiki/user-interface-galleries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc0&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page contains informal galleries of interface and visual designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc1&#34;&gt;User Interface Galleries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc2&#34;&gt;Mobile&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://inspired-ui.com/&#34;&gt;Inspired UI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iospirations.com/&#34;&gt;IOSpirations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lovelyui.com/&#34;&gt;Lovely UI (Mobile Gallery)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mobiledesignpatterngallery.com/mobile-patterns.php&#34;&gt;Mobile Design Pattern Gallery, by Theresa Neil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://mobile-patterns.com/&#34;&gt;Mobile UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://pttrns.com/&#34;&gt;pttrns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc3&#34;&gt;Web&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/designingwebinterfaces/&#34;&gt;Designing Web Interfaces Photostream&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/designingwebinterfaces/collections/&#34;&gt;Collections&lt;/a&gt; on Flickr, by Bill Scott and Theresa Neil&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://littlebigdetails.com/&#34;&gt;Little Big Details&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://miniajax.com/&#34;&gt;MiniAJAX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://patterntap.com/&#34;&gt;Pattern Tap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.patternsofdesign.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Patterns of Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://productplanner.com/&#34;&gt;Product Planner User Flow Gallery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/morville/collections/72157603785835882/&#34;&gt;Search Patterns Collection on Flickr, by Peter Morville&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smileycat.com/design_elements/&#34;&gt;Smiley Cat&amp;rsquo;s Elements of Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/factoryjoe/collections/72157600001823120/&#34;&gt;UI Collection on Flickr, by Chris Messina&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uiparade.com/&#34;&gt;UI Parade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/rosenfeldmedia/sets/72157604272550634/&#34;&gt;Web Form Design: Filling In the Blanks (book illustrations)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc4&#34;&gt;User Interface Screencasts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/channels/nui&#34;&gt;NUI (Natural User Interface) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/channels/interactiondesign&#34;&gt;Interaction Design Channel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vimeo.com/user641592/videos&#34;&gt;Interaction Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/75193&#34;&gt;Interfaces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vimeo.com/jibbajabba/videos&#34;&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/album/60924&#34;&gt;UI Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vimeo.com/album/17554&#34;&gt;UI Screencasts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/channels/xui&#34;&gt;XUI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc5&#34;&gt;See Also&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;design-patterns.html&#34;&gt;Design Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;design-pattern-repositories.html&#34;&gt;Design Pattern Repositories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concept Design</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/wiki/concept-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/wiki/concept-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Definitions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Concept design is an early phase of the design process that explores far-ranging design ideas which are plausible but which often set aside immediate technical and situational constraints in order to generate new options. The results can be seen in the concept cars from Pininfarina, the futuristic structures rendered by Rem Koolhaas’s Office for Metropolitan Architecture, and the Christian Lacroix designs on the runways of Paris.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digital-web.com/articles/concept_design_tools/&#34;&gt;Concept Design Tools&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Digital Web Magazine. By Victor Lombardi.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also known as: &amp;ldquo;conceptual design&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Videos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&amp;ldquo;Concept Design in 2 Minutes.&amp;rdquo; Nokia.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/Jo2SG4JhohQ?fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en_US&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/Jo2SG4JhohQ?fs=1&amp;amp;hl=en_US&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Sketching-User-Experiences-Interactive-Technologies/dp/0123740371&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sketching User Experiences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, by Bill Buxton.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Product-Concept-Design-Conceptual-Products/dp/1846281253/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Product Concept Design: A Review of the Conceptual Design of Products in Industry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, by Turkka Kalervo Keinonen and Roope Takala.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Patterns</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/wiki/dark-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/wiki/dark-patterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc0&#34;&gt;Definitions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dark Patterns are interface design patterns that have been designed to trick users into doing things they wouldn’t otherwise have done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term was coined by Harry Brignull, who writes on &lt;a href=&#34;http://darkpatterns.org/&#34;&gt;DarkPatterns.org&lt;/a&gt;, that they are carefully crafted with a solid understanding of human psychology, and they do not have the user’s interests in mind. In the talk Brignull gave at UX Brighton 2010, he calls for a code of ethics among professionals in the user interface design industries, and for professional associations to acknowledge that these practices are unethical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc1&#34;&gt;See also&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;design-patterns.html&#34;&gt;Design Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;design-pattern-repositories.html&#34;&gt;Design Pattern Repositories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;../node/1383.html&#34;&gt;Anti-Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>