<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Competitive Analysis on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/competitive-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Competitive Analysis on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/competitive-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>What are your favorite customer support sites and why?</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/what-are-your-favorite-customer-support-sites-and-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/what-are-your-favorite-customer-support-sites-and-why/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m doing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m doing a review of customer support sites, looking mostly for software (desktop and web) and services-related sites that provide a customer support site for getting answers to questions, and viewing documentation and tutorials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why I&amp;rsquo;m doing it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Some sites have better search capabilities for questions than others. Other sites do well at presenting documentation. I&amp;rsquo;m finding that there&amp;rsquo;s sometimes a difference in how companies handle giving answers to the most granular questions as opposed to presenting a unified view of a product via a manual-like experience. There&amp;rsquo;s a smaller/larger need, first time/experienced user dichotomy of needs, among other different descriptions of how and why a user approaches a support site. The need may range from &amp;ldquo;How do I do X&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;How do I get started using this&amp;rdquo; and every grayer need in between. I&amp;rsquo;m currently involved on a project where this is the problem we&amp;rsquo;re faced with as the company has gone through several stages of growth, and needs to evolve legacy content and systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Can you help?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
What are you favorite support sites in terms of these kinds of needs? I&amp;rsquo;m going to screen capture and review a handful of them here and show a cross-site comparison of capabilities. As a bonus, I&amp;rsquo;m doing a giveaway of a couple sketchbooks from those who comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please give me the name of the company and the URL for the support site. And thanks for helping out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some of my starting points&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uxmatters.com/mt/archives/2007/11/customer-support-on-the-web-dont-call-us-well-call-you.php&#34;&gt;UX Matters: Customer Support on the Web: Don’t Call Us, We’ll Call You&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ixda.org/node/19874&#34;&gt;IXDA Discussion: Examples of Good Customer Support Sites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getharvest.com/blog/2010/09/what-makes-a-good-help-section/&#34;&gt;Harvest: What Makes a Good Help Section?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2012/10/02/facebook-redesigns-help-center-to-suggest-answers-completes-roll-out-of-support-dashboard/&#34;&gt;TechCrunch: Facebook Redesigns Help Center To Suggest Answers, Completes Roll Out Of Support Dashboard&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/notes/facebook-safety/improved-tools-to-support-your-facebook-experience/473126442708143&#34;&gt;Facebook: Improved Tools to Support Your Facebook Experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.zendesk.com/entries/20470266&#34;&gt;ZenDesk: Examples of sites using ZD as their primary KB?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.desk.com/blog/12-awesomely-designed-support-centers-and-what-makes-them-rock/&#34;&gt;Desk: 12 Awesomely Designed Support Centers and What Makes Them Rock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seth Godin on the Importance of Domain Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/seth-godin-importance-domain-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/seth-godin-importance-domain-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seth Godin&#39;s blog often talks about where successful ideas come from, and in this post talks about &lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/08/bypassing-the-leap.html&#34;&gt;bypassing the need to make huge leaps in innovation&lt;/a&gt; by synthesizing what we know and have learned from history, using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.appleinsider.com/articles/10/01/09/palm_ceo_former_apple_exec_says_hes_never_used_an_iphone.html&#34;&gt;Palm as the cautionary tale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;It&#39;s not enough to be aware of the domain you&#39;re working in, you need to understand it. Noticing things and being curious about how they work is the single most common trait I see in creative people. Once you can break the components down, you can put them back together into something brand new.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why we are constantly doing competitive monitoring and analysis of the products in the industries we work in. At times I feel kind of crazed signing up for betas out there, because the speed at which they appear now is overwhelming. I just have to remind myself that it&#39;s ok to spend the time if there&#39;s some research value, and then quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether we&#39;re just looking at the landscape from a high level, or deeply investigating and deconstructing how things work, continually expanding or improving domain knowledge is always going to be an important activity for us as designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/08/bypassing-the-leap.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Fsethsmainblog+%28Seth%27s+Blog%29&#34;&gt;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/08/bypassing-the-leap.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Fsethsmainblog+%28Seth%27s+Blog%29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AlternativeTo: App comparison site may be useful for competitive research</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/alternativeto-app-comparison-site-may-be-useful-competitive-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/alternativeto-app-comparison-site-may-be-useful-competitive-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alternativeto.net/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1598&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4a083313cd9f9.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alternativeto.net/&#34;&gt;AlternativeTo&lt;/a&gt; might be an interesting tool when doing competitive research. The new site describes itself as a a way to find better Windows, Mac, Linux and online applications by submitting the app you want to replace. It&amp;rsquo;s a community site that relies on user submissions, so the number of alternatives is limited in some areas. Having a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://alternativeto.net/desktop/basecamp/&#34;&gt;Basecamp alternatives&lt;/a&gt;, for instance, only shows MS Project and the RedMine web app when I looked. But more popular app suggestions are abundant, e.g. alternatives to &lt;a href=&#34;http://alternativeto.net/SearchResult.aspx?profile=software&amp;amp;search=word&#34;&gt;MS Word&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could be a good resource with time for collecting examples to reference when doing a competitive study for a web app. One to watch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alternativeto.net/&#34;&gt;http://alternativeto.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>