<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Activism on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/activism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Activism on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/activism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Re-nourish: Design Sustainably</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/re-nourish-design-sustainably/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/re-nourish-design-sustainably/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.re-nourish.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2225&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4b295874ef1e1_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.re-nourish.com/&#34;&gt;Re-nourish.com&lt;/a&gt; is an independent online toolkit for sustainable graphic design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;By providing reliable, accessible sustainability tools untethered to commercial interests, we empower graphic designers to implement sustainable decision making in their day-to-day work. Our mission is nothing short of changing the industry, helping truly sustainable graphic design become what design is, not merely what it &amp;quot;could be.&amp;quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.re-nourish.com/&#34;&gt;Check it out&lt;/a&gt; and learn how to change your business&#39; impact on the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.re-nourish.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.re-nourish.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Feast Conference</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/feast-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/feast-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.feastongood.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1774&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4a4223e15b469.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve registered to join the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.feastongood.com/&#34;&gt;Feast Conference&lt;/a&gt; in New York City on Oct. 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Feast Conference gathers the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest innovators from across industries and society to empower, inspire and engage each other in creating world-shaking change. A creative look at the world&amp;rsquo;s toughest problems, The Feast Conference presents the most innovative solutions, insights, and best practices as a catalyst toward action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than a conference, The Feast represents a bottom-up movement, so we&amp;rsquo;re curating an audience as cross-disciplinary and diverse as our talks. But we&amp;rsquo;re doing something a little different &amp;ndash; we ask those who can afford to pay higher prices to micro-sponsor The Feast, which allows us to offer $99 invitations to awe-inspiring vanguards whose brains get them where their wallets can&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bottom-up innovation, unparalleled connections and real exchange &amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s something we can sink our teeth into. Join us and get full on good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of my friends and colleagues know that over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about and have been looking for productive ways to fuse my interests in creativity and education/learning with my interests in activism, and the need to live with compassion and empathy. Increasingly, I also want to bring my knowledge and skillset as a web designer into this amorphous mass of desire and need to contribute more positively to society and improve the human condition. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been to an event that fuses the creativity and activism before, so I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to get inspired and make connections there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve alluded to my interest in doing something like this in whatever small way I can via Konigi, but that plan hasn&amp;rsquo;t manifested yet. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to meet some like-minded people at this event, and elsewhere in whatever way I can. If you&amp;rsquo;re like-minded in this sense, and feel a similar pull, I&amp;rsquo;m always willing to chat over coffee in the NYC area. &lt;a href=&#34;../contact.html&#34;&gt;I can be reached here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.feastongood.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.feastongood.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>