<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>uilang</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/uilang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/uilang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uilang.com/&#34;&gt;uilang&lt;/a&gt; is a minimal, ui-focused programming language for web designers that handles click events, primarily for toggling classes and css display properties. I love the natural language approach to scripting in uilang. You just insert a statement in a code block like this and it works magically: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&amp;lt;code&amp;gt;clicking on &#34;.try-it&#34; toggles class &#34;hidden&#34; on &#34;.info-box&#34;&amp;lt;/code&amp;gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;
You still have to write your CSS to handle things like effects, but that&#39;s a plus if you don&#39;t want or need someone else&#39;s implementation of those things. &lt;a href=&#34;http://uilang.com/&#34;&gt;Check it out.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/ht &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/leonbarnard&#34;&gt;Leon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uilang.com/&#34;&gt;http://uilang.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adobe Shadow Mobile Device Testing</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/adobe-shadow-mobile-device-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/adobe-shadow-mobile-device-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Adobe Labs&#39; &lt;a href=&#34;http://labs.adobe.com/technologies/shadow/&#34;&gt;Shadow&lt;/a&gt; is an application for Mac and Windows that allows you to preview and inspect your mobile website on iOS and Android devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After installing the software on your computer and any number of mobile devices, you can connect and pair them and all devices will be kept in sync with the web site you&#39;re previewing on your computer. This should help perform remote inspection and debugging so you can see HTML/CSS/JavaScript changes instantly on your devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://labs.adobe.com/technologies/shadow/&#34;&gt;http://labs.adobe.com/technologies/shadow/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why The Valley Wants Designers That Can Code</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/why-valley-wants-designers-can-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/why-valley-wants-designers-can-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jared Spool talks about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2011/05/31/why-the-valley-wants-designers-that-can-code/&#34;&gt;why designers who code are popular in Silicon Valley&lt;/a&gt; right now, and for the most part, it boils down to this. Small software and web startups value and are able to use a broader range of skillsets, because one of the highest priorities, especially for bootstrapped startups, is to ship while lean on resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jared notes that those who don&#39;t think designers should know how to code say this dilutes the designer&#39;s value. I think we&#39;re talking both interaction designers and visual designers here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main point for me is that particular organizations favor someone more M-shaped than T-shaped, which is to say, they need to be deeper in more than one set of skills. This is true of more types of organizations than just small startups, but the main idea is that multi-role people &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; valued in organizations that are open to having  a person who can execute on a diverse set of responsibilities, even if they&#39;re viewed as &amp;quot;diluted&amp;quot; in terms of being less deep in one area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll say this. I started out doing interface design and development work on databases in-house in a corporation. Early on in my career, I envied the people who got to work on the sexy, high-profile projects and made the switch to doing front end-development at an agency. Unsatisfied with that, I went back in-house doing both design and development, and then envied the design side, and went to a company to do interaction design only. I&#39;ve never been satisfied in a silo, and have been happiest being involved across a project. I&#39;ve found that working on both ends as a designer and developer to be ideal for me, even if the development is only front-end development and prototyping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I don&#39;t think it is particularly easy to find a home when you&#39;re more M than T-shaped. Certain types of organizations won&#39;t even let you interview for more than one type of role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve spoken to quite a few people looking to make a shift from one side to another over the years. It&#39;s kind of easy to recognize an M-shaped person. They may have worked in small organizations that gave them more room to flex their muscles outside of their role, or they may be freelancers that get to and maybe have to do design and development. For whatever reason, that varied experience can make it hard for them to find the right home and to convince hiring people to consider a cross-disciplinary role to fit them into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I think what Jared is talking about could be very helpful to both the budding UX designers out there, and those considering making a change in role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems obvious to say, but if you can already do some development and you want to use it, you might look for an organization that values it. Small startups or in-house positions with small development organizations where multi-role people are valued is a good start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can&#39;t do some kind of code, at least learn HTML5, CSS and a little Javascript, and maybe some other server-side scripting languages. If you can&#39;t convince your organization to use you in that capacity, then demonstrate your skill doing prototypes in code when the opportunity presents itself, and keep your skills sharp. When there seems like no way to flex your development muscles in your current job, work on personal projects continually to stay sharp and relevant!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2011/05/31/why-the-valley-wants-designers-that-can-code/&#34;&gt;Read more at UIE&lt;/a&gt;. Interested in learning to code for the web? There are &lt;a href=&#34;../wiki/learn-code.html&#34;&gt;some resources for that here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2011/05/31/why-the-valley-wants-designers-that-can-code/&#34;&gt;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2011/05/31/why-the-valley-wants-designers-that-can-code/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drupal Coda Clips</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/drupal-coda-clips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/drupal-coda-clips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dezinerfolio.com/freebie/drupal-coda-clips&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2753&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt52304b5b464bf_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dezinerfolio&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dezinerfolio.com/freebie/drupal-coda-clips&#34;&gt;free Drupal snippet library for the Coda editor&lt;/a&gt; (Mac OS only) provides a very useful set of code clips for theming Drupal sites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dezinerfolio.com/freebie/drupal-coda-clips&#34;&gt;http://www.dezinerfolio.com/freebie/drupal-coda-clips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Napkin Look &amp; Feel</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/napkin-look-feel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/napkin-look-feel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://napkinlaf.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/napkin-look-and-feel.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://napkinlaf.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Napkin Look and Feel&lt;/a&gt; is a cool looking open source tool for Java developers to produce application prototypes with a low-fidelity sketchy interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea is to try to develop a look and feel that can be used in Java applications that looks informal and provisional, yet be fully functional for development. Often when people see a GUI mock-up, or a complete GUI without full functionality, they assume that the code behind it is working. While this can be used to sleazy advantage, it can also convince people who ought to know better (like your managers) that you are already done when you have just barely begun, or when only parts are complete. No matter how much you speak to their rational side, the emotional response still says &amp;ldquo;Done!&amp;rdquo;. Which after a while leads to a later question: &amp;ldquo;That was done months ago! What are they doing? Playing Quake?&amp;rdquo; A good article on this is Joel on Software&amp;rsquo;s “The Iceberg Secret, Revealed”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the idea is to create a complete look and feel that can be used while the thing is not done which will convey an emotional message to match the rational one. As pieces of the work are done, the GUI for those pieces can be switched to use the &amp;ldquo;formal&amp;rdquo; (final) look and feel, allowing someone looking at demos over time to see the progress of the entire system reflected in the expression of the GUI. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://napkinlaf.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;http://napkinlaf.sourceforge.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SproutCore</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/sproutcore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/sproutcore/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sproutcore.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1327&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4868ffd0a873a_0.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sproutcore.com/&#34;&gt;SproutCore&lt;/a&gt; has been getting some buzz after the June Apple WWDC, where SproutCore was demoed. This is an MVC framework that builds a standards-based application that runs entirely in the browser and is not tied to a single scripting language to power the back end. The framework is being used to drive the new &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/mobileme/&#34;&gt;MobileMe&lt;/a&gt; service from Apple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;SproutCore is a framework for building applications in JavaScript with remarkably little amounts of code. It can help you build full “thick” client applications in the web browser that can create and modify data, often completely independent of your web server, communicating with your server via Ajax only when they need to save or load data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a review of SproutCore &lt;a href&#34;http://arstechnica.com/journals/apple.ars/2008/06/17/sproutcore-rich-web-apps-in-javascript-no-flash-needed&#34;&gt;in Ars Technica&lt;/a&gt;, with lengthy discussion about some browser issues that may affect the decision to use it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sproutcore.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.sproutcore.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find Freelance Developers With oDesk</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/find-freelance-developers-odesk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/find-freelance-developers-odesk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.odesk.com/w/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1296&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4846e2291ee4d.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Designers come up with great ideas, but we aren&amp;rsquo;t always the right people to pull off the technical implementation. If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, you might be itching to get some of those ideas out into the world. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.odesk.com/w/&#34;&gt;oDesk&lt;/a&gt; is a resource for finding and tracking freelance developers to work on your project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get your sketches into the hands of someone who will make it real, this might be a useful resource. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used this service or any others like it in the past, so I&amp;rsquo;d be interested in hearing if others have an opinion of oDesk or know of other freelance development sourcing sites.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.odesk.com/w/&#34;&gt;http://www.odesk.com/w/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>