<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>John M. Carroll on the History of HCI</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/john-m-carroll-history-hci/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/john-m-carroll-history-hci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John M. Carroll discusses the history of Human Computer Interaction on Interaction-Design.org.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Human-computer interaction (HCI) is an area of research and practice that emerged in the early 1980s, initially as a specialty area in computer science. HCI has expanded rapidly and steadily for three decades, attracting professionals from many other disciplines and incorporating diverse concepts and approaches. To a considerable extent, HCI now aggregates a collection of semi-distinct fields of research and practice in human-centered informatics. However, the continuing synthesis of disparate conceptions and approaches to science and practice in HCI has produced a dramatic example of how different epistemologies and paradigms can be reconciled and integrated.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.interaction-design.org/encyclopedia/human_computer_interaction_hci.html&#34;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.interaction-design.org/encyclopedia/human_computer_interaction_hci.html&#34;&gt;http://www.interaction-design.org/encyclopedia/human_computer_interaction_hci.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The History &amp; Evolution of User Experience Design</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/history-evolution-user-experience-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/history-evolution-user-experience-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.teawithteresa.com/2009/03/history-evolution-of-user-experience.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1534&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt49b811b22fb50.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the Tea with Teresa podcast, Teresa Brazen interviews Adaptive Path&amp;rsquo;s Peter Merholz to talk about the history and evolution of User Experience Design. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;User experience design is, at its core, a philosophy that products and services should be designed so that they are pleasurable and easy for people to use. While that might seem an obvious design approach, it&amp;rsquo;s actually not the way many designers historically thought about making things. In fact, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until the 1990s that an industry came together around this particular approach to design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did some research to try uncover the history of this field, and, I didn&amp;rsquo;t find a lot - partly because it hasn’t been around for long. So, I had tea with Peter Merholz, who has been involved in the industry since its very early stages. We had a great conversation about what it was like when the industry started to come together and where he thinks it&amp;rsquo;s headed. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listen to the podcast at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.teawithteresa.com/2009/03/history-evolution-of-user-experience.html&#34;&gt;Tea with Theresa&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/jeepu/statuses/1312159478&#34;&gt;@jeepu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.teawithteresa.com/2009/03/history-evolution-of-user-experience.html&#34;&gt;http://www.teawithteresa.com/2009/03/history-evolution-of-user-experience.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>