<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Creativity on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/creativity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Creativity on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/creativity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>99u Master Class: Irene Au on Mindfulness Techniques to Make You a Better Creative</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/99u-master-class-irene-au-mindfulness-techniques-make-you-better-creative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/99u-master-class-irene-au-mindfulness-techniques-make-you-better-creative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ireneau.com/&#34;&gt;Irene Au&lt;/a&gt; was a design and user experience leader at Google, Yahoo, and Netscape. She&amp;rsquo;s now a partner at Khosla Ventures, and has been focussing on her yoga instruction in the past few years. She led a session at the 99u Conference to discuss mindfulness mediation techniques for creatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au talked about different methods of mindfulness mediation practice. Mindfulness, in general, is a state of awareness or consciousness of the present moment. Mindfulness mediation comes from the Buddhist practice of controlling the mind, and uses awareness of the present as a form of meditation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Au talked about benefits of mindfulness practice, including references to scientific research, use in treating psychological issues. Mindfulness practice is also becoming more of a secular, mainstream topic appearing in the media frequently, including a &lt;a href=&#34;http://time.com/1556/the-mindful-revolution/&#34;&gt;Time Magazine feature&lt;/a&gt; on mindfulness. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jon_Kabat-Zinn&#34;&gt;Jon Kabat-Zinn&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; work on bringing mindfulness meditation to non-Buddhists for its benefits in stress reduction is only one example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mindfulness meditation is an element that Au uses in her yoga practice and suggests that we might also be able to practice mindfulness practices to improve our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She introduced us to the different techniques of mindfulness mediation. In focussed attention meditation, one can choose to focus attention on one thing. In open monitoring meditation, one may allow the mind to wander and observe without reacting or judging. In both, the focus and awareness of breath and body, bring the mind back to the present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience participated in several mindfulness activities. The first exercise was a warm up. We all practiced yoga breathing with eyes closed, while being aware of our presence in our seats in the room and building. We used counting with our breath to bring awareness back to the room when we wandered. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She pointed out that sitting meditation can help us in daily life in several ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enhances single to noise contrast&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Recover from distraction&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Improve cognitive capacities (decision making, perspective taking, memory)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Emotion stabilization&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second activity was the one that interested me most. Au is a journal writer, and she talked about how she has used journal writing most of her life. I liked the idea of daily journal writing to help get perspective. I once tried morning journaling after starting to read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Artists-Way-Julia-Cameron/dp/1585421464&#34;&gt;The Artists Way&lt;/a&gt; a long time ago, but didn&amp;rsquo;t get through that book, and that sort of journaling felt forced to me. Using journaling to just record and observe the thoughts and activities of the day feels more natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience was asked to spend several minutes writing in our journals, finishing each of these sentences. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;When I feel understood, I&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m at my best, I&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;What I really care about is&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we spent the next few minutes taking turns telling the person sitting next to us what we wrote about to complete the first sentence. That listener would then take a few minutes to repeat back to the teller what they heard. This was a fantastic exercise in listening, and reminds me of the practice of reflecting back to someone what they hear when expressing needs, something I learned from Marshall Rosenberg&amp;rsquo;s book on &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nonviolent_Communication&#34;&gt;Nonviolent Communication&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this practice of intently listening to someone and repeating back is something that can be very difficult to become comfortable with, but the reward is invaluable. It is a gift, and is something I highly recommend doing with your partner/spouse or children. We do this in my family, and I can&amp;rsquo;t tell you how much it has helped during difficult times. Doing it in the work day can be very valuable in helping practice empathy and is something that I&amp;rsquo;m sure a lot of people who do research are already comfortable with. I recommend Rosenberg&amp;rsquo;s book because of this, if you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable getting uncomfortable. It&amp;rsquo;s not easy to use his communication framework, believe me, but it helps to be given a language and framework for doing the work of listening and reflecting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final exercise in focussed attention mindfulness involved us each taking a piece of chocolate to fully experience mindfully. We took our time holding, touching, smelling and tasting the chocolate and observing our thoughts during the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from liking the chocolate and the discussion of the emotional and spiritual benefits of mindfulness meditation, I&amp;rsquo;m really intrigued by the idea of using mindfulness practice to help in your work life. I&amp;rsquo;ve dabbled in mindfulness meditation only briefly in my life, introduced to the idea when I was younger and interested in Thich Nhat Hanh&amp;rsquo;s books. I was maybe too restless and unready at that time to meditate, even while walking or washing dishes, and have gravitated to more physical ways to connect mind and body. But I&amp;rsquo;m finding that the possibilities have changed with everything as I&amp;rsquo;ve matured. Sure it took me only a few decades to feel that, but better late than never. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a sense of connection in journaling when writing with your own hand that has the same feeling of connectedness I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten in occasionally doing yoga in the past and in doing martial arts now. I like that hand writing feels more doable, but I feel like I need something like the structure of those prompts (the starter sentences above) to give me a framework for starting. Motivation is easy, but sustainable practice is hard. Quitting is easy. I like some of the ideas in Austin Kleon&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://austinkleon.com/show-your-work/&#34;&gt;Show Your Work&lt;/a&gt; for making yourself capture what you&amp;rsquo;re working on daily. Google tells me a lot of people have come up with these &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=journaling+prompts&#34;&gt;creative writing prompts for inspiration&lt;/a&gt;, so I&amp;rsquo;m also exploring that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some ideas Au suggested to apply when journaling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Collect list of prompts, randomly pick one daily&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When a salient emotion occurs, write&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Begin each day by tapping core values&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use as a &amp;ldquo;brain dump&amp;rdquo; and clarifier&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suspect that I&amp;rsquo;ll spend some time figuring out how to integrate what I took away from Irene&amp;rsquo;s talk into my daily practice. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also to check out: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ted.com/talks/amy_cuddy_your_body_language_shapes_who_you_are&#34;&gt;Amy Cuddy&amp;rsquo;s TED talk on posture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://750words.com/&#34;&gt;750 Words&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/get-some-headspace/id493145008&#34;&gt;Headspace meditation app for iPhone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jack White on Constraints</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/jack-white-constraints/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/jack-white-constraints/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;t14&#34;&gt;Telling yourself, “Oh, you have all the time in the world, you have all the money in the world, you have all the colors in the palette you want, anything you want,” I mean, that just kills creativity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#8212;Jack White&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was going through the parts I had highlighted in my Kindle version of Austin Kleon&#39;s book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.austinkleon.com/steal/&#34;&gt;Steal Like An Artist,&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and I keep thinking of how much I like this quote from musician Jack White, talking about using constraints to stay creative. I think about how much constraints and removal of the unnecessary makes a difference in helping flow in the tools I use as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quote was actually taken from an interview of White that you can watch in the documentary &lt;em&gt;Under Great White Northern Lights&lt;/em&gt;. There&#39;s an extended except in the Makin&#39; Ads blog &lt;a href=&#34;http://makinads.blogspot.com/2010/04/jack-white-on-creativity.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/fDl-if5Du70?t=1m26s&#34;&gt;watch a video clip on YouTube here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bruce Springsteen on Creativity</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/bruce-springsteen-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/bruce-springsteen-creativity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;I&#39;d like to talk about the one thing that&#39;s been consistent over the years—the genesis and power of creativity. ... It’s all about how you’re putting what you do together. The elements you’re using don’t matter. Purity of human expression and experience is not confined to guitars, to tubes, to turntables, to microchips. There’s no right way, no pure way of doing it—there’s just doing it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Bruce Springsteen&#39;s inspiring &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/2012/03/16/148778665/bruce-springsteens-sxsw-2012-keynote-speech&#34;&gt;2012 SXSW Keynote Speech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/2012/03/16/148778665/bruce-springsteens-sxsw-2012-keynote-speech&#34;&gt;http://www.npr.org/2012/03/16/148778665/bruce-springsteens-sxsw-2012-keynote-speech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Creative People Need to Be Eccentric</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/why-creative-people-need-be-eccentric/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/why-creative-people-need-be-eccentric/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://the99percent.com/tips/7021/Why-Creative-People-Need-to-Be-Eccentric&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2503&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4dc94996a685e_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love these two posts by Mark McGuiness on the 99% on why &lt;a href=&#34;http://the99percent.com/tips/7021/Why-Creative-People-Need-to-Be-Eccentric&#34;&gt;eccentricity&lt;/a&gt; and how &lt;a href=&#34;http://the99percent.com/tips/7007/How-Mundane-Routines-Produce-Creative-Magic&#34;&gt;daily routine&lt;/a&gt; helps trigger creativity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He points out three characteristics of a hypnotic trigger:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Uniqueness - it should be something (or a combination of things) you don&#39;t associate with other activities, otherwise the effect will be diluted.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emotional intensity - the kind you experience when you&#39;re really immersed in creative work.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repetition - the more times you experience the unique trigger in association with the emotions, the stronger the association becomes.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I live by daily routines, but I also associate that with my need to feel balanced and in control of my time and the living and working space around me. I also have a tendency to be impulsive or to dive very deeply into activities, so routine acts both as clock and trigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some excellent anecdotes about the routines of famous creatives. I find myself really intrigued by the more eccentric ones, like those of Victor Hugo and especially that of Orhan Pamuk. Pamuk&#39;s act of re-creating his &amp;quot;walk to work&amp;quot; trigger is pretty ingenious. &lt;a href=&#34;http://the99percent.com/tips/7021/Why-Creative-People-Need-to-Be-Eccentric&#34;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://the99percent.com/tips/7021/Why-Creative-People-Need-to-Be-Eccentric&#34;&gt;http://the99percent.com/tips/7021/Why-Creative-People-Need-to-Be-Eccentric&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 10% Myth and How to Put Your Creative Process on Autopilot</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/10-myth-and-how-put-your-creative-process-autopilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/10-myth-and-how-put-your-creative-process-autopilot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;What if we could eliminate noise and give our brains space to do harder work or process different things?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Costanza Principle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a particularly funny episode of Seinfeld titled &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Abstinence&#34;&gt;The Abstinence&lt;/a&gt;,&#34; where George abstains from sex because his girlfriend has Mono, and strange things begin to happen to the serial underachiever. He appears to utilize more of his brain and becomes mentally sharp. He remembers where he left things years ago. He starts to read and understands math. He becomes more intelligent. Of course he ruined it all in a weak moment with a comely waitress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That comedy sketch summarizes a simple and persistent myth that has stuck for years&amp;#8212;that we use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=do-we-really-use-only-10&#34;&gt;only 10% of our brain&lt;/a&gt;. That number may have more to do with 10 percent of our potential or capacity rather than 10% of brain use. But the idea sticks, I think, because of that hopeful notion of doing more than one thinks she is capable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought of the Seinfeld sketch while I was reading Barry Schwartz&#39;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Paradox_of_Choice&#34;&gt;The Paradox of Choice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and it put me on a separate train of thought about creativity and productivity. What if we could take the idea of eliminating noise in order to give our brains space to focus, to do harder work, or to process different things? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schwartz says that in effect we do this every day when we go into autopilot to take care of our morning routines&amp;#8212;bathing, shaving, brushing, etc&amp;#8212;because we don&#39;t need or want to waste time and effort considering choices all the time. So it started me wondering how this idea translates to the work I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The are two ways I thought this idea could have some benefit for me: first as a tool for freeing my mind in everyday creative activity, and second, as a tool for users of the things I design not to feel overwhelmed with choice and decision making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started listing how I might make this idea work in each of those contexts. For now, I&#39;m going to focus on how this relates to my creative process, and what I try to do that now seems related to this idea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Processes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I learn and use a technique or process, I write about it and when necessary turn it into a set of tools that support the process. I record the steps in the system for re-doing without having to re-learn. I modify what I learn and borrow from others when what I&#39;ve gleaned limits my ability to get things done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve done this over and over with all of the information architecture and interaction design practices that I employ. I just stand on the shoulders of those who pioneer and test these processes, making use of what makes sense, and discarding aspects as needed. This is one of the aspects of agencies that I think is really great. Processes are so well defined for those inside and outside the agency to understand that it becomes part of the common language of the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tool Sets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find toolsets and frameworks for nearly everything I do, or I create them when I can&#39;t find them. They add rigor to my process, and allow me to re-use without thought. I break out of the frameworks as necessary, but start with a sense of the complete framework, even if only in concept, and expand to satisfy my use cases and needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things I learned early in my career from Perl programmers I worked with is that code libraries help you to be lazy. Laziness can be a virtue if it means you don&#39;t want to sweat the routine and small things so you can focus on the bigger ideas. Designers also do this with design pattern libraries and component libraries. I don&#39;t limit myself to only what libraries provide, but I do exploit them when they&#39;re useful and save me time and effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;So what does this buy you?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think to sum up, this all comes back to the idea of freeing your mind from the tyranny of small decisions, so you can focus on the bigger, more intellectual or creative ones. A lot of this isn&#39;t exactly auto-pilot, or may not feel that way in the beginning. But after years of developing and evolving these things, I feel some of the routines or toolsets I&#39;ve created have become a part of my vocabulary. The only problem is maybe that other things compete for the open space I create. I have more to say about that, and the issue of focus, but will leave that to another entry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll end as I often do with a question. What kinds of things are you doing to put your work life on autopilot?&lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Buxton on How to Keep Innovating</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/bill-buxton-how-keep-innovating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/bill-buxton-how-keep-innovating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In BusinessWeek, Bill Buxton discusses &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessweek.com/innovate/content/feb2009/id20090218_337947.htm&#34;&gt;how to keep innovating&lt;/a&gt;, with the main idea being that you can continue to cultivate creativity and innovation by finding new things that you have a passion for. He suggests that when you get good enough at a thing, you should find something else to be passionate about, and commit and throw yourself into learning how to do it. You&#39;ll be bad at it at first, but the experience of learning something new, no matter how bad you are at it at first, may affect your creativity in positive ways that you won&#39;t realize until you experience it. In some cases, they may inform what you are already expert at, and in others lead you in entirely new and surprising directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discussion reminds me of Paula Scher&#39;s talk focussing on &lt;a href=&#34;paula-scher-gets-serious-ted.html&#34;&gt;serious versus solemn design&lt;/a&gt; at TED. Scher spoke about the different times in her career where she was able to be most innovative in her craft, and the thing that was common in each case was that she was doing something new--something she didn&#39;t know much about when she started that particular project. The fact that one has no reference point or bearing can lead to innovative thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the same argument Buxton is making. I think Buxton is saying that the continued pursuit of new endeavors itself, is what can help cultivate one&#39;s creativity and create the pre-conditions for innovation. I&#39;m sure a lot of people who take up new hobbies and have the continuing need to learn see the obvious in this. This is one of the reasons I feel at home in a city where it is easy for me to start investigating and learning something new all the time. Being in a city isn&#39;t necessary, per se, but being able to get inspired and start doing something new is a hell of a lot easier for me here. This coupled with the fact that my wife and I homeschool our 8 year old son, which has lead me to dive deep on countless topics and project that I would never have held my interest in the past. If you read my personal blog, you know about my forays into toy making, game design, character creation and storytelling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, the story is not new, but is a reminder for me that being well-rounded and having many interests is a good thing. In fact it&#39;s one of the top criteria I&#39;ve used when participating in the hiring of people.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessweek.com/innovate/content/feb2009/id20090218_337947.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.businessweek.com/innovate/content/feb2009/id20090218_337947.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative 30</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/creative-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/creative-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.creative30.net/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1389&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt490613e5f251a_0.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;VICE, Volvo, The Independent and Yahoo! have teamed up on a project called Creative 30 which aims to find and celebrate thirty of Britain’s most promising young creative people. Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.creative30.net/&#34;&gt;video interviews&lt;/a&gt; that take a peek into the lives and process of the selected designers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.creative30.net/&#34;&gt;http://www.creative30.net/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>