<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meetings on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/meetings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meetings on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/meetings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Pear Note: Note taking utility for Mac</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/pear-note-note-taking-utility-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/pear-note-note-taking-utility-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.usefulfruit.com/pearnote/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2736&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt52300510755a6_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.usefulfruit.com/pearnote/&#34;&gt;Pear Note&lt;/a&gt; from Useful Fruit Software is a powerful note-taking tool for Mac OS X. The application integrates text notes with audio and video you can record from interview sessions, meetings, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notes are time-marked to the video and slides that are being viewed during the recording, so you can click text from your notes, and the app will jump to that time in the recording so you can watch the video or see the slide that went with the note. While you&#39;re playing back, text notes are highlighted as you follow along with audio/video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty amazing looking tool to supplement your user research toolbox, and fills a well defined need for researchers, but is just as useful for meetings, conference calls, remote design reviews, and classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More info in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pear-note/id411827890?mt=12&#34;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt; or at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.usefulfruit.com/pearnote/&#34;&gt;Pear Note site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.usefulfruit.com/pearnote/&#34;&gt;http://www.usefulfruit.com/pearnote/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cohdoo Highlight: Voice recording iPhone app</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/cohdoo-highlight-voice-recording-iphone-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/cohdoo-highlight-voice-recording-iphone-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cohdoo.com/highlight.php&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2677&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt522fad14ed298_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cohdoo, the company that makes the iPhone whiteboard magnets that I&amp;rsquo;ve posted about have just released &lt;a href=&#34;http://cohdoo.com/highlight.php&#34;&gt;Highlight&lt;/a&gt; a nice iPhone app for voice recordings. It&amp;rsquo;s aimed at helping user researchers record interviews, and is just as useful for recording meetings and conference talks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start new sessions, press the New Recording button, and during the recording you can tap the huge green Mark Highlight button, which I could see being useful for marking new questions during interviews, or marking sections of conference talks. Afterwards during playback, you can press a marker to jump to it, and swipe a marker to label it. You can then sync and access your recordings via iTunes, or email the audio recordings.  Really nice app. I can see myself using this for more than just user research recordings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cohdoo-highlight/id422247746?mt=8&amp;amp;ls=1&#34;&gt;More info in the App Store&lt;/a&gt; or on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cohdoo.com/highlight.php&#34;&gt;Highlight&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cohdoo.com/highlight.php&#34;&gt;http://cohdoo.com/highlight.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Whiteboarding with Twiddla</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/team-whiteboarding-twiddla/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/team-whiteboarding-twiddla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twiddla.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/twiddla-1.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twiddla.com/&#34;&gt;Twiddla&lt;/a&gt; is an easy to use collaborative whiteboard service, but it&amp;rsquo;s really got the potential to be much more. The whiteboard lets you mark up websites and graphics, and even use a drag-drop library of interface elements for working on interface concepts collaboratively. You communicate with others in the meeting with the chat window, and you can also use built in audio-conferencing capabilities. Very impressive, and free. Would make sense for there to be options for private meetings as well as embedding the whiteboard into your CMS or intranet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just gave it a try and the images they&amp;rsquo;ve provided are very restrictive. They&amp;rsquo;re basically just graphics you drag in, but they can&amp;rsquo;t be scaled outside of their original dimensions properly since they&amp;rsquo;re bitmaps. It&amp;rsquo;s also not a true prototyping environment like Balsamiq or iPlotz, since there are no properties for the elements. The best you can do is draw or even upload your own bitmap elements. It&amp;rsquo;s truly only a whiteboard. That said, the drawing capabilities are decent.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give it a try, click the Twiddla button: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twiddla.com/New.aspx?title=&#34; title=&#34;Twiddle this page!&#34; onclick=&#34;this.href+=document.title;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.twiddla.com/images/buttons/twiddle_this_100x20.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Twiddle this page!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twiddla.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.twiddla.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>