<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Entrepreneurs on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/entrepreneurs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Entrepreneurs on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/entrepreneurs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Build It With Me Connects App Designers and Builders</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/build-it-me-connects-app-designers-and-builders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/build-it-me-connects-app-designers-and-builders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.builditwith.me/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2221&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4b2118e56a283_large_0.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build It With Me is a free site that connects like-minded designers &amp;amp; developers with the same goal: create cool &amp;amp; useful apps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Getting funding for your app idea is hard and often unrealistic. Most of the time you may just need to connect with a partner who has a skill set you lack to finish off your app. This is where Build It With Me is comes in, connecting you to those people. Skip the funding. Build It With Me will help you bootstrap your ideas into actual apps.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.builditwith.me/&#34;&gt;Check it.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.builditwith.me/&#34;&gt;http://www.builditwith.me/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caterina Fake on why working hard is overrated</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/caterina-fake-why-working-hard-overrated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/caterina-fake-why-working-hard-overrated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caterina.net/archive/001196.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1902&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4ac372308eb1f.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Caterina Fake, founder of Flickr and Hunch, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caterina.net/archive/001196.html&#34;&gt;talks about why working hard isn&amp;rsquo;t as important as working on the right things&lt;/a&gt;. Or as I once heard on a cartoon as a kid&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;you have to work smarter not harder.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much more important than working hard is knowing how to find the right thing to work on. Paying attention to what is going on in the world. Seeing patterns. Seeing things as they are rather than how you want them to be. Being able to read what people want. Putting yourself in the right place where information is flowing freely and interesting new juxtapositions can be seen. But you can save yourself a lot of time by working on the right thing. Working hard, even, if that&amp;rsquo;s what you like to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved that paragraph. I also loved the anecdote about Watson and Crick, the scientists who discovered the structure of DNA, and how their discoveries didn&amp;rsquo;t come from hard work, as much as from being in the world thinking, experiencing, allowing ideas to happen. I think there&amp;rsquo;s a valuable nugget in there to product developers about that space that&amp;rsquo;s sometimes needed for creativity that isn&amp;rsquo;t valued enough and understood. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating features to compete, building, and accretion without the relentlessness to say no and focus on the right things isn&amp;rsquo;t the path to quality and excellence. The right path in product development is kind of like finding the right path in life. Asking the hard questions about the things that matter and prioritizing effort around those things &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; hard work. But it&amp;rsquo;s not working hard on the wrong problems, for the sake of working or existing. It&amp;rsquo;s defining what is meaningful and pursuing those thing with fervor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/1951-so-often-people-are-working-hard-at-the-wrong&#34;&gt;37signals&lt;/a&gt; for the link. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caterina.net/archive/001196.html&#34;&gt;Read more at Caterina.net&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caterina.net/archive/001196.html&#34;&gt;http://www.caterina.net/archive/001196.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iStik Designers Make a Better iPod Holder</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/istik-designers-make-better-ipod-holder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/istik-designers-make-better-ipod-holder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goistik.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/istik.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.core77.com/blog/object_culture/couple_makes_good_with_selfdesigned_ipod_accessory_11504.asp&#34;&gt;Core77 talks&lt;/a&gt; about a couple that makes good with self-designed iPod accessory, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goistik.com/&#34;&gt;iStik&lt;/a&gt;. Great example of designers finding buyers in a market saturated with accessory makers. They stand out because they&amp;rsquo;ve thought of the problem, researched how to make the better mousetrap and deliver a product that sells the story of sticking your nano wherever you want when you work out. They&amp;rsquo;ve made $50K in 6 months. Excellent stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goistik.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.goistik.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>