<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Collaboration on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/collaboration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Collaboration on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/collaboration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Frontify: Design review, documentation, and specification app</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/frontify-design-review-documentation-and-specification-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/frontify-design-review-documentation-and-specification-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://frontify.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2850&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt5238f10c9c93d_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://frontify.com/&#34;&gt;Frontify&lt;/a&gt; looks like an interesting SaaS product for design teams. It provides collaborative features for getting design feedback, creating specifications, documentation and style guides, and linking pages together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commenting and linking features are what you&#39;d expect, but what I was really impressed with are the measures, colors, and typography tools for generating style guides. Very nicely done. There are additional capabilities for code export &amp;amp; integration with their API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://frontify.com/&#34;&gt;http://frontify.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call Recorder for Skype</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/call-recorder-skype/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/call-recorder-skype/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ecamm.com/mac/callrecorder/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2742&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt5230115bec53c_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;ecamm&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ecamm.com/mac/callrecorder/&#34;&gt;Call Recorder for Mac&lt;/a&gt; captures audio and video to save Skype calls as QuickTime movies. Useful for user interviews or screensharing sessions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/vanderwal&#34;&gt;Thomas @vanderwal&lt;/a&gt; for the tip&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ecamm.com/mac/callrecorder/&#34;&gt;http://www.ecamm.com/mac/callrecorder/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPEVO Ziggi Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/ipevo-ziggi-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/ipevo-ziggi-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/tools/external/ipevoziggi1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Camera attached to computer&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever done the dance of holding a sketch up to your computer&amp;rsquo;s webcam or taken pictures of them with your iPhone to email to yourself or to colleagues? I&amp;rsquo;ve done that sort of thing for all of the years that I&amp;rsquo;ve worked remotely on design and development teams, because scanners get tired real fast. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frustrated with this process, I had largely given up, until a few months ago when I was looking for tools to share work on paper between students and teachers. I stumbled upon the $89 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipevo.com/prods/IPEVO_Ziggi_USB_Document_Camera&#34;&gt;IPEVO Ziggi USB Document Camera&lt;/a&gt; and have been evaluating it for a few months now as a tool for design collaboration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been finding it easy to use for both shooting sketches for sharing in other apps, and for capturing and reviewing sketches with remote users using a screen-sharing tool like Skype. I now also believe it could be useful for other tasks including video capture for usability testing on mobile devices, and even presentations like one would do with an old school overhead projector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The compact camera folds down and fits in a small bag. It comes with a posable arm to adjust the camera height, a rotatable camera head, an anti-glare shield, and the P2V software is used to display the video on your screen or to a projector when in fullscreen mode. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera includes buttons to adjust exposure, a focus button, and a switch to set autofocus on or off. These functions can also be controlled via the software interface. The software additionally provides a focussed mode for capture, a thumbnail view for review, and the fullscreen view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/tools/external/ipevoziggi2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Camera controls&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a closeup of the camera with the foldable anti-glare shield which can be used when capturing back lit devices like a smartphone or tablet screen. If you were to record an iOS device screen, you would keep this attached. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/tools/external/ipevoziggi3.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a low-resolution video I took of me sketching that you may have seen in a presentation I gave. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty low quality because of the movement and video compression since I used it in a presentation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/51043154?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;badge=0&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;419&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/51043154&#34;&gt;Sketch Basics&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/konigi&#34;&gt;konigi&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera itself has a 2.0-megapixel CMOS sensor with auto-focus and is capable of 30 fps live video capture (at 640 x 480). Still shots can be taken up to 12.2&amp;rdquo; x 9.1&amp;rdquo; (310 x 230mm) and offer resolutions up to 1600px x 1200px.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use the camera as an input for third party software like Skype or Google Talk, although you&amp;rsquo;ll lose some capture capabilities. If you&amp;rsquo;re capturing a test session you&amp;rsquo;re most likely want to screen capture the session with another app like Silverback or Screenflow. I&amp;rsquo;m also using the new Evernote page capture feature a lot with the Moleskine, but could see this device being a better alternative at a desktop. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;rsquo;m really pleased to have this as one of the few tools in my design arsenal. There are few that stay, but this one is turning out to be as useful as I&amp;rsquo;d hope it to be with little fuss. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipevo.com/prods/IPEVO_Ziggi_USB_Document_Camera&#34;&gt;http://www.ipevo.com/prods/IPEVO_Ziggi_USB_Document_Camera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draftboard: Design Review Tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/draftboard-design-review-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/draftboard-design-review-tool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.draftboardapp.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2809&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt52313b78d79c6_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.draftboardapp.com/&#34;&gt;Draftboard&lt;/a&gt; is a wireframe and visual design review web app for capturing design reviews of your work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.draftboardapp.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.draftboardapp.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A wireframe kit for Google Drawings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/wireframe-kit-google-drawings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/wireframe-kit-google-drawings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mortenjust.com/2010/04/19/a-wireframe-kit-for-google-drawings/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2749&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt52303e1983dc0_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Morten Just created &lt;a href=&#34;http://mortenjust.com/2010/04/19/a-wireframe-kit-for-google-drawings/&#34;&gt;wireframe templates using the new drawing tools available for Google Docs&lt;/a&gt;. The illustration tools in Docs gives you basic shapes you need to create UI elements that can be combined and grouped to create components. The biggest advantage is that since it&amp;rsquo;s document authoring in the Docs cloud, you can do collaborative editing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For what it&#39;s worth, I don&#39;t think this is ideal, but it is interesting because of the online collaboration. Like OmniGraffle, it wasn&#39;t created for wireframing, but clever designers will always find a way to make tools useful for our needs, beyond what they were intended for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mortenjust.com/2010/04/19/a-wireframe-kit-for-google-drawings/&#34;&gt;http://mortenjust.com/2010/04/19/a-wireframe-kit-for-google-drawings/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Whiteboarding with Twiddla</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/team-whiteboarding-twiddla/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/team-whiteboarding-twiddla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twiddla.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/twiddla-1.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twiddla.com/&#34;&gt;Twiddla&lt;/a&gt; is an easy to use collaborative whiteboard service, but it&amp;rsquo;s really got the potential to be much more. The whiteboard lets you mark up websites and graphics, and even use a drag-drop library of interface elements for working on interface concepts collaboratively. You communicate with others in the meeting with the chat window, and you can also use built in audio-conferencing capabilities. Very impressive, and free. Would make sense for there to be options for private meetings as well as embedding the whiteboard into your CMS or intranet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just gave it a try and the images they&amp;rsquo;ve provided are very restrictive. They&amp;rsquo;re basically just graphics you drag in, but they can&amp;rsquo;t be scaled outside of their original dimensions properly since they&amp;rsquo;re bitmaps. It&amp;rsquo;s also not a true prototyping environment like Balsamiq or iPlotz, since there are no properties for the elements. The best you can do is draw or even upload your own bitmap elements. It&amp;rsquo;s truly only a whiteboard. That said, the drawing capabilities are decent.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give it a try, click the Twiddla button: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twiddla.com/New.aspx?title=&#34; title=&#34;Twiddle this page!&#34; onclick=&#34;this.href+=document.title;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.twiddla.com/images/buttons/twiddle_this_100x20.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Twiddle this page!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twiddla.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.twiddla.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Tool Design: Design by Sketching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/software-tool-design-design-sketching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/software-tool-design-design-sketching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.simple-talk.com/dotnet/.net-tools/software-tool-design-design-by-sketching/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/design-by-sketching.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.simple-talk.com/dotnet/.net-tools/software-tool-design-design-by-sketching/&#34;&gt;second part of Stephen Chambers&amp;rsquo; series&lt;/a&gt; on designing the ANTS Profiler tool, a .NET code profiler, discusses how a team leader challenged a group to really work collaboratively on developing the concept for the tool&amp;rsquo;s interface by taking away computers and requiring that the team work with only paper, whiteboards, pencils, and markers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James, the team leader had just read Bill Buxton&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Sketching the User Experience&lt;/em&gt; and wanted to try to get his engineers to rally around the idea that everyone can participate in this ideation phase, and no one needed any specific skill to propose and sketch ideas. After some initial discomfort, a few people got the ball rolling, and then as the ideas started flowing, constraints and possibilities were clarified, revelations ensued, and useful design directions manifested themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen writes that the 2 main things he took away from the exercise were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s easy to generate and explore new ideas when everyone is sitting around a table with a pencil and sketchbook to hand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don’t have to second guess what someone is thinking. We often just said “Don’t try and tell me – show me.” Two minutes later you had the idea on paper, concrete and unambiguous. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a wonderful example of how to get everyone (especially engineers!) on your team involved in concrete idea generation. There&amp;rsquo;s no need to fear failure or criticism of ideas because sketches are disposable, but by having the ideas shown rather than just discussed, concepts become inherently clear rather and can be quickly refined or discarded with much less lost time when compared to first doing the work in software. The method used here might be a little extreme&amp;ndash;taking all the computers out of the room for the duration of the exercise&amp;ndash;but the benefits are clear, given the observations in Stephen&amp;rsquo;s telling of the results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.simple-talk.com/dotnet/.net-tools/software-tool-design-design-by-sketching/&#34;&gt;http://www.simple-talk.com/dotnet/.net-tools/software-tool-design-design-by-sketching/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protonotes: HTML prototyping collaboration tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/protonotes-html-prototyping-collaboration-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/protonotes-html-prototyping-collaboration-tool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.protonotes.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2842&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt523347325c8d2_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.protonotes.com/&#34;&gt;Protonotes&lt;/a&gt; provides a service to allow teams to add notes directly onto html prototypes. Check out the video below for a demo. After you register the confirmation email provides a few snippets of javascript to put into your html prototypes to insert a menubar over the top of your site. The menubar provides controls for creating notes and can be configured to be unobtrusive.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/JSYMhdWgr_M&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/JSYMhdWgr_M&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.protonotes.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.protonotes.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sumopaint.com beta - Image Editing in the Browser</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/sumopaintcom-beta-image-editing-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/sumopaintcom-beta-image-editing-browser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sumopaint.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1383&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt48f4b57bab96e_0.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sumopaint.com/&#34;&gt;Sumopaint&lt;/a&gt;, by Snap Group Ltd is looking to be a really slick Flash-based online graphics creation and editing tool. It has a very complete list of functionalities with shapes, brushes, layers, text editing, filters, and many of the features you&amp;rsquo;d expect from Photoshop or (ack) GIMP. Users can share images for community editing, create and view versions, and add comments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This looks like it might turn out to be an excellent resource for those looking at doing things like shared whiteboarding and prototyping without the real-time editing. On the surface this appears to be only a Photoshop-like tool, but if you were to leverage the community and versioning features, the possibilities for a flexible tool like this become pretty interesting. Check it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sumopaint.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.sumopaint.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CollabFinder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/collabfinder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/collabfinder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://collabfinder.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1379&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt48ee0702db0cd_0.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;CollabFinder is a new community to find and communicate with other designers and developers with the goal of collaborating on future projects. Great and simple idea that could turn out to be a very useful connector. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://collabfinder.com/&#34;&gt;http://collabfinder.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ProofHQ</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/proofhq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/proofhq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.proofhq.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2847&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt5236118b735c4_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;ProofHQ is a collaborative tool for reviewing creative projects such as photography and graphic design. The tool allows you to upload anything from a PDFs, PSDs, and JPGs to Word and PowerPoint files up to 75 MB. The functionality is a bit like a mashup of Flickr and Skitch. It allows users to annotate, mark up, and comment on the work. The art can be embedded into a web site with the provided embed code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.proofhq.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.proofhq.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backboard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/backboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/backboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://getbackboard.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2752&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt5230460821450_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://getbackboard.com/&#34;&gt;Backboard&lt;/a&gt; is a very simple collaboration service that allows teams to upload images (e.g. schematics, design comps, and screenshots) to a web page and elicit feedback from team members. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://getbackboard.com/&#34;&gt;http://getbackboard.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TextFlow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/textflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/textflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/2527203491/&#34; title=&#34;TextFlow by jibbajabba, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2355/2527203491_f3311cf739_o.png&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; alt=&#34;TextFlow&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.textflow.com/&#34;&gt;TextFlow&lt;/a&gt; is a new parallel document editing application and service that allows multiple users to work on a document simultaneously. The service should appeal to people who use the Track Changes feature of Microsoft Word. TextFlow lets users edit documents, and instantly see the changes suggested. One person can review the changes and apply them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference between this service and something like Google Docs or working in a wiki, is that the changes are indicated visually, rather than having to go through the diff displays in revision history. It&#39;s simple and should be intuitive for users who use Track Changes in Word. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The service is currently in beta, and you can view a screencast demonstration on the TextFlow site.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.textflow.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.textflow.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Denning and Yaholkovsky on Real Collaboration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/denning-and-yaholkovsky-real-collaboration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/denning-and-yaholkovsky-real-collaboration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thomas Van Der Wal Personal provides a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.personalinfocloud.com/2008/04/denning-and-yah.html&#34;&gt;brief synopsis&lt;/a&gt; of &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://portal.acm.org/citation.cfm?doid=1330311.1330316#abstract&#34;&gt;Getting to &#34;we&#34;&lt;/a&gt;&#34;, an article in Communications of the ACM (Volume 51, Issue 4 - April 2008). According to Thomas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Peter Denning and Peter Yaholkovsky break down the tools needed for various knowledge needs into four categories: 1) Information sharing; 2) Coordination; 3) Cooperation; and Collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article apparently discusses the misunderstanding of the term collaboration, and when it is an appropriate practice. There may be some definition of the subtle nuances of the tools for knowledge work here that should be interesting to those involved with social software and km.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.personalinfocloud.com/2008/04/denning-and-yah.html&#34;&gt;http://www.personalinfocloud.com/2008/04/denning-and-yah.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>