<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mp3 Players on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/mp3-players/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mp3 Players on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/mp3-players/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Pacemaker Mobile MP3 DJ Device Gets a GUI Redesign</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/pacemaker-mobile-mp3-dj-device-gets-gui-redesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/pacemaker-mobile-mp3-dj-device-gets-gui-redesign/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pacemaker.net/default.aspx?documentID=294&amp;amp;entryID=10482&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/pacemaker2.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pacemaker, the mobile MP3 DJ device that debuted last year with a 120 GB hard drive, is getting a 2.0 release this spring and offering an additional lower capacity 60 GB hard drive option, and a new user interface. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was enamored with this device and the way they could incorporate most of the possible mixer and track selection controls for 2 deck track mixing into a single, albeit large, handheld device with their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pacemaker.net/device/tutorials/&#34;&gt;original product&lt;/a&gt; UI. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pacemaker.net/default.aspx?documentID=294&amp;amp;entryID=10482&#34;&gt;newly redesigned UI&lt;/a&gt; looks like it made some usability tweaks and subtle improvements. For instance, there&amp;rsquo;s a new scrolling behavior that highlights your alpha headings. Some filtering options look like they&amp;rsquo;d be welcome improvements as well. For those that actually DJ, there are a bunch of new effects in there too it seems. The hardware remeains the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the lower price point and an improved UI, I might actually get one of these. It&amp;rsquo;s still pricey, but over the years my use of 1200s, Trakktor, and Torq have diminished to near nothing. I get by now playing with a DS KORG. I miss DJing, but this may be the toy for me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pacemaker.net/default.aspx?documentID=294&amp;amp;entryID=10482&#34;&gt;http://www.pacemaker.net/default.aspx?documentID=294&amp;entryID=10482&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>