<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>POTD: J.K. Rowlings Plot Spreadsheet for Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/potd-jk-rowlinge28099s-plot-spreadsheet-e28098harry-potter-and-order-phoenixe28099/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/potd-jk-rowlinge28099s-plot-spreadsheet-e28098harry-potter-and-order-phoenixe28099/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slashfilm.com/2010/10/08/potd-jk-rowlings-plot-spreadsheet-for-harry-potter-and-the-order-of-the-phoenix/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1187/5104558387_88ff2b5cd7_o.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slashfilm.com/2010/10/08/potd-jk-rowlings-plot-spreadsheet-for-harry-potter-and-the-order-of-the-phoenix/&#34;&gt;this post on /Film&lt;/a&gt; showing a few artifacts from J.K. Rowling&amp;rsquo;s creative process. Rowling uses spreadsheets she draws by making grid lines on plain paper, creating columns to outline a book&amp;rsquo;s plot along a timeline, with months progressing downward. The initial columns contains a title and blurb about the plot, and further columns contain info about sub-plots. The excerpt below describes this in detail:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rowling outlines each chapter in detail including which month of the school year it takes place in, the title and the plot. All of that seems standard. But it’s the next few columns where things get really good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She keeps track of all the book’s subplots in every chapter and how they are developing in the real world of the book, even if they aren’t mentioned on the page. So, there’s a full column on “The Prophecy” which is the main subplot Harry is worried about throughout the book. Then there’s a column for the romantic subplot, titled “Cho/Ginny” followed by “D.A.” which follows what’s going on with Harry, Ron and Hermione’s resistance group “Dumbledore’s Army,” one called “O of P,” a column about what’s the latest with the “Order of the Phoenix,” a.k.a, the people who believe Voldemort is still alive, then separate columns for Snape (and others, I can’t read Rowlings writing) and the Hagrid and Grawp story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slashfilm.com/2010/10/08/potd-jk-rowlings-plot-spreadsheet-for-harry-potter-and-the-order-of-the-phoenix/&#34;&gt;Read more on /Film.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.subtraction.com/2010/10/21/jk-rowlings-plot-diagrams&#34;&gt;Via +Subtraction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slashfilm.com/2010/10/08/potd-jk-rowlings-plot-spreadsheet-for-harry-potter-and-the-order-of-the-phoenix/&#34;&gt;http://www.slashfilm.com/2010/10/08/potd-jk-rowlings-plot-spreadsheet-for-harry-potter-and-the-order-of-the-phoenix/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content Templates to the Rescue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/content-templates-rescue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/content-templates-rescue/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/content-templates-to-the-rescue/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1813&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4a55ec6a2256d.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Erin Kissane writes about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/content-templates-to-the-rescue/&#34;&gt;using content templates&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; to help speed up the information-collection process, improve consistency across the website, and make the editing process easier and more orderly&amp;rdquo; in A List Apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ideal situation is to have a content strategist, perhaps a technical writer, who can provide the guidance for auditing and organizing information, and add some rigor to the writing process. The absence of a content strategist on a project necessitates at least dedicating one person to this task. Kissane&amp;rsquo;s article shows how to use content templates to provide the framework for preparing each page of content so they may communicate the essential information effectively and consistently. If you have an IA on the project, this can follow from wireframes on new work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/content-templates-to-the-rescue/&#34;&gt;http://www.alistapart.com/articles/content-templates-to-the-rescue/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Microcopy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/writing-microcopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/writing-microcopy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bokardo.com/archives/writing-microcopy/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1807&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4a549df7cbc7a.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Joshua Porter writes about &lt;a href=&#34;http://bokardo.com/archives/writing-microcopy/&#34;&gt;the use of microcopy&lt;/a&gt; to create confidence and alleviate concerns in customers about the actions they take on your site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ironically, the smallest bits of copy, microcopy, can have the biggest impact. &amp;hellip; Microcopy is small yet powerful copy. It’s fast, light, and deadly. It’s a short sentence, a phrase, a few words. A single word. It’s the small copy that has the biggest impact. Don’t judge it on its size…judge it on its effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Porter provides a few detailed examples showing how microcopy helped users entering ecommerce funnels, in one case reducing errors by qualifying an address form, and in another case adding information to assure customers that they don&amp;rsquo;t need a PayPal account to purchase with PayPal. He provides a few more before/after bits of copy for typical registration and ecommerce scenarios as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bokardo.com/archives/writing-microcopy/&#34;&gt;http://bokardo.com/archives/writing-microcopy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Language We Use</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/language-we-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/language-we-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://davemalouf.com/?p=1560&#34;&gt;The language we use&lt;/a&gt;,&#34; David Malouf discusses how ideas about user interaction can become so ingrained in what we are familiar with, that our language begins to reflect that familiarity. That can lead to a natural tendency to explain away interaction without thought to what it means to the design of a thing. In this case a student describes the change of context in a sketch presentation by using the word &#34;click&#34; (as in clicks to go to the next screen). The absent minded use of the word &#34;click&#34; brings with it the connotations of a mouse click, and limits the possible set of interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David makes two great observations here. First, that the way we talk about interaction design is as important as the visual elements of the design solutions we produce. The language we use, and in particular the selection of meaningful words that convey behaviors, and the intellectual content and analysis of our design is a closely bound component of what we&#39;re providing when we do design work. It is productive, therefore, to write about interactions (e.g. in your spec) and deconstruct what you write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second great observation David makes is that there is danger in the use of loaded language when it comes to describing interaction. Words like &#34;click&#34; explicitly point to the use of one type of input behavior, whether it&#39;s a mouse input or finger touch, that carry with it the limitations or constraints of that behavior. The same might be true of using certain conventions or design patterns. The use of a specific, familiar interface element, like a tab for instance, might lead to known but perhaps limiting behavior for a given application, that would hold the designer back from considering better alternatives for the interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This discussion also reminds me of the thread started by Josh Kamler on &lt;a href=&#34;designing-writing.html&#34;&gt;&#34;Designing by Writing.&#34;&lt;/a&gt; It is extremely valuable to engage in writing and discussion about design through deconstruction. Even in the absence of a studio environment, we can learn to analyze what we design by paying particular attention to how we describe what we&#39;ve designed when we write specs and re-reading and deconstructing what we&#39;ve written, and actively engaging in regular critique of our work.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://davemalouf.com/?p=1560&#34;&gt;http://davemalouf.com/?p=1560&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing by Writing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/designing-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/designing-writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love what tiny gigantic has written in this great short &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tinygigantic.com/2009/02/11/designing-by-writing-or-the-non-iterative-design-process/&#34;&gt;post about designing by writing&lt;/a&gt; (or the non-iterative design process). I agree wholeheartedly, although I think of writing as part of design to be accretive and/or iterative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few choice bits from the entry:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;[W]hen someone asks you why you used green, or why you included that crumpled-paper background, or why there’s a bird in the logo, you’re gonna need to know. What’s more, you’re going to need to be able to articulate it in a way that makes them care. I’ve been in graphic design classes in which I’ve asked students presenting their work why they did what they did. And 90% of them have said something like: “because it’s like, I don’t know. It’s like I thought that color looked super good right there. And I like birds.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not enough to make pretty things. You’ve got to be able to talk about them, to present them, to parse their meaning. And the truth of it is that if you can’t articulate what the thing you’re making means, you’re gonna have a helluva time making it mean something to someone else. Which is a problem, because that’s the job. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to write before I do anything related to interaction design. I like to read, gather and summarize loads of user feedback, to talk among my team about ideas we have to solve problems, and then distill it all into statements of the problem, proposals for design concepts, and stories (use cases and scenarios). This is all the intellectual work of design. Where I work now, it happens in a wiki article with users adding paragraph comments, all before I start to sketch. Then it continues to happen when my team annotates sketches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, the point is that the thought process that leads to design is what&#39;s important, and if there is none, then maybe writing can help in that case. Perhaps not everyone needs to write so much as communicate and capture in some way, even if it&#39;s only in discussion and notetalking or what have you.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tinygigantic.com/2009/02/11/designing-by-writing-or-the-non-iterative-design-process/&#34;&gt;http://www.tinygigantic.com/2009/02/11/designing-by-writing-or-the-non-iterative-design-process/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Slow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/going-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/going-slow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/11/23/fashion/23slowblog.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/nytimes-slowblogging.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The New York Times fashion section article, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/11/23/fashion/23slowblog.html&#34;&gt;Blogging at a Snail&amp;rsquo;s Pace&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; discusses slow blogging, a near Ludd-like movement against the practice of posting quick and in high volume. It&amp;rsquo;s like slow food versus fast food. Slow bloggers discard the belief that webloggers need to post often, because the reflectiveness of thought and quality of writing suffer. When comparing the slow versus fast differences, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bgblogging.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Barbara Ganley&lt;/a&gt;, a blogger who writes from Vermont had this to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ms. Ganley, the blogger in Vermont, has a slogan that encapsulates the trend: “Blog to reflect, Tweet to connect.” Blogging, she said, “is that slow place.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a distaste for fast blogging because I watch the fast blogs, and because I&amp;rsquo;m somewhere in between, doing a little of both the fast and terse and the slow and thoughtful. I have found myself posting when there is time, and thinking about each entry as I deconstruct interfaces and visual designs. I once saw a tweet referencing Konigi that was surprised I didn&amp;rsquo;t post more. It&amp;rsquo;s because I try to post more thoughtfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interesting example from the article is &lt;a href=&#34;http://dawdlr.tumblr.com/&#34;&gt;dawdlr&lt;/a&gt;, the rebel twin sister of Twitter. Dawdlr asks the same question essentially, &amp;ldquo;what are you doing, you know, more generally?&amp;rdquo; But the twist is you answer by postcard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/dawdlr.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the idea of dawdler. Email, blogging, etc. has meant that I get and receive a lot fewer letters and postcards from friends and family. Close friends and family know I was passionate about letter writing, and tended to spend as much time crafting the actual letter and envelope as much as I did the writing and selection of the additional contents I&amp;rsquo;d send along. There&amp;rsquo;s something about the time in between replies that makes each letter that much denser and saturated in meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My blogging arc has been somewhat wavy. I started blogging iaslash as a reblogger in 2001 and slowly started doing more and more critique and review there, and then retired from that blog in 2005. Over the course of my personal blog at urlgreyhot, I wrote lengthy essays, but essentially turned it into a microblogging site as I focussed on Konigi. Now, I do something in between the fast and slow. There&amp;rsquo;s no high volume, and neither is there the multi-scroll essay. And I mix in some time to look at and tweak the tools I use in the real world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m trying to be something more like the good, reliable neighborhood restaurant. I don&amp;rsquo;t know. I&amp;rsquo;m just happy you come to visit so I can serve you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/11/23/fashion/23slowblog.html&#34;&gt;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/11/23/fashion/23slowblog.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Pogue on Tech Terms to Avoid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/david-pogue-tech-terms-avoid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/david-pogue-tech-terms-avoid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;David Pogue offers some suggestions the selection of non-jargony words when writing/speaking about technology. Most of these I agree with. Here&#39;s a few: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;* Enable. Who on earth says, &#34;Enable the GPS function&#34;? Only user-manual writers and computer-book authors. Say &#34;Turn on GPS&#34; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* Support. I don&#39;t mean &#34;support&#34; as in &#34;tech support,&#34; although even that term is a corporate creepy cop-out (it means &#34;help line&#34;). No, I mean the verb, as in, &#34;The laptop supports Wi-Fi and Bluetooth.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In no other corner of modern discourse is &#34;support&#34; used that way. I use &#34;has,&#34; &#34;offers&#34; or &#34;works with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/10/16/technology/personaltech/16pogue-email.html?_r=1&amp;amp;8cir&amp;amp;emc=cira1&amp;amp;oref=slogin&#34;&gt;More at NY Times...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/10/16/technology/personaltech/16pogue-email.html?_r=1&amp;amp;8cir&amp;amp;emc=cira1&amp;amp;oref=slogin&#34;&gt;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/10/16/technology/personaltech/16pogue-email.html?_r=1&amp;8cir&amp;emc=cira1&amp;oref=slogin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Economist.com Editorial Style Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/economist-com-editorial-style-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/economist-com-editorial-style-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/research/styleguide/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1353&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt48b81ee6c8c81.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Economist, the magazine and news site, provides access to the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/research/styleguide/&#34;&gt;editorial style guide&lt;/a&gt; that every journalist for the company is given. The book, written by John Grimond, is also available for purchase in the printed book form.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.economist.com/research/styleguide/&#34;&gt;http://www.economist.com/research/styleguide/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>