<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Libraries on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/libraries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Libraries on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/libraries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>NYPL Labs Infomaki: A lightweight usability testing service</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/nypl-labs-infomaki-lightweight-usability-testing-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/nypl-labs-infomaki-lightweight-usability-testing-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://labs.nypl.org/2009/02/16/introducing-infomaki-bite-sized-usability-testing/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/nypl-infomaki.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The New York Public Library Labs has begun testing a &lt;a href=&#34;http://labs.nypl.org/2009/02/16/introducing-infomaki-bite-sized-usability-testing/&#34;&gt;light usability testing system&lt;/a&gt; to supplement their formal tests, inspired by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fivesecondtest.com/&#34;&gt;Five Second Test&lt;/a&gt; method which was devised by Jared Spool and turned into a service by the guys at mayhem(method).  The service, nicknamed Infomaki (info roll?), combines the type of service 5 second test provides, as well as allowing single question surveys for checking on things like simple labeling issues, which you might have tested using card sorting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The test lets you answer only 1 question, or continue answering as you like, which makes the task feel very game like, and reminds me of crowdsourcing apps like Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Mechanical Turk. I love that the types of questions you can ask require simple twitch-like responses, so you can get through a lot very quickly. Here&amp;rsquo;s a bit more from the NYPL Labs site about the project: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has become apparent that we needed a tool in our kit that would allow us to get simple usability questions in front of users with a minimum of fuss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[O]ften, what is needed is just a sanity check– a reassurance to our team that we are on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our design sessions frequently result in debate about which of two words is more compelling or accurate for our users, or whether a particular button is noticeable in a particular location. When we can, we test designs on real people using paper or digital prototypes, but it is impractical to test every day; sitting down with real people is not always as simple as you’d expect, what with the schedules of busy New Yorkers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve used SurveyMonkey in the past for full-fledged traditional surveys, and we’ve also evaluated OptimalSort for online card sorting, and been inspired by the Five Second Test. But none of them were a perfect fit, for reasons including complicated interfaces, inflexible setup, privacy policy hassles, and/or lack of a way to embed a link back to our site when the test is completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, we set out to create our own rapid-testing usability laboratory from scratch, and last Tuesday we launched it, in rough beta form.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having worked on information systems in research libraries, I&amp;rsquo;m always excited to see libraries that are ahead of the curve in terms of technology, and the NYPL never fails to impress. The NYPL Labs is testing the system with a small number of usability questions related to NYPL sites now, so you might get some repeat questions, as I did. It would be great if the system could cookie sessions to ensure that questions aren&amp;rsquo;t repeated. This is a terrific start though. The NYPL Labs plan to release Infomaki as an open source application, which is great news for us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://labs.nypl.org/2009/02/16/introducing-infomaki-bite-sized-usability-testing/&#34;&gt;http://labs.nypl.org/2009/02/16/introducing-infomaki-bite-sized-usability-testing/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>