<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Nick Finck&#39;s Gifts for User Experience Geeks 2011</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/nick-fincks-gifts-user-experience-geeks-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/nick-fincks-gifts-user-experience-geeks-2011/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nickfinck.com/blog/entry/gifts_for_user_experience_geeks_2011/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2547&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4ed3e065c98d9_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for gifts for your team, Nick Finck has once again rounded up a massive list of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nickfinck.com/blog/entry/gifts_for_user_experience_geeks_2011/&#34;&gt;gear for UX geeks&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks, Nick.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nickfinck.com/blog/entry/gifts_for_user_experience_geeks_2011/&#34;&gt;http://www.nickfinck.com/blog/entry/gifts_for_user_experience_geeks_2011/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have a nice day</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/have-nice-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/have-nice-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;Don&#39;t let anyone tell you that the tools you choose are wrong or inappropriate. Find the right design and keep winning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally I&#39;m asked to provide an opinion about a topic that people think I should have some authority to comment on for some reason. That topic, as you might guess, is wireframing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoy pointing people towards good resources, or helping them with a problem using a tool that I&#39;m familiar with. I also love to give my own design resources to peers, or to teach techniques that I think will help people perfect their craft. In the end, I benefit from that exchange the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked to comment on slanted opinions that throw a stake in the ground and tend to confuse and divide the community, I abstain. Navel gazing and defining the damned thing became an uninteresting use of time to me long ago. It took some time immersed in those conversations to know that I have nothing to contribute. I&#39;d rather be making stuff than talking about it. I just say call yourself whatever you like, and do whatever works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interface design tools are as good as you make them. When I started out, I had to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=michael+angeles+visio&#34;&gt;Visio&lt;/a&gt; to communicate UI specs. It wasn&#39;t awesome, but I made it work. Later I found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=michael+angeles+omnigraffle&#34;&gt;Omnigraffle&lt;/a&gt;. It was not designed specifically to enable interface designers, but we made it awesome. We learned how to use it to make our documents communicate design ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are the ones who determine what&#39;s useful for us after immersion in tools. We&#39;ve debated what we want in the ultimate IA tool, we&#39;ve found parallels in other industries and fields of practice and made them our own. We&#39;ve experimented with forward-looking low-fidelity prototyping projects like Denim, and pondered what the right suite of tools are for our work. Some of us built them and shared our work. Some of us are still building them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over years of working and watching others work, I&#39;ve noticed that some attributes are common among the people whose work I admire. The people who are the most effective seem to continue to study their practice, and perfect their craft. After long hours of use, they find the way to flow within any app at their disposal, and become as fast and effective as they can using it. The key is what they do with the app once they&#39;ve become expert at their craft, expert in finding the right design, expert in communicating, and expert in refining. There&#39;s some kind of maker/doer tenacity I see in people, and it doesn&#39;t have to do with any one tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no good or bad tools for finding the right design. Paper prototypes are your thing? Awesome. If you want to sketch and go right to building in HTML? Go for it! I&#39;ve done it. You want to craft gray box schematics in OmniGraffle, Photoshop, or Mockups? Godspeed you wireframer. Maybe I can help you with that. You want to use a tool that generates interactive prototypes? Have a nice day. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the side-taking is useless to me. If you&#39;ve ever interviewed people for an IA or IXD position, you know that beautiful documents and prototypes are meaningless if in the end they don&#39;t demonstrate good problem solving and good design decision making. I don&#39;t care what people use. They can use finger puppets and crayons if they help them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say use whatever makes sense or is at your disposal. Your tools are only as effective as you are at using them to accomplish goals. But don&#39;t let anyone tell you that what you choose is wrong or inappropriate. Find the right design and keep winning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad Stylus Roundup: And the winner is...</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/ipad-stylus-roundup-and-winner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/ipad-stylus-roundup-and-winner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/ipad-styli.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Update: This review was updated after getting the latest version of the Stylus Socks.]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My search for the perfect stylus for sketching on the iPad is over. I&#39;ve tried ever stylus I could get my hands on. The three finalists that earned a space on my desk or pocket in the past year have been the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/iClooly-Stylus-iPhone-Devices-Version/dp/B0032J1NM0&#34;&gt;iClooly&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.etsy.com/shop/shapedad&#34;&gt;Stylus Socks&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.griffintechnology.com/products/stylus&#34;&gt;Griffin Stylus for iPad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Starting off on the wrong foot&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started out initially playing with a few rubber tipped styli and the Pogo Sketch. I had to &lt;a href=&#34;hacking-pogo-stylus-smoother-ipad-sketching.html&#34;&gt;hack the Pogo Sketch&lt;/a&gt; to make it glide, which I still think is an elegant hack. I even contacted the creator about my hack but he didn&#39;t seem to care much for the idea of having a plastic nib inserted in the conductive foam, so I gave up on that. All of the rubber tipped styli created too much friction to be useful, and I didn&#39;t see much promise in the hacks that involved scraping a metal snap across my glass screen. After those experiences I set out to find the perfect stick to take out with me to supplement sketching on paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have 2 main criteria by which I judged the styli.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tip should glide smoothly with as little friction as possible on the screen so that sketching feels natural&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The stick should be long enough to fit comfortably in the hand&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The finalists&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/iClooly-Stylus-iPhone-Devices-Version/dp/B0032J1NM0&#34;&gt;iClooly&lt;/a&gt; ($14.95)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The iClooly uses a small, soft metallic brush tip that seemed to glide the smoothest on the screen, but the metal stick is too thin and short to use comfortably for more than the shortest sketching sessions. I used this consistently for at least 6 months and found it exceptional. I came up with an &lt;a href=&#34;hacking-iclooly-ipad-stylus.html&#34;&gt;inelegant hack&lt;/a&gt; to extend the stick, and that served me well, but who wants to use an ugly hacked stick?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.etsy.com/shop/shapedad&#34;&gt;Stylus Socks II&lt;/a&gt; ($7)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Stylus Socks II sold by Shapedad on Etsy are a clever solution that wraps the end of a plastic KOH-I-NOOR pen holder with a conductive fabric. My initial review of the Stylus Sock was based on my use of a prototype version, but I&#39;ve since received the final version which includes a felt tip under the fabric. The best thing about this stylus is the long stick, which makes it the most usable of the bunch. At only $7 a stylus, this may be the best choice for the budget-conscious sketcher. It works very well and it feels good to support an independent maker. At this price I think this may be the perfect solution for most people. One thing I would like is a heavier version. I may try to purchase a metal pen holder and move the fabric over to that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shapedad is also working on a prototype mouthstick for people who don&#39;t have use of their arms, prompted by a request to make a long stylus for a quadriplegic customer. You can watch his progress &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/shapedad/5265910567/&#34;&gt;in his Flickr photostream&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.griffintechnology.com/products/stylus&#34;&gt;Griffin iPad Stylus&lt;/a&gt; ($18.99)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Someone finally tipped me to the Griffin iPad Stylus in November and I started watching the videos of users on YouTube and was easily convinced that it could be smooth enough. I was skeptical at first, but the rubber tip is surprisingly untacky and glides smoothly with little friction. It&#39;s slightly less smooth than the iClooly, but the biggest positive is that the stick is thicker and resembles the thickness of a pen or marker. It feels great in the hand, and it&#39;s long enough to  reach from my closed index finger and thumb to rest between the two fingers. The clip slides nicely onto the spine of my iPad cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;And the winner is...&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Griffin was my initial winner among the three. Although it&#39;s the most expensive, it works well and I like the metal stick, which I found to be the right thickness. The clip also helps me keep it tethered to the iPad case. After I received the final version of the Stylus Socks II that included the felt tip under the fabric, I found this stylus to be equally as effective as the Griffin, and glides more smoothly. I think they&#39;re both good choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still find sketching on paper superior to sketching on the iPad, but there are definite advantages to immediately having an image to share digitally. iPad sketching has a permanent place in my toolkit, and the Griffin is my weapon of choice. Hopefully this will be the last in this year-long series on finding the right tool for this task.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Touchscreen Stencils</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/touchscreen-stencils/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/touchscreen-stencils/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kickerstudio.com/blog/2008/12/touchscreen-stencils/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2709&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt522fd9c86a764_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dan Saffer of Kicker Studio provides &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kickerstudio.com/blog/2008/12/touchscreen-stencils/&#34;&gt;free touch screen gesture stencils&lt;/a&gt; for OmniGraffle, Visio, Illustrator, and Fireworks. The icons are designed by Rachel Glaves for Saffer&amp;rsquo;s book, &lt;em&gt;Designing Gestural Interfaces&lt;/em&gt;, and depict hands performing common touchscreen gestures like tap, slide, point, drag, pinch, and spread.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kickerstudio.com/blog/2008/12/touchscreen-stencils/&#34;&gt;http://www.kickerstudio.com/blog/2008/12/touchscreen-stencils/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OmniGraffle UX Template Updated (v. 2.2)</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/omnigraffle-ux-template-updated-v-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/omnigraffle-ux-template-updated-v-22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../tools/omnigraffle-ux-template.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1457&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt496fa2c8296bf.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;../tools/omnigraffle-ux-template.html&#34;&gt;UX Template&lt;/a&gt; has been updated (Vers. 2.2) with some minor fixes. The iPhone template was recreated using OmniGraffle drawing tools rather than imported PNGs to shrink file size. Template was converted to flat XML format rather than bundle. Guides cleaned up on all pages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../tools/omnigraffle-ux-template.html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://konigi.com/tools/omnigraffle-ux-template&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/tools/omnigraffle-ux-template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Konigi OG Toolset is Coming</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/konigi-og-toolset-coming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/konigi-og-toolset-coming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-wireframe-draft.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s OmniGraffle, not Original Gangster. It&amp;rsquo;s been over a year since the last update to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://urlgreyhot.com/personal/resources/omnigraffle_wireframe_palette&#34;&gt;OmniGraffle Wireframe Stencils&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m due for a new version after some cleanup and organization into separate stencils to make use of OG5&amp;rsquo;s nice new stencil panel. The above is the current state of my working stencil in all its ugly glory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also in my stencil directory are a bunch of pre-fabricated stencils for the projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on in the past 2 years at Sling and at Traction. So there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of social networking, video controls, and now a growing arsenal of application-oriented controls now that I&amp;rsquo;m helping to define the user experience of Traction Software. You&amp;rsquo;ll hopefully be able to try some of that stuff out in Q1/2 of 2009. And sometime in &amp;lsquo;09 you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to use those stencils as well, as I plan to release them to the public. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be more on the toolset after the new year, so stay tuned. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GUI Prototyping Tools</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/gui-prototyping-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/gui-prototyping-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cunningham &amp;amp; Cunningham have a wiki page listing a great collection of &lt;a href=&#34;http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?GuiPrototypingTools&#34;&gt;prototyping tools&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?GuiPrototypingTools&#34;&gt;http://c2.com/cgi/wiki?GuiPrototypingTools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corporate Ipsum Widget</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/corporate-ipsum-widget/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/corporate-ipsum-widget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.doubleforte.net/widgets/corporate/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1348&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt489cbb2b8087d_0.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you ever get tired of writing sample copy in your design documents, at least be semi-lazy rather than completely lazy. Use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.doubleforte.net/widgets/corporate/&#34;&gt;Corporate Ipsum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.doubleforte.net/widgets/corporate/&#34;&gt;http://www.doubleforte.net/widgets/corporate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silverback: Usability Testing Software for the Mac</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/silverback-usability-testing-software-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/silverback-usability-testing-software-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://silverbackapp.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/silverback.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://silverbackapp.com/&#34;&gt;Silverback&lt;/a&gt; launches to provide UX pros with Macintoshes a simple, inexpensive tool for recording usability test sessions, so you won&amp;rsquo;t have to ever touch another Windows box if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to. (I&amp;rsquo;m kidding. I&amp;rsquo;m sure you will at some point in your life.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silverback provides most of the functionality you need for discount usability. People wanting a full featured tool like Morae won&amp;rsquo;t find their solution here, but if all you want is to organize test sessions, capture audio/video of screen interactions and participants face and voice, then Silverback might be for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process is pretty simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You set up projects and individual test sessions in the tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re ready to start a session, click the &amp;ldquo;Start Session&amp;rdquo; button and Silverback hides, leaving only a menubar icon for when you&amp;rsquo;re ready to stop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During recording you can use your Apple Remote to drop in chapter markers by pressing the + button. Use this for start of each task or to log errors or questions, for instance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re finished with the sesion, click stop from the menubar icon or by pressing Command Option S to open pause/stop dialog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Afterwards you may export the session as a QuickTime file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This application is a bit like using the screen capture tool ScreenFlow, but provides a few nice functionalities that make sense for usability testing. I admit to not doing a lot of time on task reporting in Morae, since my focus has mostly been on qualitative research, but that&amp;rsquo;s one thing you might miss. I also like the post-test surveys built into Morae, but you can easily create a SurveyMonkey survey or something and have the user fill that out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other thing that you won&amp;rsquo;t find are simple video editing tools so you can cut pieces out for your highlight reel when presenting your findings&amp;ndash;if you do that sort of thing. You can easily do that in QuickTime though and stitch together your clips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this tool has the right functionality you&amp;rsquo;d need to do discount testing on the Mac right now. All of the features you need to go the extra mile to make clips presentable are pretty much at your disposal if you have QuickTime Pro or iMovie. For me as a discount usability tester, the best part of this is, I won&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about needing a separate PC to do simple testing. If you bundle this with screensharing tools like those built into iChat or using VNC, you have the makings of a decent Mac UX toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purchase price is only $49.95 and Clearleft are donating 10% of all profits to The Dian Fossey Gorilla Fund. That&amp;rsquo;s two reasons too feel good about making this purchase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://silverbackapp.com/&#34;&gt;http://silverbackapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuum Javascript Ratio Calculator</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/continuum-javascript-ratio-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/continuum-javascript-ratio-calculator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.continuum2.com/js_ratio.php&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/javascript-ratio-calculator.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuum&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.continuum2.com/js_ratio.php&#34;&gt;Javascript Ratio Calculator&lt;/a&gt; is a handy tool you can use to calculate object dimensions based on a ratio you provide. You can do this easily in a graphics tool like Photoshop by setting an image size and resizing, but this can be useful when you just need to pull those dimensions out when planning a project layout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.continuum2.com/js_ratio.php&#34;&gt;http://www.continuum2.com/js_ratio.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>280 Slides - Create &amp; Share Presentations Online</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/280-slides-create-share-presentations-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/280-slides-create-share-presentations-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://280slides.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1316&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt485f99ae85289_0.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://280slides.com/&#34;&gt;280 Slides&lt;/a&gt; is a service that lets you create presentations online in a Keynote-like interface, and then share them, download them to PowerPoint, and present them online.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://280slides.com/&#34;&gt;http://280slides.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Screenshot Utilities You Should Know About</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/6-screenshot-utilities-you-should-know-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/6-screenshot-utilities-you-should-know-about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/2452008412/&#34; title=&#34;Screenshot Utilities You Should Know About by jibbajabba, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2136/2452008412_20087047d9_b.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot Utilities You Should Know About&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use different screen capture utilities depending on the type of screen I&amp;rsquo;m trying to grab. Some are great for a quick and dirty capture of a page I want to send someone. Others are good for annotating an interface I want to post to a web page. And still others are best for archival screen capture or for interfaces with video. Below are the 6 screenshot utilities that Mac users should know about. Don&amp;rsquo;t skip over the first one, because there&amp;rsquo;s a tip in there you might not be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/pro/tips/secretcapture.html&#34;&gt;Apple Screen Capture (Mac)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The built in screen capture tools provided by the Mac allow you to capture full screen (Command-Shift-3) or portions of screens (Command-Shift-4). The PNG images are then placed on your desktop named as Picture-1, etc. Adding Control (Control-Command-Shift-4 or 3) places the screenshot in your clipboard so you can paste right into Photoshop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.skitch.com/&#34;&gt;Skitch (Mac, free)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Skitch is an excellent screen capture tool from Plasque, the makers of Comic Life. The tool provided a twitchy interface for quickly capturing screens, annotating, and uploading to a photo site like Flickr, to it&amp;rsquo;s image portal, or to your FTP directory. This tool is easy to use, and I would argue provides greater flexibility and control than Apple&amp;rsquo;s built in tools in terms of file naming, screen selection, and editing. The only downside of this tool is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t capture complete windows requiring a scroll below the fold. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jingproject.com/&#34;&gt;Jing (Windows and Mac, free)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Jing is a screen capture utility from Techsmith, the makers of PC screen capture  tool SnagIt, and video capture tool Camtasia. The tool copies the simple flow that makes Skitch so succesful, but adds video capture (exported as Flash/SWF) to the mix. As with Skitch, Jing doesn&amp;rsquo;t capture complete scrolling windows. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.screengrab.org/&#34;&gt;Screengrab for Firefox (Windows and Mac, free)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you use Firefox, Screengrab is a handy extension that makes it easy to save or copy (to clipboard) a complete web page, a selection, or only visible portions of the browser window. A small icon is installed in the status bar of your browser, so whenever you see a page you want to grab, you can select your save/copy options, and the directory where you want the PNG to go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tribalmedia.com/bts/SnapWeb/SnapWeb.html&#34;&gt;SnapWeb (Mac, Commercial)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
SnapWeb is a tool I&amp;rsquo;ve used for several years to grab complete pages including content below the fold. This is essentially a slimmed down browser that give you a lot of control over how you&amp;rsquo;re saving files&amp;#8212;you choose from multiple formats, browser dimensions, and file naming preferences. It takes a few more steps to use this tool, but it&amp;rsquo;s proven the most effective at grabbing trickier Flash sites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tastyapps.com/&#34;&gt;Tasty Apps&amp;rsquo; Web Snapper (Mac, Commercial)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Web Snapper is a nice tool you can use with Safari that allows you to queue up screens you want to capture, and either save off one at a time, or using the Web Snapper window. The application allows you to capture pages in their currently viewed state so you can snap DHTML layers or Flash elements. One very nice feature is that you can save off all those screenshots into a multi-paged PDF. Love it. To trigger the capture so you can capture interactive elements on hover, you can invoke the keyboard shortcut Command-Shift-E.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, a supporting cast member&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.johnhaney.com/backdrop/&#34;&gt;Backdrop (Mac, free)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Jing and Skitch will take screencaptures of individual windows (on Skitch, use CMD-Shift-5 and click the window) and put them on a white background. But if you want to capture several windows, you probably want a clean background. Backdrop is an application that simply fills the background with solid white.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://realmacsoftware.com/littlesnapper/&#34;&gt;Little Snapper&lt;/a&gt; from Realmac Software came onto the scene, and now I can recommend this above all the others. Aside from my Firefox Screengrab utility, this one is turning out to be the most useful to me because it lets me organize and tag my screenshots in the desktop software, and save them to the online QuickSnapper service. Excellent piece of software and well worth the $40.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designers Toolbox: OS Form Elements</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/designers-toolbox-os-form-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/designers-toolbox-os-form-elements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.designerstoolbox.com/designresources/elements/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1218&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt480f2be87afed.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Designers Toolbox provides a nice resource for designers looking to create &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.designerstoolbox.com/designresources/elements/&#34;&gt;form elements&lt;/a&gt; in design comps or wireframes. The site displays every type of form element that can be generated by Windows XP IE and Firefox, and Mac OS X Safari and Firefox. Photoshop files can be downloaded for each form element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks, &lt;a href=&#34;http://swissmiss.typepad.com/&#34;&gt;swissmiss&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.designerstoolbox.com/designresources/elements/&#34;&gt;http://www.designerstoolbox.com/designresources/elements/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>