<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Set Top Box on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/set-top-box/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Set Top Box on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/set-top-box/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hillcrest Labs Remote Control</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/hillcrest-labs-remote-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/hillcrest-labs-remote-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;Hillcrest Labs&lt;/a&gt; provides a vision of the pointing and navigating future with their demonstration of Freespace motion-controlled TV remote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/2bw7gPQdTWw&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/2bw7gPQdTWw&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across the video demos of Hillcrest Labs&#39; remote control via &lt;a href=&#34;http://newteevee.com/2008/06/24/hillcrest-remote-flick-wrist-to-flip-channels/&#34;&gt;NewTeevee&lt;/a&gt;. The video above shows a demo at the Consumer Electronics Show last winter, but check the &lt;a href=&#34;http://newteevee.com/2008/06/24/hillcrest-remote-flick-wrist-to-flip-channels/&#34;&gt;NewTeevee&lt;/a&gt; link for the more complete demo of their Freespace motion control technology (sadly they won&#39;t let me embed it here). The demo shows a proof of concept software interface for the TV that allows the user to navigate and access media on their TV/Computer using the &#34;Loop&#34; concept remote control. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prototype TV interface shows the flexibility and scalability of navigation that is possible with a motion controlled remote pointing device equipped with scroll wheel and selection buttons. The software they demo is a zoomable user interface (ZUI) that was created to demonstrate the possibility for navigating a media space on the TV. The remote provides tremor control, so panning motions with the remote don&#39;t produce the jiggle you see on the Wiimote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This demonstrates the great potential and possibilities that ZUIs provide for a simple hierarchical interface like this. Other options could have been explored, but the ZUI provides a very intuitive experience using pointing rather than an up/down/left/right control for navigation, e.g. in your TiVo and Apple TV remotes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technology will be licensed to consumer electronics companies, so we might hopefully see this navigation paradigm on set top boxes in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hillcrestlabs.com/index.php&#34;&gt;http://hillcrestlabs.com/index.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roku Netflix Player</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/roku-netflix-player/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/roku-netflix-player/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.roku.com/netflixplayer/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1264&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4832e7e599724_0.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.roku.com/netflixplayer/&#34;&gt;another set top box makes a move to bring the 10 foot Internet TV and movie experience to your living room&lt;/a&gt;. This time Roku, maker of the Soundbridge audio player, has teamed up with Netflix to deliver their video on demand service to a set top box designed for Netflix service only. The $100 box allows you to navigate your queue, view show/movie information, and stream videos that were previously only available for Internet streaming to Windows users previously. It&amp;rsquo;s not apparent if you can browse videos outside of your queue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Netflix users, the service is included free of charge if your plan allows Internet streaming. The streaming catalog still only hovers around 10,000 movies compared to the 100,000 available DVDs.  This is mostly older titles, but that&amp;rsquo;s still not a bad number and you can expect the catalog to grow. I can confirm that I see about 10% of my queue with Play Now options presently. Sadly, the box doesn&amp;rsquo;t deliver HD, so expect VCR quality video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This move brings Netflix further into the Internet-enabled set top box subcategory of the Video on Demand market   with manufacturers including Apple and VUDU. Look for cable set top boxes to incorporate more of these services over time, and with that, the introduction of yet more features into already crowded 10 foot menus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.roku.com/netflixplayer/&#34;&gt;http://www.roku.com/netflixplayer/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>