<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Innovation on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/innovation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Innovation on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/innovation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How might we...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-might-we/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/how-might-we/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We know that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.startwithwhy.com/&#34;&gt;starting with why&lt;/a&gt; is important to product design, but what comes next? &#34;How&#34; would definitely come soon after. But there are many ways to propose how to begin exploring possibilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 99u &lt;a href=&#34;http://99u.com/workbook/20529/answer-these-6-questions-before-starting-a-project&#34;&gt;points to a number of questions to ask before starting a project&lt;/a&gt;, and how language matters. They refer to Warren Berger&#39;s article in the Harvard Business Review about one of the questions top innovators ask when confronted with a design challenge. It starts with the phrase &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.hbr.org/2012/09/the-secret-phrase-top-innovato/&#34;&gt;How Might We?&#34; (HMW)&lt;/a&gt;. It boils down to the selectivity and power of words, and in this case particularly with the choice of the word &#34;might&#34; rather than &#34;can&#34; or &#34;should.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s why the words make a difference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;When people within companies try to innovate, they often talk about the challenges they’re facing by using language that can inhibit creativity instead of encouraging it, says the business consultant Min Basadur, who has taught the How Might We (HMW) form of questioning to companies over the past four decades. “People may start out asking, ‘How can we do this,’ or ‘How should we do that?,’” Basadur explained to me. “But as soon as you start using words like can and should, you’re implying judgment: Can we really do it? And should we?” By substituting the word might, he says, “you’re able to defer judgment, which helps people to create options more freely, and opens up more possibilities.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim Brown of IDEO talks about how the words carry meaning for problem solving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;[W]ithin the phrase, each of those three words plays a role in spurring creative problem solving. &#34;The &#39;how&#39; part assumes there are solutions out there — it provides creative confidence,&#34; Brown said to me &#34;&#34;Might&#39; says we can put ideas out there that might work or might not — either way, it’s OK. And the &#39;we&#39; part says we&#39;re going to do it together and build on each other’s ideas.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out how &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openideo.com/open&#34;&gt;IDEO are using the HMW phrasing at Open IDEO&lt;/a&gt; to get people thinking about and proposing how to solve challenges for social good. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been trying to do more to accentuate the positive, and keep conversations open to possibilities in my personal life and work, but it can be difficult to talk about solving problems without bias given agendas, missions, roadmaps, prior knowledge, and history. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Choosing the word &#34;might&#34; feels like one way to begin early problem definition and solving without the weight  that comes from words like &#34;should&#34; or &#34;can.&#34; It&#39;s like the freedom in the tentative and erasable nature of a pencil rather than the indelibility of a pen. &#34;Might&#34; leads to conversation that is open to consider different directions rather than saddling you with choices that feel cemented too early. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Min Basadur&#39;s story about discovering the concept for Coast soap at Proctor and Gamble embodies this idea of opening up the conversation. The word &#34;might&#34; can lead to re-asking the question, and maybe even realizing that you&#39;re asking the wrong one. What I love most about that story is that ultimately asking &#34;How might we&#34; led back to asking &#34;Why?&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with the broader notions of starting with why, the HMW question seems a very powerful tool for facilitating design discussions and problem definition. I don&#39;t see very concrete, prescriptive techniques here, which is a good thing. The suggestion of asking the HMW question may be enough, but Brown warns that the size and types of design problem matter. HMW may not work for problems as big as &#34;How do we solve homelessness?&#34; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.hbr.org/2012/09/the-secret-phrase-top-innovato/&#34;&gt;Read more about HMW&lt;/a&gt; in the Harvard Business Review.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.hbr.org/2012/09/the-secret-phrase-top-innovato/&#34;&gt;http://blogs.hbr.org/2012/09/the-secret-phrase-top-innovato/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seth Godin on the Importance of Domain Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/seth-godin-importance-domain-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/seth-godin-importance-domain-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seth Godin&#39;s blog often talks about where successful ideas come from, and in this post talks about &lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/08/bypassing-the-leap.html&#34;&gt;bypassing the need to make huge leaps in innovation&lt;/a&gt; by synthesizing what we know and have learned from history, using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.appleinsider.com/articles/10/01/09/palm_ceo_former_apple_exec_says_hes_never_used_an_iphone.html&#34;&gt;Palm as the cautionary tale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;It&#39;s not enough to be aware of the domain you&#39;re working in, you need to understand it. Noticing things and being curious about how they work is the single most common trait I see in creative people. Once you can break the components down, you can put them back together into something brand new.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why we are constantly doing competitive monitoring and analysis of the products in the industries we work in. At times I feel kind of crazed signing up for betas out there, because the speed at which they appear now is overwhelming. I just have to remind myself that it&#39;s ok to spend the time if there&#39;s some research value, and then quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether we&#39;re just looking at the landscape from a high level, or deeply investigating and deconstructing how things work, continually expanding or improving domain knowledge is always going to be an important activity for us as designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/08/bypassing-the-leap.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Fsethsmainblog+%28Seth%27s+Blog%29&#34;&gt;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/08/bypassing-the-leap.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Fsethsmainblog+%28Seth%27s+Blog%29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Konigi Nominated as InJo Pick for Conference on Innovation Journalism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/konigi-nominated-injo-pick-ij-7-seventh-conference-innovation-journalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/konigi-nominated-injo-pick-ij-7-seventh-conference-innovation-journalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ij7.innovationjournalism.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2388&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4bfea4994750d_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week I got a surprising call from Roman Pixell, Fellow in the Innovation Journalism Fellowship Program at Stanford. The InJo program at Stanford is focused on journalism covering innovation processes and ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m honored to have been nominated for the InJo Pick alongside the well respected journalists in this year&#39;s selection, and will be attending the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ij7.innovationjournalism.org/&#34;&gt;InJo 7 conference&lt;/a&gt; in Palo Alto, participating in a round table on June 8. I&#39;m certain there will be much for me to learn from the experience and the exposure to the great minds at this event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ij7.innovationjournalism.org/&#34;&gt;http://ij7.innovationjournalism.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The iPad is a Toy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ipad-toy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ipad-toy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;353&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.hulu.com/embed/0zBU5VwtAbk6NSdVTsxDbA/1425/1445/i1438&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.hulu.com/embed/0zBU5VwtAbk6NSdVTsxDbA/1425/1445/i1438&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowFullScreen=&#34;true&#34;  width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;353&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Apple said Monday that it sold more than 300,000 iPads on the day of its launch, ushering in a new era of people buying things to find out what they are.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Seth Meyer for Weekend Update on SNL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew that it would be much more like an iPod Touch than a Mac netbook. But what I didn&amp;rsquo;t know until I &amp;ldquo;found out what it really was,&amp;rdquo; to quote Seth Meyer, was that it is for me better and more than I want from a netbook. I have a netbook. I use it so rarely that I ended up just tethering it to our second TV in the house. The iPad I use daily, because it is fun and it replaces my computer for a lot of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I came across yet another article saying iPad wasn&amp;rsquo;t serious enough and that Apple would fail, as it did the PC market. There are a lot of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?q=ipad+is+a+toy&#34;&gt;articles on this theme&lt;/a&gt;, attempting to mostly compare it to laptops and netbooks. They said the same thing about the iPhone as well. I don&amp;rsquo;t think these people get it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night I tweeted, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading articles dismissing iPad as a toy &amp;amp; not a tool, as if to say toys have no value. Guess what? Toys are fun.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/MichaelSurtees/status/12614483471&#34;&gt;Michael Surtees replied&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;ldquo;interesting @konigi —have you read the next big thing will start out looking like a toy at cdixon.org &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/6MZqQR&#34;&gt;http://bit.ly/6MZqQR&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Dixon&amp;rsquo;s blog entry, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cdixon.org/2010/01/03/the-next-big-thing-will-start-out-looking-like-a-toy/&#34;&gt;The next big thing will start out looking like a toy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; nails it on the head. This is a disruptive device that people don&amp;rsquo;t seem to understand and appear to be dismissing without really experiencing it long enough to know why it&amp;rsquo;s interesting. These are the people that focus on the feature set only, and don&amp;rsquo;t think about the bigger ripple this will make in expanding people&amp;rsquo;s use with both the personal and networked experiences. The similarities in the confusion the iPad is creating among people who don&amp;rsquo;t get it are similar to those initial reactions with the Wii, Twitter, iPod, and iPhone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For one thing, the experience (the interface and interaction) is the product. You don&amp;rsquo;t get it until you live with it. It was the same with those examples above. And when you get, you get it big. There&amp;rsquo;s the same gratification of understanding the multi-touch gestures. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pT4EbM7dCMs&#34;&gt;Two year olds&lt;/a&gt; get that. I even caught my 9 year old son trying to swipe the LCD on our camera last week. Then slowly you get that it&amp;rsquo;s useful in ways you didn&amp;rsquo;t expect and that most importantly, it&amp;rsquo;s more fun than you thought it would be. The apps help there. You like it. You like enough that you bring it everywhere and because it&amp;rsquo;s bigger than your iPhone, you realize it&amp;rsquo;s more usable for things like watching movies or playing Plants Vs Zombies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, there are limitations. After years of believing and playing the feature wars game with Windows Mobile and Palm, I had a hard time with the iPhone initially. But I used the iPhone more and more and never regretted that I can&amp;rsquo;t use Excel or whatever else I could do with those smart phones that really were &amp;ldquo;tools&amp;rdquo; crammed into a PDA disguised as a phone. This is the longest I&amp;rsquo;ve stuck with one brand of phone, and you want to know why? It&amp;rsquo;s because I enjoy using it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPad is no different to me than the iPhone when it comes to the experience of the apps. There are tools on it that I&amp;rsquo;m going to make an effort at using. By tools, I mean those that aren&amp;rsquo;t just media consumption apps. I&amp;rsquo;m making an effort to try to use OmniGraffle, Sketchbook Pro, and Pages. They won&amp;rsquo;t be replacements for my Mac versions, but they will be stand-ins when I&amp;rsquo;m away from the desk. In those situations, it is good enough, and I think with time I will learn to work simply and it may turn out to provide better experiences. To speed my adoption, I&amp;rsquo;m experimenting with leaving pen and paper at home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iPad is brutally selective on features, and comes up short compared to the world of user expectations. There is no camera, there is no 3G yet, there is no multi-tasking yet, and there is no printing. It builds off the experience of the iPhone, and it expands it to include the utility of the apps for simple productivity and creativity, while keeping the size and weight lean, and the battery life satisfying for an entire day. It even excels providing simpler experiences than those the tool-overloaded laptops and netbooks can provide. It&amp;rsquo;s an everyday experience, it&amp;rsquo;s a conference device, it&amp;rsquo;s a commuter device. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, it is a toy to me, but I don&amp;rsquo;t say that to put it down. Toys make me happy. I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the last time a tool really made me as happy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cdixon.org/2010/01/03/the-next-big-thing-will-start-out-looking-like-a-toy/&#34;&gt;http://cdixon.org/2010/01/03/the-next-big-thing-will-start-out-looking-like-a-toy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User-Centered Innovation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/user-centered-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/user-centered-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Roberto Verganti&#39;s article in HBR, &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.hbr.org/cs/2010/03/user-centered_innovation_is_no.html&#34;&gt;User-Centered Innovation Is Not Sustainable&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;quot; discusses how focussing on what user&#39;s say they want isn&#39;t a strategy for innovation. Not news to you, but his take looks at what that means regarding innovation from a sustainability perspective. I found it thought-provoking in other ways as well. The main idea is this. Forward-looking designers and business or policy decision makers may have a greater role and influence regarding designing sustainability products than customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article tells the story of the Toyota Prius, which emerged during a time when the SUV reigned supreme in the US, and customer desire reflected that interest more than any desire for small cars that had less of an impact on the environment. The proposal to produce that innovation came from a vision that started within company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Verganti believes that decision makers &amp;quot;need to step back from current dominant needs and behaviors and envision new scenarios. They need to propose new unsolicited products and services that are both attractive, sustainable, and profitable.&amp;quot; It&#39;s an interesting story from many perspectives, with environmental impact being only one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To dumb the discussion down a little, because I feel more comfortable with my smaller ideas, I&#39;ll tell you a silly story from my youth. When I was a teenager, I used to hang out occasionally at this record shop to pick up vinyl. I, like countless male Filipinos in NJ could mix and would DJ now and then. This guy who owned the record shop, his name was Spike, would play whatever new stuff had come in that he thought I would want to play, or I would ask him if he had stuff that I wanted. He knew tracks that I would hum to him after hearing them in the city clubs I&#39;d go to. He was like the reference librarian of the DJs to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In those needle drop sessions we would chat about what we had played and what the reaction was. One day I remember asking him  what he did when people would ask for something he would refuse to play. As you can imagine, as a teenage boy, it&#39;s hard to ignore girls who come up to ask you to play something for them. His answer was this. &amp;quot;You play them &lt;strong&gt; what you decide they need to hear&lt;/strong&gt;, not what they ask for. You&#39;re the dealer and they come to you because you know what&#39;s good for them.&amp;quot; Or at least that&#39;s how I remember it. Not sure about the drug dealer analogy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I laugh when I think about that story, mostly because it was funny. I thought, well that&#39;s what separates one type of DJ from another. But I based what I would play on that idea. A DJ is like a curator. Mixing ability is one thing, but it&#39;s nothing without taste and experience designing the vibe of the night. Or something like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So oddly enough, after reading this HBR article, I think back to this Spike story and think about the role of the designer and what we do with our user research. I think modeling products based on what we believe customers need to do is necessary. But somewhere in that process there&#39;s also this need to go on something else. Taste, authority, gut? It&#39;s something more like vision based on those things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.hbr.org/cs/2010/03/user-centered_innovation_is_no.html&#34;&gt;http://blogs.hbr.org/cs/2010/03/user-centered_innovation_is_no.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside IDEO</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/inside-ideo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/inside-ideo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design Observer &lt;a href=&#34;http://designobserver.com/archives/observed.html?id=47147&#34;&gt;points to&lt;/a&gt; the 1999 ABC Nightline program that took an inside look at IDEO. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;How does the process of designing a better product work? To show you, Nightline went to Palo Alto, CA to the designers at IDEO, and gave them the toughest problem we could think of. Take something old and familiar like the shopping cart and completely redesign it in just five days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IDEO&amp;rsquo;s unique brand of brainstorming is called &amp;ldquo;Deep Dive,&amp;rdquo; a sort of total immersion into the problem at hand. It&amp;rsquo;s one company&amp;rsquo;s secret weapon for innovation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a great quote in video 2 that I took away with me. &amp;ldquo;Enlightened trial and error succeeds over the plans of the lone genius.&amp;rdquo; This was a reaction to the question about why a team vote on brainstorming trumps a boss&amp;rsquo;s opinion. There&amp;rsquo;s also the adage, &amp;ldquo;Fail Often To Succeed Sooner&amp;rdquo; that&amp;rsquo;s often referenced at IDEO, regarding their prototyping process. It&amp;rsquo;s great to see the process of ideation, refinement, organization and focusing, and prototyping in this video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/2Dtrkrz0yoU&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z6z-3ejvvGE&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z6z-3ejvvGE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Buxton on How to Keep Innovating</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/bill-buxton-how-keep-innovating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/bill-buxton-how-keep-innovating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In BusinessWeek, Bill Buxton discusses &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessweek.com/innovate/content/feb2009/id20090218_337947.htm&#34;&gt;how to keep innovating&lt;/a&gt;, with the main idea being that you can continue to cultivate creativity and innovation by finding new things that you have a passion for. He suggests that when you get good enough at a thing, you should find something else to be passionate about, and commit and throw yourself into learning how to do it. You&#39;ll be bad at it at first, but the experience of learning something new, no matter how bad you are at it at first, may affect your creativity in positive ways that you won&#39;t realize until you experience it. In some cases, they may inform what you are already expert at, and in others lead you in entirely new and surprising directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The discussion reminds me of Paula Scher&#39;s talk focussing on &lt;a href=&#34;paula-scher-gets-serious-ted.html&#34;&gt;serious versus solemn design&lt;/a&gt; at TED. Scher spoke about the different times in her career where she was able to be most innovative in her craft, and the thing that was common in each case was that she was doing something new--something she didn&#39;t know much about when she started that particular project. The fact that one has no reference point or bearing can lead to innovative thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the same argument Buxton is making. I think Buxton is saying that the continued pursuit of new endeavors itself, is what can help cultivate one&#39;s creativity and create the pre-conditions for innovation. I&#39;m sure a lot of people who take up new hobbies and have the continuing need to learn see the obvious in this. This is one of the reasons I feel at home in a city where it is easy for me to start investigating and learning something new all the time. Being in a city isn&#39;t necessary, per se, but being able to get inspired and start doing something new is a hell of a lot easier for me here. This coupled with the fact that my wife and I homeschool our 8 year old son, which has lead me to dive deep on countless topics and project that I would never have held my interest in the past. If you read my personal blog, you know about my forays into toy making, game design, character creation and storytelling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, the story is not new, but is a reminder for me that being well-rounded and having many interests is a good thing. In fact it&#39;s one of the top criteria I&#39;ve used when participating in the hiring of people.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessweek.com/innovate/content/feb2009/id20090218_337947.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.businessweek.com/innovate/content/feb2009/id20090218_337947.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paula Scher gets serious at TED</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/paula-scher-gets-serious-ted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/paula-scher-gets-serious-ted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://embed.ted.com/talks/paula_scher_gets_serious.html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fantastic TED video of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ted.com/index.php/talks/paula_scher_gets_serious.html&#34;&gt;Paula Scher looking back at her career&lt;/a&gt; for those moments where she was able to devote time and effort to serious play and create wonderful work, and contrasting it with the unfortunate moments when the serious becomes solemn. I love how this retrospective observation of her career brings her to conclude that the best of times for her as a designer is when she comes into a project with no grounding or bearing&amp;ndash;those times where lack of history or reference point allows that kind of play to emerge. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ted.com/index.php/talks/paula_scher_gets_serious.html&#34;&gt;http://www.ted.com/index.php/talks/paula_scher_gets_serious.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clover Innovates the Coffee Maker</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/clover-innovates-coffee-maker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/clover-innovates-coffee-maker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The $11,000 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cloverequipment.com/home/&#34;&gt;Clover Coffee Maker&lt;/a&gt; brews one cup of coffee at a time using a method similar to a French Press, but with the ability to customize water volume and temperature per cup. The machine is programmable and has a network connection, so the machine can use brewing parameters for specific roasts. Check the video below for the Clover in action. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/zAEagZRoXPY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/zAEagZRoXPY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Wired Magazine, Howard Schultz, the founder of Starbucks described the coffee by saying, &#34;In my 25 years at Starbucks, the Clover machine unquestionably delivers the best cup of brewed coffee I have ever tasted.&#34; Schultz tried his first cup after seeing a line formed outside of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cafegrumpy.com/&#34;&gt;Cafe Grumpy&lt;/a&gt; in Chelsea. The company later bought out the Coffee Equipment Company, which makes the Clover, and will be testing them in Starbucks coffee shops. Shultz, who has retaken the position of CEO is hoping to restore the original idea of Starbucks, and support the the heritage of coffee at their shops. They will be making changes like grinding beans in store, and getting rid of the breakfast sandwiches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Clover seems to have an almost cult-like following. What I like most about this story is the history and back story of the Coffee Equipment Company. The company was started by Zander Nosler, a former product designer at IDEO, with the purpose of perfecting the single-brew coffee machine, based on research he did designing a commercial machine while at IDEO. This single idea led to the realization of a machine that produced unmatched quality in a cup of coffee that no other machine had, by focusing on delivering one cup at a time with very controlled customization of the brewing process. That attention to this process produced this $11,000 machine that indie shops and wealthy coffee connoisseurs were apparently happily paying for to make the perfect cup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Clover is no longer for sale to indie shops and individuals. It will be manufactured for Starbucks only in the future. For more about the Clover Coffee Machine, check out the August issue of Wired. &lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cloverequipment.com/home/&#34;&gt;http://cloverequipment.com/home/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Zappos Pays New Employees to Quit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/why-zappos-pays-new-employees-quit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/why-zappos-pays-new-employees-quit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The stories of Zappos&#39; commitment to superior customer service has become nearly legendary. From regular upgrades to next day delivery at no cost to the story of a customer service reps &lt;a href=&#34;http://consumerist.com/consumer/above-and-beyond/zappos-sends-you-flowers-311369.php&#34;&gt;delivery of flowers&lt;/a&gt; to a customer whos mother passed away. Now, in Harvard Business Online, Bill Taylor tells of Zappos&#39; unusual customer training program. &lt;a href=&#34;http://discussionleader.hbsp.com/taylor/2008/05/wy_zappos_pays_new_employees_t.html&#34;&gt;Zappos offers new employees a $1000 offer to quit&lt;/a&gt; after a 4 week training session. The idea behind this tactic is that by weeding out people who take the offer, they keep the ones who will be committed to the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because if you’re willing to take the company up on the offer, you obviously don’t have the sense of commitment they are looking for. It’s hard to describe the level of energy in the Zappos culture&amp;#8212;which means, by definition, it’s not for everybody. Zappos wants to learn if there’s a bad fit between what makes the organization tick and what makes individual employees tick&amp;#8212;and it’s willing to pay to learn sooner rather than later. (About ten percent of new call-center employees take the money and run.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a small practice with big implications: Companies don’t engage emotionally with their customers—people do. If you want to create a memorable company, you have to fill your company with memorable people.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that&#39;s innovative thinking&amp;#8212;being willing to pay to find and keep committed employees.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://discussionleader.hbsp.com/taylor/2008/05/wy_zappos_pays_new_employees_t.html&#34;&gt;http://discussionleader.hbsp.com/taylor/2008/05/wy_zappos_pays_new_employees_t.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of Contextual User Interfaces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/rise-contextual-user-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/rise-contextual-user-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Alex Iskold&#39;s article, &lt;a href=&#34;http://alexiskold.wordpress.com/2008/05/15/the-rise-of-contextual-user-interfaces/&#34;&gt;The Rise of Contextual User Interfaces&lt;/a&gt;, the writer and CEO of software company AdaptiveBlue talks about the rise of contextual interfaces on the desktop an in the services we use on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He points out the failing of choice over context in the old paradigm of UI design. Standardization of UI elements (tabs, combo boxes, etc.) was meant as a way to keep users from having to learn how to use an interface. The argument made was apparently that users are stupid and this paradigm supported the idea that we shouldn&#39;t innovate on core UI elements because users wouldn&#39;t be able to figure out how to user our applications. But over time UI designers simply made all of the choices available in an application in the forefront, putting the burden of having to sift through all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another philosophy of the old UI approach was that the user wants to see all information all the time. Instead of building UIs that responded to the way that people actually interacted with the tool, the user interface opened up all possible choices at all times. Naturally, this is completely overwhelming and confusing to people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result of the users are stupid/let&#39;s show all the choices paradigm ends up being, unfortunately, that even if users are smart enough to use these interfaces, they often end up feeling stupid when they can&#39;t figure out how to use bloated UIs. Sadly, many of these UIs make software so difficult to grok that we become frustrated using them, and often simply choose not use them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strategy of innovating interface elements based on usage and using simpler, contextual interfaces is the antithesis of the old paradigm, and is what is offered to rescue users from the flood of choices in lazily designed interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new interfaces are winning people over because they are based on usage patterns instead of choices. The key thing about new UIs is that they are contextual - presenting the user with minimal components and then changing in reaction to user gestures. Thanks to Apple, we have seen a liberating movement towards simplistic, contextual interfaces. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex tells the story of something his boss once told him, declaring that user interface are cheap. What the boss meant was, that &#34;the UI is so essential and so important to get right that you shouldn’t just reuse code and widgets.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iskold points to Apple&#39;s ability to continually innovate on its interface, but points out that the use of contextual interfaces has increased on the web due to the use of the richer set of interactions provided by AJAX and RIA tools such as Flash. The example that many of us have commonly use are the controls provided by flash video sites when we hover over video players (e.g. in YouTube, Vimeo, etc.). These players hide the controls for viewing embedding options, related videos, etc. until you make the conscious decision to move the mouse over the video. Use of AJAX to make expert features available via expanding/collapsing and hiding/displaying design patterns are another example of contextual controls that can be provided nearby when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the innovations using contextual controls even break the traditional rules for how these controls work, but in the new model, this is done to provide emphasis to function over form. In the eyes of interface designers, the belief seems to be, &#34;when an efficiency can be provided by breaking the rules, why not do it?&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://alexiskold.wordpress.com/2008/05/15/the-rise-of-contextual-user-interfaces/&#34;&gt;http://alexiskold.wordpress.com/2008/05/15/the-rise-of-contextual-user-interfaces/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>