<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Whiteboards on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/whiteboards/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Whiteboards on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/whiteboards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting with the IPEVO Interactive Whiteboard</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/experimenting-ipevo-interactive-whiteboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/experimenting-ipevo-interactive-whiteboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipevo.com/prods/IPEVO-IS-01-Interactive-Whiteboard-System&#34;&gt;IPEVO Interactive Whiteboard System&lt;/a&gt; ($149 retail price) to demo and did a first little experiment. The product consists of a video sensor and interactive pen. You have to have a projector as well. Here&#39;s a super rough demo I made for my team at Balsamiq to show how it would work using Balsamiq Mockups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/101344544&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the demo is pretty rough given the 15 minutes I gave myself to set up and record with my phone, it&#39;s pretty interesting to consider the possibilities for whiteboarding with wireframing software, if you&#39;re so inclined. I used a regular painted wall, but I&#39;m going to give it a try on a real whiteboard. &lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipevo.com/prods/IPEVO-IS-01-Interactive-Whiteboard-System&#34;&gt;http://www.ipevo.com/prods/IPEVO-IS-01-Interactive-Whiteboard-System&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Whiteboarding with Twiddla</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/team-whiteboarding-twiddla/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/team-whiteboarding-twiddla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twiddla.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/twiddla-1.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twiddla.com/&#34;&gt;Twiddla&lt;/a&gt; is an easy to use collaborative whiteboard service, but it&amp;rsquo;s really got the potential to be much more. The whiteboard lets you mark up websites and graphics, and even use a drag-drop library of interface elements for working on interface concepts collaboratively. You communicate with others in the meeting with the chat window, and you can also use built in audio-conferencing capabilities. Very impressive, and free. Would make sense for there to be options for private meetings as well as embedding the whiteboard into your CMS or intranet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just gave it a try and the images they&amp;rsquo;ve provided are very restrictive. They&amp;rsquo;re basically just graphics you drag in, but they can&amp;rsquo;t be scaled outside of their original dimensions properly since they&amp;rsquo;re bitmaps. It&amp;rsquo;s also not a true prototyping environment like Balsamiq or iPlotz, since there are no properties for the elements. The best you can do is draw or even upload your own bitmap elements. It&amp;rsquo;s truly only a whiteboard. That said, the drawing capabilities are decent.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give it a try, click the Twiddla button: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twiddla.com/New.aspx?title=&#34; title=&#34;Twiddle this page!&#34; onclick=&#34;this.href+=document.title;&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://img.twiddla.com/images/buttons/twiddle_this_100x20.png&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Twiddle this page!&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twiddla.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.twiddla.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Cost Multi-point Interactive Whiteboards Using the Wiimote</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/low-cost-multi-point-interactive-whiteboards-using-wiimote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/low-cost-multi-point-interactive-whiteboards-using-wiimote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;Researcher provides another Wii Remote hack, this time to help business users create interactive whiteboards on the cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/5s5EvhHy7eQ&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/5s5EvhHy7eQ&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;344&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might remember the incredible Wiimote hacks by by Johnny Chung Lee, who gave us head tracking demo for desktop VR displays. Lee, a PhD student in the Human-Computer Interaction Institute at Carnegie Mellon University is back with some more useful Wiimote hacks, this time to turn any surface into an interactive whiteboard. He shows how to turn a wall into a whiteboard with a DIY LED pen interface, and also how to create a multi-touch desktop or laptop LCD display using 2 LED pens. These are incredibly useful ideas for creating inexpensive interactive displays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using an LED array and some reflective tape, you can use the infrared camera in the Wii remote to track objects, like your fingers, in 2D space. This lets you interact with your computer simply by waving your hands in the air similar to the interaction seen in the movie &#34;Minority Report&#34;. The Wiimote can track upto 4 points simultaneously. The multipoint grid software is a custom C# DirectX program. &lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~johnny/projects/wii/&#34;&gt;http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~johnny/projects/wii/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>