<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Announcement on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/announcement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Announcement on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/announcement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael to Join Balsamiq</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/michael-join-balsamiq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/michael-join-balsamiq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;This is going to be big.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been keeping a secret for a few months, that I&#39;m finally able to share with my friends and colleagues who follow Konigi. Today I&#39;ll be bringing my love of interface design to the small team at Balsamiq. I will be joining Peldi, Val, Marco, Luis, Mariah, and Malcolm, my new family at the company that introduced software and web designers to the fun and easy way to create quick, sketch-style wireframes with Balsamiq Mockups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This move is the right change for me at the right time. I&#39;ll be able to marry my experience at working in-house on an evolving product, with my love of creating tools that advance my craft and sharing that knowledge and toolset with the UX design community. The move also represents the need at this point in my career to find a small group of passionate people that feel like family, that share my values, and that have a commitment to delivering a fun, simple product that people love to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve communicated with Peldi off and on in the past few years. We actually made contact initially because we both wrote daddy blogs a while ago. Every time I&#39;ve spoken to Peldi since, it feels like talking to a brother, and his enthusiasm is absolutely infectious. We&#39;ve ended some Skype calls giving high fives on screen, which felt at once nerdy and totally awesome. He&#39;s a natural leader, and I respect his commitment to transparency and doing good. When I&#39;ve chatted with Val, Marco, Luis, and Mariah in the past few months, I felt that same kind of warmth and enthusiasm, and I knew I found my home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t wait to start doing the work. I think we can expect that I&#39;ll be working on the user experience for Mockups Desktop and the myBalsamiq web app. My goal is to support the team in continuing to improve the overall experience with Balsamiq products, from providing support and fielding customer needs to bringing rigor to the design of every product feature. There&#39;s a clear vision for simplicity and quality in this team, and I want to help fulfill that. This is going to be big, and as you can tell, I&#39;m having a hard time containing my excitement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.balsamiq.com/blog/2010/03/01/michael-angeles-joins-balsamiq/&#34;&gt;Read Peldi&#39;s announcement on the Balsamiq&lt;/a&gt;. You can also follow my new Twitter identity, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/balsamiqMike&#34;&gt;@balsamiqMike&lt;/a&gt;, for Balsamiq related UX tweets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://balsamiq.com/&#34;&gt;http://balsamiq.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Konigi Site is Back and Server Moved</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/konigi-site-back-and-server-moved/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/konigi-site-back-and-server-moved/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sorry for the downtime. Konigi went down for most of the day yesterday because a spike in traffic and number of database requests caused the databases to be taken offline. With our web host&#39;s help, we&#39;ve moved Konigi to a virtual private server, and now we&#39;re able to run our own database rather than share database resources and limit the number of requests we can make. These are all good problems, and the growing pains are to be expected I suppose. Again, sorry for the interrupted service. I think i day of downtime to move the server is pretty good, so I&#39;m just happy we&#39;re back in business.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank You for 2009</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/thank-you-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/thank-you-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;I wanted to take a moment before I start the New Year&#39;s reveling with my family to thank all of you for the past year.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been a great second year discussing and learning with all of you via Konigi. I&#39;ve connected with so many awesome UX designers by posting my thoughts and experiments on the site, meeting up in the NYC area at social gatherings and conferences, and in the exchange of little tweets here and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To end a great year, I promised to donate 50% of sales proceeds to New York City charities that fight poverty and homelessness, and you guys came through with your support. With your help, I was able to donate $800 ($400 each) to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foodbanknyc.org/&#34;&gt;The Food Bank of New York City&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.robinhood.org/&#34;&gt;Robin Hood&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thank all of you who bought my little sketchbooks, notepads, icons, and stencils. Every one of them counted, and while the dollars may be small compared to what corporations give, I feel good knowing that this is a giving effort that&#39;s been powered by an indie spirit and hand made goods. It&#39;s felt so good that I&#39;m going to make the promise to donate of a percentage of sales a regular part of what I do as long as I sell stuff on this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So cheers to the great UX community that I&#39;m fortunate enough to be a part of. I wish all of a you an ass kickin&#39; Twenty Ten!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Konigi DIY Wireframe Magnets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/konigi-diy-wireframe-magnets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/konigi-diy-wireframe-magnets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../tools/wireframe-magnets-diy-kit.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1775&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4a48c47e68167_0.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../tools/wireframe-magnets-diy-kit.html&#34;&gt;The Konigi DIY Wireframe Magnet Kit&lt;/a&gt; is based on the wireframe stencils and includes 3 sheets of elements that might be useful in whiteboard prototyping. Simply download and print the PDFs onto magnet sheets. They were designed and tested for use with Avery 3270 Printable Magnet Sheets for Inkjet Printers. Lamination is also recommended so they&amp;rsquo;re usable with dry-erase markers. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../tools/wireframe-magnets-diy-kit.html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://konigi.com/tools/wireframe-magnets-diy-kit&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/tools/wireframe-magnets-diy-kit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireframe Icons Updated (v. 1.2)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-icons-updated-v-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-icons-updated-v-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/wireframe-icons-1-2.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons&#34;&gt;wireframe icons&lt;/a&gt; have been updated to add a bunch of new icons and crop the PNGs to 16 x 16 px. Still recession priced at $10, with lifetime free upgrades. If you own this set, go to your &lt;a href=&#34;../user.html&#34;&gt;account page&lt;/a&gt; and click the &amp;ldquo;Files&amp;rdquo; link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New icons: home, currency symbols, light bulb, hour glass, bell, rubber stamp, text tool, drawing tool, layout, calculator, medal, ribbon, puzzle piece/plugin, key, asterisk/new, wand/wizard, music, exit, pagination arrows,  mobile phone, iPhone, happy face, and sad face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those new to this icon set, the icons are meant for creating wireframes, grayscale user interface design schematics. The downloadable file gives you an OmniGraffle stencil and a folder of PNGs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons&#34;&gt;Find out more&lt;/a&gt; about the wireframe icons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-icons?q=store/product/wireframe-icons&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/product/wireframe-icons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Konigi Wants to Grow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/konigi-wants-grow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/konigi-wants-grow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m going to be tearing things up a little while Konigi gets a clue about what it is. I started playing with this blog in Nov 07 as a more organized way of doing my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/sets/72157600094498222/&#34;&gt;visual design&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/groups/designpatterns/&#34;&gt;user interface design&lt;/a&gt; sets on Flickr, and think it&#39;s still going well. But over time I&#39;ve found myself drawn to re-blogging and writing the occasional essay, reminding me of my first try at blogging when I did iaslash. And then the old sketchbooks full of ideas that came out of all those great conversations with IAI peeps in Monterrey and my iaslash readers kept returning, and I found myself wanting to find time to work on some micro-projects to build IA/IXD tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been a little over a year since I started announced Konigi, and it feels like time to take this site a bit more seriously and use it as a platform for other kinds of the learning, sharing, and collection of resources that I&#39;ve wanted to do for some time. Konigi wants to be better and do more with its life. So I&#39;m going to start with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/3344620893/&#34;&gt;a few little design tweaks&lt;/a&gt; and evolve the site organically as time becomes available to help this baby along. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what&#39;s coming? I have a series of instructional essays that I&#39;ve outlined and have started writing. I have a wonderful new community project planned that that will be possible through Peldi Guilizzoni, the gracious and talented creator of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.balsamiq.com/products&#34;&gt;Balsamiq&lt;/a&gt;. And I&#39;m going to play at opening up the site a little more until stuff gets broken. The Modus Operandi will be to just do stuff rather than doing so much thinking and talking, to do it wrong, to fail, to have people mock me, and be left standing at the end. As always, I plan to give away some stuff, charge a little for other stuff, and push a few smallish projects forward with the help of friends to fill gaps where we need educational/learning resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I personally want to do more and contribute more outside of this community, and I&#39;m hoping to find a way to give away more to people in need. The sale of things on this site has really taken me by surprise and now I want to do something better and more meaningful if I&#39;m in a position to do so. I&#39;m still not sure what I&#39;m going to do, but when the idea begins to take shape I&#39;ll let you know what that&#39;s all about. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So onward. Grow up little, Konigi. Make something of yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You may now login with email instead of username</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/you-may-now-login-email-instead-username/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/you-may-now-login-email-instead-username/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks to @lorenbaxter&#39;s suggestion, I&#39;ve enabled logging in with email rather than username if you prefer. Luckily Drupal&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://drupal.org/project/logintoboggan&#34;&gt;logintoboggan&lt;/a&gt; module allows admins to offer this option, as well as offering registration and signup without the roundtrip to email. Sweet. Thanks for making my life easier, Drupal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should help ease the experience of finding your file downloads as well if you bought stencils or icons form the store. It also brings me around to re-implementing  some of the features I put in in Feb-March last year and then took out, e.g. vote to promote on design and interface submissions. I have a minor redesign planned that hopes to bring that back, but will bring it back for signed in users.&lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Notebook for Konigi Friends at SXSW Wireframe Talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/free-notebook-konigi-friends-sxsw-wireframe-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/free-notebook-konigi-friends-sxsw-wireframe-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;chrome://speeddial/content/speeddial.xul&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-notebooks-sxsw.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve made some 8.5 in. by 5.25 in. graph paper notebooks because I wanted something a little more functional than what I was using for sketching. They&amp;rsquo;re basically a mini version of the wireframe grid I use, with markers for 1/3s and 1/4s, but without the gutters. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with a prototype of this for a few months now and have a bunch of these ready to put up for sale, but haven&amp;rsquo;t been rushing to do it, mostly because I made them for myself and selling stuff like notebooks isn&amp;rsquo;t profitable until you get into selling large quantities, and unfortunately I haven&amp;rsquo;t the time to market the pads and books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I had a great idea for now. I am going to sell these eventually, when other higher priorities get out of the way, but for now, I&amp;rsquo;m going to start off by giving the first 30 or so away, starting with a little gift for my Konigi readers who happen to be able to make it to SXSW to hear the &lt;a href=&#34;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/ideas/view/2186&#34;&gt;wireframe panel&lt;/a&gt; that Nick Finck, Donna Maurer and I are doing. After the talk, if you&amp;rsquo;re one of the first 30 to come up to me and give me the secret word, which I&amp;rsquo;ll announce on Twitter a few days before the talk, you&amp;rsquo;ll get one of the books. My little thank you for being a reader and making it out to the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;chrome://speeddial/content/speeddial.xul&#34;&gt;chrome://speeddial/content/speeddial.xul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OmniGraffle UX Template Updated (Version 2.1)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/omnigraffle-ux-template-updated-version-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/omnigraffle-ux-template-updated-version-21/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../tools/omnigraffle-ux-template.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1457&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt496fa2c8296bf.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The OmniGraffle UX Template for interface and interaction designers has been updated to version 2.1. Included in this release are major alignment, grid, and layout changes. Added guides for 24 column grid with vertical and horizontal gutters on wireframes. Added appropriate guides to all templates that necessitated alignment guides. Added small wireframe and iPhone templates. Download it &lt;a href=&#34;../tools/omnigraffle-ux-template.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../tools/omnigraffle-ux-template.html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://konigi.com/tools/omnigraffle-ux-template&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/tools/omnigraffle-ux-template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Konigi on Twitter and Facebook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/konigi-twitter-and-facebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/konigi-twitter-and-facebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/konigi&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1428&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt495b9a0894cc6.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It seems it&amp;rsquo;s time to start spilling out some of the meta-discussion in my head&amp;ndash;the monologue I guess&amp;ndash;about what I&amp;rsquo;m doing here on Konigi. So I started to post announcements and thoughts about what I&amp;rsquo;m working on with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/konigi&#34;&gt;Konigi Twitter account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, I feel like I want to separate Konigi-specific postings from my regular Twitter stream so I can update interested readers via that account, as well as post more work in progress commentary, observations, and announcements related strictly to Konigi. So if Twitter suits you more than RSS or Email, or if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in my back-channel banter, you can get updates there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also a product page for Konigi now &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.facebook.com/pages/Konigi/45954601363&#34;&gt;on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/konigi&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/konigi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Holidays from Konigi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/happy-holidays-konigi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/happy-holidays-konigi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/happy-holidays-from-konigi.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to take a moment to thank everyone who took some time out of their busy days to read Konigi this year, to provide their feedback and commentary, to download my tools, to buy notepads, and to help me keep a dialogue going with you, my new and old design and development friends. This has been a very rewarding first year playing with this blog, and I feel light years away from those years spent doing iaslash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish you all a safe and happy holiday season. I&amp;rsquo;ll be slowing down quite a bit in the next few weeks to spend time with my family, but will return in the next few months with some improvements and surprises on this site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Michael&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Notepads Should Be Available Next Week</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/new-notepads-should-be-available-next-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/new-notepads-should-be-available-next-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Konigi Notepad inventory will be arriving next week. We&#39;ll have the wireframe paper, storyboard paper, and a few new designs for designers who don&#39;t need all the fuss of the big title boxes--minimalists like me! Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Konigi Graph Paper Notepad Preview</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/konigi-graph-paper-notepad-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/konigi-graph-paper-notepad-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m happy to announce that Konigi will soon be offering several products for creatives. I&#39;ve posted some photos I took quickly of the first set below. Better photos will come when the shopping cart is set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first round of gear will include wireframe and storyboard notepads. Each of these pads include 50 sheets at 8 1/2 x 11 inches on white 70# paper, glued on the left side. The ink is a non-photo blue (cyan) so that the grid lines and any sketch lines made in non-photo blue pencil can be knocked out when scanned and processed in graphics software. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wireframe Notepads&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/tools/notepads/wireframe-notepad-corner.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/tools/notepads/wireframe-notepad.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;photo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storyboard Notepads&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/tools/notepads/storyboard-notepad-corner.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;photo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/tools/notepads/storyboard-notepad.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;photo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dot Grid on back of Wireframe and Storyboard Notepads&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/tools/notepads/dot-grid.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in the details of the scanning process I use with graph paper like this, and are also interested in the issues related to knowledge management during the creative process, I recently posted a relevant response to someone question about this in the Information Architecture Institute members mailing list. Later in the week, I&#39;ll do a longer write up about this here on Konigi to talk about why I&#39;ve been working with scanned sketches, and why I think there&#39;s a need for this paper. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Faceted Browsing on Konigi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/better-faceted-browsing-konigi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/better-faceted-browsing-konigi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;companies.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-notes-by-company.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;About 10 years ago I participated in the daily indexing of news articles as part of my job designing a digital library. During graduate study for the MLS my concentration was actually on information retrieval and classification, so I was interested in doing the job and understanding the content in order to know how to make it useful to users. Customers would get this information via the web site, by email, and in newsletters. Every day I had a bunch of news articles from a load of database feeds queued up for me to skim and tag. A first pass of auto-indexing and clustering was done and we&amp;rsquo;d have to check the applied tags and add new tags for subject, company, product, etc. We had a person whose primary job it was to maintain these terms, with the cooperation of subject matter experts in the business, in separate controlled vocabularies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That faceted approach to indexing and description has really informed a lot of what I&amp;rsquo;ve done as a blogger in the years that I&amp;rsquo;ve maintained sites at iaslash, urlgreyhot, and now here. You see the result of the faceted approach to tagging in the metadata for every entry, and in the navigation for things like Design Tags and Design Colors. But I&amp;rsquo;ve hidden some of that tagging until I had some time to add views for navigating via those facets. I&amp;rsquo;ve been operating this blog with the mantra, &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; better to get it up fast and fix it later.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I&amp;rsquo;ve added a few more facets to the navigation. If you notice the subnav in the Interface, Design, and Notebooks sections, you will see that there are now options to browse by Companies in all of them, and additionally by Person in Notebook. So now you can view &lt;a href=&#34;../interface/companies/Nike.html&#34;&gt;only Nike Interfaces&lt;/a&gt; or alternatively &lt;a href=&#34;../design/companies/Nike.html&#34;&gt;only Nike Designs&lt;/a&gt;, for instance. Also, in the entry metadata, the term Nike will appear in the pill shaped tag, and you can click that link to see all Nike tagged items across all sections of the site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just to give you an idea of how these tags get into each entry, have a look at the article editor below, and you&amp;rsquo;ll see how granular I get with my tagging. I think it&amp;rsquo;s probably much more than you&amp;rsquo;ll find in a typical blog. Aside from the title, every field you see below is a taxonomy field expanded in the categories (ugh, I hate that they changed the label) area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://s3.amazonaws.com/konigi/notebook/konigi-editor-taxonomy.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe over time this will provide a more complete picture around the experiences with each of the sites that I&amp;rsquo;m choosing to feature here. There are quite a few features in my roadmap for this site that just take time to implement. I will for instance find a way to segregate views by product rather than merely by company, so you can view only GMail UIs and not all Google UIs. Rest-assured, those tags are already baked in, but you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to see them until later. Some of these and other useful features that made me want to create this site are forthcoming. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve spent some months understanding what I like to do here, the volume may decrease slightly so I can focus on quality and providing more analysis. As always I welcome suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drupal users may also expect that sometime in the future I&amp;rsquo;ll expose more about the process used to put this site together, especially regarding how the taxonomy bits are being utilized. Thanks for continuing to stay with me as I explore these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;companies.html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://konigi.com/notebook/companies&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/notebook/companies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back From a Break</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/back-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/back-break/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I pretty much took the week off from blogging because I was having a little bit of a creative block this week after finishing off a project and starting a new one. I also had a little bit of a let down after seeking out an estimate to create custom notebooks with my &lt;a href=&#34;../tools/graph-paper.html&#34;&gt;graph paper&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, I wanted to do a really high quality book, with a scored cover like the Rhodia, but the quote came in so high that I got really discouraged. So I stepped away from the blog to focus on other things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent this week doing some competitive research on the new project, and doing other creative things, like helping my son do some animation in Flash, playing with Ableton Live, cycling of course, and watching Le Tour. But now I&#39;m back and ready to start posting again and starting a new podcast recording. I gathered a bunch of sites I want to share with you and you should start seeing them next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the notepads, I have some ideas for making that happen, and I&#39;m going to start developing some new parts of this site related to that. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-m&lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>