<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ipad on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ipad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ipad on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ipad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Starters Guide to iOS Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/starters-guide-ios-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/starters-guide-ios-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://taybenlor.com/2013/05/21/designing-for-ios.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2682&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt522fb0376d88f_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ben Taylor&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://taybenlor.com/2013/05/21/designing-for-ios.html&#34;&gt;Starters Guide to iOS&lt;/a&gt; describes an exhaustive range of topics as intro to iOS design. He covers the deliverables you&amp;rsquo;ll be expected to produce, outlines the constraints of the medium, and introduces fundamental iOS and UI design concepts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://taybenlor.com/2013/05/21/designing-for-ios.html&#34;&gt;http://taybenlor.com/2013/05/21/designing-for-ios.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OmniGraffle UX Template 2.5: Updated with iPad Pages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/omnigraffle-ux-template-25-updated-ipad-pages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/omnigraffle-ux-template-25-updated-ipad-pages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../tools/omnigraffle-ux-template.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/tools/og-ux-template/iPad_Portrait_2_Up.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@nickf called me out for not having iPad templates in the Konigi OmniGraffle Wireframe Template, so I got off my lazy ass and added some since this thing hasn&amp;rsquo;t been updated in over 2 years! Added iPad Portrait 1 up, iPad Portrait 2 up, iPad Landscape 1 up. They have guides for 2x2 or 3x3 grid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note, &lt;strong&gt;this is for OmniGraffle Pro ONLY&lt;/strong&gt;. You will not be able to edit shared layers to modify the headers and other templates.  &lt;a href=&#34;../tools/omnigraffle-ux-template.html&#34;&gt;Get yours&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../tools/omnigraffle-ux-template.html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://konigi.com/tools/omnigraffle-ux-template&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/tools/omnigraffle-ux-template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MORE/REAL Stylus Cap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/morereal-stylus-cap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/morereal-stylus-cap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1004382302/more-real-stylus-cap&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2478&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4d5a9894732f3_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don Lehman&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1004382302/more-real-stylus-cap&#34;&gt;MORE/REAL Stylus Cap&lt;/a&gt; is a cool iPad stylus project looking for funding via Kickstarter.  The idea is to create a cap with a conductive tip that will fit over a Sharpie, Bic, or Fineliner pen. Lehman&amp;rsquo;s introductory video below shows the stylus cap at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;410px&#34; src=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/donlehman/more-real-stylus-cap/widget/video.html&#34; width=&#34;480px&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looks fantastic and simple, and you&amp;rsquo;ll have one fewer thing to carry with you because it acts as pen and stylus. Sweet. You can help fund the project and reserve a cap by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1004382302/more-real-stylus-cap&#34;&gt;heading to the Kickstarter page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.core77.com/blog/starting_out/don_lehmans_morereal_stylus_cap_18561.asp&#34;&gt;Core77&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/jenniferhogan/status/37370108703678465&#34;&gt;@jenniferhogan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1004382302/more-real-stylus-cap&#34;&gt;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1004382302/more-real-stylus-cap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad Dry Erase Board</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ipad-dry-erase-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ipad-dry-erase-board/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uistencils.com/products/ipad-dry-erase-white-board&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2476&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4d545565aa430_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;New sketching goodies hit the shelves at UI Stencils, from our good friends Design Commission. They&amp;rsquo;ve created an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uistencils.com/products/ipad-dry-erase-white-board&#34;&gt;iPad dry erase board&lt;/a&gt; with dot grid, and updated their awesome &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uistencils.com/products/iphone-sticky-pad&#34;&gt;iPhone sticky pads&lt;/a&gt;. Definitely want to get my hands on the dry erase board.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Mine arrived and I have to say that this is the nicest dry erase board I have now. It&#39;s made on hard particle board, similar to what you&#39;d find on a clipboard, so it feels great in the hands. There&#39;s an interaction key laminated to the back with gesture symbols and common icons, to help you while you sketch. It comes with 2 fine point dry erase markers with eraser heads that work well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m loving it, and so is my son, who plans to use it for stop motion animations. I&#39;m not working on iPad design right now, so I&#39;d love to have a few screen and browser dry erase boards, or a 6-up/8-up sketchboard for thumbnail sketches and storyboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uistencils.com/products/ipad-dry-erase-white-board&#34;&gt;http://www.uistencils.com/products/ipad-dry-erase-white-board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad Stylus Roundup: And the winner is...</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ipad-stylus-roundup-and-winner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ipad-stylus-roundup-and-winner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/ipad-styli.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Update: This review was updated after getting the latest version of the Stylus Socks.]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My search for the perfect stylus for sketching on the iPad is over. I&#39;ve tried ever stylus I could get my hands on. The three finalists that earned a space on my desk or pocket in the past year have been the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/iClooly-Stylus-iPhone-Devices-Version/dp/B0032J1NM0&#34;&gt;iClooly&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.etsy.com/shop/shapedad&#34;&gt;Stylus Socks&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.griffintechnology.com/products/stylus&#34;&gt;Griffin Stylus for iPad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Starting off on the wrong foot&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started out initially playing with a few rubber tipped styli and the Pogo Sketch. I had to &lt;a href=&#34;hacking-pogo-stylus-smoother-ipad-sketching.html&#34;&gt;hack the Pogo Sketch&lt;/a&gt; to make it glide, which I still think is an elegant hack. I even contacted the creator about my hack but he didn&#39;t seem to care much for the idea of having a plastic nib inserted in the conductive foam, so I gave up on that. All of the rubber tipped styli created too much friction to be useful, and I didn&#39;t see much promise in the hacks that involved scraping a metal snap across my glass screen. After those experiences I set out to find the perfect stick to take out with me to supplement sketching on paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have 2 main criteria by which I judged the styli.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tip should glide smoothly with as little friction as possible on the screen so that sketching feels natural&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The stick should be long enough to fit comfortably in the hand&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;The finalists&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/iClooly-Stylus-iPhone-Devices-Version/dp/B0032J1NM0&#34;&gt;iClooly&lt;/a&gt; ($14.95)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The iClooly uses a small, soft metallic brush tip that seemed to glide the smoothest on the screen, but the metal stick is too thin and short to use comfortably for more than the shortest sketching sessions. I used this consistently for at least 6 months and found it exceptional. I came up with an &lt;a href=&#34;hacking-iclooly-ipad-stylus.html&#34;&gt;inelegant hack&lt;/a&gt; to extend the stick, and that served me well, but who wants to use an ugly hacked stick?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.etsy.com/shop/shapedad&#34;&gt;Stylus Socks II&lt;/a&gt; ($7)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Stylus Socks II sold by Shapedad on Etsy are a clever solution that wraps the end of a plastic KOH-I-NOOR pen holder with a conductive fabric. My initial review of the Stylus Sock was based on my use of a prototype version, but I&#39;ve since received the final version which includes a felt tip under the fabric. The best thing about this stylus is the long stick, which makes it the most usable of the bunch. At only $7 a stylus, this may be the best choice for the budget-conscious sketcher. It works very well and it feels good to support an independent maker. At this price I think this may be the perfect solution for most people. One thing I would like is a heavier version. I may try to purchase a metal pen holder and move the fabric over to that one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shapedad is also working on a prototype mouthstick for people who don&#39;t have use of their arms, prompted by a request to make a long stylus for a quadriplegic customer. You can watch his progress &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/shapedad/5265910567/&#34;&gt;in his Flickr photostream&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.griffintechnology.com/products/stylus&#34;&gt;Griffin iPad Stylus&lt;/a&gt; ($18.99)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Someone finally tipped me to the Griffin iPad Stylus in November and I started watching the videos of users on YouTube and was easily convinced that it could be smooth enough. I was skeptical at first, but the rubber tip is surprisingly untacky and glides smoothly with little friction. It&#39;s slightly less smooth than the iClooly, but the biggest positive is that the stick is thicker and resembles the thickness of a pen or marker. It feels great in the hand, and it&#39;s long enough to  reach from my closed index finger and thumb to rest between the two fingers. The clip slides nicely onto the spine of my iPad cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;And the winner is...&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Griffin was my initial winner among the three. Although it&#39;s the most expensive, it works well and I like the metal stick, which I found to be the right thickness. The clip also helps me keep it tethered to the iPad case. After I received the final version of the Stylus Socks II that included the felt tip under the fabric, I found this stylus to be equally as effective as the Griffin, and glides more smoothly. I think they&#39;re both good choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still find sketching on paper superior to sketching on the iPad, but there are definite advantages to immediately having an image to share digitally. iPad sketching has a permanent place in my toolkit, and the Griffin is my weapon of choice. Hopefully this will be the last in this year-long series on finding the right tool for this task.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking an iClooly iPad Stylus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/hacking-iclooly-ipad-stylus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/hacking-iclooly-ipad-stylus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5204/5205139138_8867bed8de_z.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iClooly is the pen I&amp;rsquo;ve been using most for quick sketches on the iPad, but for longer sketches and for drawing the handwritten font I&amp;rsquo;m making in iFontMaker, the short stick kind of sucks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extending the iClooly stick is an easy hack that almost doesn&amp;rsquo;t merit a post: rip off the back, take apart a mechanical pencil, and mash the two together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Verbose version: Remove the clicky end and the spring inside, making sure the brush is pressed down and the bristles exposed. Find a cyclinder that the iClooly will slide into&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;m using the plastic housing of a Sanford mechanical pencil&amp;ndash;and push the iClooly into the cylinder. &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sarah Sampsel on Designing The Washington Post for iPad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/sarah-sampsel-designing-washington-post-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/sarah-sampsel-designing-washington-post-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sarahsampsel.com/blog/2010/11/10/designing-the-washington-post-for-ipad-detailed-wireframes/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2455&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4cdc1064e10d5_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sarah Sampsel wrote about designing the Washington Post iPad app, in 2 entries describing a little bit about the process. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sarahsampsel.com/blog/2010/11/08/designing-the-washington-post-app-for-ipad/&#34;&gt;first entry&lt;/a&gt; describes the types of interaction, visual design, and brand issues she had to consider when designing for the device. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sarahsampsel.com/blog/2010/11/10/designing-the-washington-post-for-ipad-detailed-wireframes/&#34;&gt;The second shows a few wireframes&lt;/a&gt; of the evolution of the home screen design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would have been lovely to also see some of the sketches, but it&#39;s awesome that Sarah shared not just final wireframes, but a series of wireframes showing the iterations. I&#39;m hopeful that she&#39;ll continue the series to discuss the visual design and some post-launch thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sarahsampsel.com/blog/2010/11/10/designing-the-washington-post-for-ipad-detailed-wireframes/&#34;&gt;http://www.sarahsampsel.com/blog/2010/11/10/designing-the-washington-post-for-ipad-detailed-wireframes/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 7 Tablet vs. iPad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/windows-7-tablet-vs-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/windows-7-tablet-vs-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;367&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/f2IuEH07xBg&amp;amp;color1=0xb1b1b1&amp;amp;color2=0xd0d0d0&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;fs=1&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowScriptAccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/f2IuEH07xBg&amp;amp;color1=0xb1b1b1&amp;amp;color2=0xd0d0d0&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;fs=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; allowScriptAccess=&#34;always&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;367&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a pretty fun comparison of a Windows 7 Hanvon tablet and the iPad. Mute the music and Steve Jobs voice over unless your into that kind of cacophony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found via &lt;a href=&#34;http://52tiger.net/windows-7-tablet-vs-ipad/?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed:+52Tiger+(52+Tiger)&#34;&gt;52 Tiger&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://52tiger.net/windows-7-tablet-vs-ipad/?utm_source=feedburner&#34;&gt;http://52tiger.net/windows-7-tablet-vs-ipad/?utm_source=feedburner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LiveView for iPhone &amp; iPad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/liveview-iphone-ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/liveview-iphone-ipad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zambetti.com/projects/liveview/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2724&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt522ff0a27abca_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zambetti.com/projects/liveview/&#34;&gt;LiveView&lt;/a&gt; is a free remote screen viewing application created by Nicholas Zambetti to help designers create graphics for mobile applications, and for quick and dirty simulations, demos, and prototypes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visual Designers may use it to view artboard while you work. LiveView is compatible with both standard and Retina displays. Interaction Designers can use with iPhone or iPad tethered via WiFi, to interact with software prototypes and demos running on your Mac to communicate and iterate your concepts quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zambetti.com/projects/liveview/&#34;&gt;Download here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zambetti.com/projects/liveview/&#34;&gt;http://www.zambetti.com/projects/liveview/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketching with the iClooly Stylus</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/sketching-iclooly-stylus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/sketching-iclooly-stylus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/4622655821/&#34; title=&#34;Quick sketch testing out Clooly pen on iPad by jibbajabba, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3323/4622655821_058b3da992_o.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Quick sketch testing out Clooly pen on iPad&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;This seems the ideal solution for my iPad sketching needs.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, when I thought of &lt;a href=&#34;hacking-pogo-stylus-smoother-ipad-sketching.html&#34;&gt;hacking&lt;/a&gt; my Pogo Sketch, I started researching all of the options for creating my own drawing tool for the iPad&amp;rsquo;s capacitive touch screen, and was researching the styli that were available. I came across the odd design of the iClooly and thought I&amp;rsquo;d try it out of curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had low expectations, but was surprised by how well it works for iPad sketching. I did the quick character sketch above in about 5 minutes with the odd little &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0032J1NM0?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=urlgreyhot-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0032J1NM0&#34;&gt;iClooly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=urlgreyhot-20&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=1&amp;amp;a=B0032J1NM0&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; style=&#34;border:none !important; margin:0px !important;&#34; /&gt; and Sketchbook Pro. As usual, there are things I think could be designed better, but this seems the ideal solution for my iPad sketching needs. The pros and cons follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iClooly is manufactured in Korea and is not the prettiest looking or most ergonomic stylus. The drawing tip is actually a brush. A cap covers the tip, and a button at the end of the metal cylinder must be depressed to push out the soft metal bristles. It actually resembles a makeup brush. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/4624567138/&#34; title=&#34;iClooly UI Sketch Test by jibbajabba, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4051/4624567138_334549f87d_o.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;iClooly UI Sketch Test&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I&amp;rsquo;ll touch on the things I dislike. Like most touch styli out there, it&amp;rsquo;s barely long enough to fit in your hand&amp;ndash;I find myself keeping my fingers higher above the screen on an iPad than I would a normal pen or Wacom stylus to avoid making marks. The cylinder is quite thin, so those with big fingers that detest thin pens be warned. The cap comes with a little key ring, and must be removed to use the brush tip. Unfortunately, it can&amp;rsquo;t be attached to the back of the pen. One thing I also worry about is how the bristles will hold up. I&amp;rsquo;m imagining that they&amp;rsquo;ll be splayed out with repeated use, like a well-worn toothbrush. Time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;ll cover the pros, starting with the form factor. I&amp;rsquo;m used to using thin pens that I get occasionally from Japanese stationery stores, so the form factor doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother me, and I like the fact that it has a clip to attach it to the outside of my Apple iPad cover. The metal cylinder feels durable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where this stylus really shines is in how it performs as a drawing tool. At first I thought it would be weird drawing with a brush, but it is not at all. Once I let go of the idea of needing a fine point to sketch, I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to evaluate these things a little more practically. The broad brush is not much thicker than a pencil eraser, and if you move fluidly on the screen it&amp;rsquo;s possible to let the physical size of the tip disappear and focus on getting your idea down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main reason this stylus beats the others, in my opinion, is because the brush tip glides across the screen effortlessly. The quick test at drawing UI shapes in Sketchbook Pro below shows how lines can be smoothly drawn, without any of the ugly jagged shapes I occasionally would get using a foam or rubber stylus tip, which tends to catch the glass and cause too much friction. That&amp;rsquo;s why I had to hack my Pogo in the first place. This is why I loved Ideate at first&amp;ndash;it makes up for the jagged line problem by smoothing your lines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/4623969525/&#34; title=&#34;iClooly sketch test by jibbajabba, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3333/4623969525_fd4533df42_o.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;iClooly sketch test&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should add that drawing finer details like the icons is really impossible for me without using a sketch app that lets you zoom like Sketchbook Pro does. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last observation I have is that if you view sketching as something you do loosely, and give up on any of the things that make it feel more mechanical, i.e. straight and clean lines, grid backgrounds, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to start feeling capable sketching on the iPad. I think in my quick test this kind of shows. The rougher and looser I draw, the easier it is for me to get out of my own way and not fuss on aesthetics. The Kirby character drawing I started above was fun and effortless and using the brush tip to airbrush color just felt awesome, better even than doing it with my Wacom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend this thing to iPad-toting interface designers that want to try their hand at getting creative with some of the better drawing apps out there. Tell me what you think and please post your sketches to the flickr &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/groups/ipadsketch&#34;&gt;iPad Sketch Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking a Pogo Stylus for Smoother iPad Sketching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/hacking-pogo-stylus-smoother-ipad-sketching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/hacking-pogo-stylus-smoother-ipad-sketching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/4621798330/&#34; title=&#34;My hacked Pogo Sketch Stylus for the iPad by jibbajabba, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4032/4621798330_3b7717f3ef_o.jpg&#34; width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; alt=&#34;My hacked Pogo Sketch Stylus for the iPad&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I blogged about what I thought could possibly make a better stylus recently and thought I&amp;rsquo;d sketch what I was thinking. The above picture shows how I think you could hack the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tenonedesign.com/sketch.php&#34;&gt;Pogo Sketch stylus&lt;/a&gt; so it will glide a little more smoothly on the iPad screen. The capacitive foam creates a little too much friction to feel natural to me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I drilled a small hole in the foam and inserted a plastic nib from an old pressure-sensitive screen stylus into the center. I then sawed off the back of the barrel and inserted a metal skewer into the back end to hold the nib in place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spring was actually part of the old stylus nib, and actually works well for adjusting the pressure when drawing&amp;ndash;pressing hard makes the nib recede and the foam makes more contact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The photo below shows what I ended up with. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/4621302783/&#34; title=&#34;My hacked Pogo Sketch Stylus by jibbajabba, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4041/4621302783_49604014ab_o.jpg&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;600&#34; alt=&#34;My hacked Pogo Sketch Stylus&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems like a simple way to get past the problem of drag on the screen. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad Sketching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ipad-sketching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ipad-sketching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;Pen and paper are still superior, but iPad sketching is good enough to leave those behind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topic of UI sketching on the iPad is coming up pretty regularly for UI designers. People want to know how it feels and if it&#39;s going to replace pen/pencil and paper. After a few months using as many drawing apps as I can get my hands on, I find that it&#39;s more than adequate for UI sketching needs. Pen and paper are still superior, but iPad sketching is good enough to leave those behind when you&#39;re away from your desk. Here&#39;s my run down of pros/cons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My initial reaction was that finger/nail drawing wasn&#39;t going to cut it. For one thing, while you can get around the fat finger obstacles by using your fingernail as your tip, fingers don&#39;t work because they hide the screen. A stylus helps, but because of the fat tips of capacitive styli and the friction caused by capacitive foam, it doesn&#39;t feel as smooth and the foam stylus doesn&#39;t glide on the glass. But, I don&#39;t think that&#39;s a hindrance for basic sketching. I&#39;ve also read that the sensors on the touch screen aren&#39;t really designed to work with fine tips in the same way that resistive (pressure sensitive) screens are. What I think would be perfect is something that glides like your fingernail on the end of a stick--a plastic nib in the center of a capacitive foam tip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all my nits and dream stylus fantasies, at the end of the day I think that the fatness of a pen like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tenonedesign.com/sketch.php&#34;&gt;Pogo Sketch&lt;/a&gt; is arguably better in terms of forcing you to do rough sketching as opposed to fine detailed drawings. Roughness and low-fidelity is one of the important attributes of ideation--generating ideas in quick succession and in volume to explore ideas without fussing over aesthetics. This is how I&#39;m justifying the constraints in my head anyway. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That in mind, some designers, regardless of my rationalization, will care about the feel of pen options and responsiveness of drawing programs. There&#39;s an interesting blog entry on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://doodl.es/blog/?p=139&#34;&gt;doodl.es&lt;/a&gt; blog that talks about capacitive styli and the applications Brushes and Sketchbook Pro from an artist&#39;s perspective. While some of the discussion about the features of the apps may not be relevant to everyone, the description of what is possible to those who care about the style of their drawings will like the comparison of the Pogo Sketch with the HTC HD2 stylus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally settled on using &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/sketchbook-pro/id364253478?mt=8&#34;&gt;Sketchbook Pro&lt;/a&gt; with a Pogo Sketch the most for its closeness in feel to sketching on paper. It&#39;s about as good as it gets for my needs right now. I won&#39;t argue with anyone that says it&#39;s not as natural-feeling as paper, but it&#39;s good enough for me. For detailed work, I think the capabilities of the vector drawing tools in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.omnigroup.com/products/omnigraffle-ipad/&#34;&gt;OmniGraffle for iPad&lt;/a&gt; are also very interesting, because your lines have all the line properties that OG offers, and can be closed to make shapes, with fill properties. Some of the features in OG iPad are so good actually, that I can see them being useful in OG Pro Desktop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m going to try to occasionally post sketches in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/groups/ipadsketch/&#34;&gt;iPad Sketch Flickr group&lt;/a&gt;, so watch that space.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad Sketch Group on Flickr</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ipad-sketch-group-flickr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ipad-sketch-group-flickr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because of &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/fred_beecher/status/13004887399&#34;&gt;@fred_beecher&lt;/a&gt; I setup this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/groups/ipadsketch/&#34;&gt;iPad Sketch Group&lt;/a&gt; on Flickr so we can share our UI sketches. I&#39;m going to slowly post what I work on there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;Freehand design sketching on the iPad is for UX designers. Any app that lets you do freehand user interface sketches, either using finger tips or a capacitive stylus like the Pogo Sketch is what we&#39;re sharing here. If you drop non-iPad sketches, they will be booted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggested tools to start: Autodesk Sketchbook Pro, Adobe Ideas, Penultimate, Brushes, OmniGraffle, Sundry Notes.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/groups/ipadsketch/&#34;&gt;Go.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/groups/ipadsketch/&#34;&gt;http://www.flickr.com/groups/ipadsketch/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fueledbycoffee iPad Sketch Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/fueledbycoffee-ipad-sketch-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/fueledbycoffee-ipad-sketch-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fueledbycoffee.tumblr.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2367&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4bd19761197d8_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been telling people how much I dig Adobe&amp;rsquo;s free &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/adobe-ideas-1-0-for-ipad/id364617858?mt=8&#34;&gt;Ideas app&lt;/a&gt; and Autodesk &lt;a href=&#34;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/sketchbook-pro/id364253478?mt=8&#34;&gt;Sketchbook Pro&lt;/a&gt; for sketching on the iPad. Craighton Berman&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://fueledbycoffee.tumblr.com/&#34;&gt;Fueled by Coffee sketchblog&lt;/a&gt; will give you an idea of what sketches can look like using these tools. Ideas is super simple and smoothens your lines so things look naturally drawn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m really loving it. The adjustment is taking time, and it&#39;s not as quick as pen and paper, but it&#39;s slightly more natural using a &lt;a href=&#34;http://tenonedesign.com/sketch.php&#34;&gt;Pogo Sketch Stylus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fueledbycoffee.tumblr.com/&#34;&gt;http://fueledbycoffee.tumblr.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad Application Sketch Template</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ipad-application-sketch-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ipad-application-sketch-template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/owaters/4501918517/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2350&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4bbdb8f9d6e23_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oliver Waters released an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/owaters/4501918517/&#34;&gt;iPad graph paper sketch template&lt;/a&gt;. 10px squared, with tick marks to indicate indicate the heights of the Status Bar, Navigation Bar, Split View (Landscape Only), Keyboard and Tab Bar. See also his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/owaters/3846053408/in/set-72157623733453872/&#34;&gt;iPhone sketch template&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/owaters/4501918517/&#34;&gt;http://www.flickr.com/photos/owaters/4501918517/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>