<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Presentations on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/presentations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Presentations on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/presentations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Des Traynor: Product Strategy is About Saying No</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/des-traynor-product-strategy-about-saying-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/des-traynor-product-strategy-about-saying-no/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The devil runs UX workshops for idle hands, and he comes up with bad features. This is Des Traynor&amp;rsquo;s lightning talk at Business of Software in 2013. He did an extended version of this in 2014, but the pecha kucha version gets to the heart of the topic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/81544164?byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;color=ffffff&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/81544164&#34;&gt;http://vimeo.com/81544164&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation Skills Considered Harmful</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/presentation-skills-considered-harmful/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/presentation-skills-considered-harmful/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t like public speaking. I love talking to people one to one and in very small groups. But public speaking and me don&#39;t mix, and if you&#39;ve ever seen me speak, you probably agree. In the handful of times that I have spoken publicly, I think only two were really worth coming to see and hear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe the only reason the worthwhile talks were not utter failures was because I had something to share that I think people wanted to hear, and could get something out of. They really had little to do with me. I think those talks had more to do with what the audience could do with what I shared. My passion about the topic let me forget about myself until I was just basically just giving people something they wanted instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathy Sierra is one of the people whose articles I like to read and presentations I like to watch, because I come away with ideas that I feel I can do something with. There&#39;s something almost pragmatic to me about what she shares. Don&#39;t get me wrong though, she is a charismatic, funny, and super smart speaker. But &lt;a href=&#34;http://seriouspony.com/blog/2013/10/4/presentation-skills-considered-harmful&#34;&gt;her post about public speaking and presentation skills&lt;/a&gt; is useful to me as someone who hates public speaking, and always feels bad turning down the invitation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s the message: If you imagine that your role in speaking is to be the delivery mechanism for the message/story/whatever, you become the UI for the User Experience of that exchange between you and the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I think this thought sums up what the role is about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s not really about the user experience they have during your presentation. Like your presentation, their experience of it is also just the enabler for something bigger. Because what matters most is NOT the UX but the POST-UX UX. What happens after and as a result of the user experience?  ... What happens after what happens happens? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When they walk away from the user experience, then what? Are they different? Are they a little smarter? Are they a little more energized? Are they a little more capable? Are they a little more likely to talk to others about it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe there&#39;s hope for me after all? I like this idea of the post-UX-UX, when it comes to products or presentations. At the end of the day, while the delivery and execution are very important, your presentation skill holds much less weight than how you&#39;ve impacted the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this brings me back to why I got into working in this field to begin with. I started professional life working on libraries, and wanting to help people find information that helps them do things that fulfill needs in the real world, outside of the experience of using the library. What I do still comes down to that, and I guess public speaking should be no different. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m still afraid of being the awkward kid at the head of the class, even if I know the material. But maybe next time, I&#39;ll just imagine myself as the UI, and the rest will fall away. &lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://seriouspony.com/blog/2013/10/4/presentation-skills-considered-harmful&#34;&gt;http://seriouspony.com/blog/2013/10/4/presentation-skills-considered-harmful&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketching Interfaces: Speaking notes and mini book</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/sketching-interfaces-speaking-notes-and-mini-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/sketching-interfaces-speaking-notes-and-mini-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../book/sketch-book.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/book/sketch/title.png&#34; style=&#34;width: 590px; padding: 10px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asburyagile.com/&#34;&gt;Asbury Agile 2012&lt;/a&gt; and have published my presentation deck and speaking notes as a zine-like mini book in a new section of this site. My friends on Instagram have seen me teasing out this talk for a few months now, and I&#39;m happy to get the ideas out because this is something I&#39;ve been thinking about ever since I started this site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the perspective of someone who is starting over and taking the beginners path. &lt;a href=&#34;../book/sketch-book.html&#34;&gt;Check it out.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../book/sketch-book.html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://konigi.com/book/sketch-book&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/book/sketch-book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letting Go</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/letting-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/letting-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two great slides from Yiibu&#39;s presentation, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/yiibu/letting-go-9109114&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;Letting Go&lt;/a&gt;, a talk about design in an time of increasing disruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6170/6188891324_71eb68e152_z.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#34;Issuing your customers with something that is rough, incomplete, and possibly even substandard seems counterintuitive but there is growing evidence that people don&#39;t necessarily want the perfect product. They prefer to deal with something ragged around the edges that they can adapt or improve.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8212;  Martin Thomas in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Loose-Future-Business-Letting-Go/dp/0755361555&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&#34;Loose: The Future of Business is Letting Go&#34;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6127/6189715023_b5fc1f1b73_z.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#34;The best designs will set the stage, but stop short of fully defining the experience.&#34;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8212; Adam Silver, Frog Design&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awesome presentation deck. Would have loved to see and hear it in person. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/yiibu/letting-go-9109114&#34;&gt;See the full presentation here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Photo credits: &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/tiseb/13541804&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/hodac/2243470147&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/yiibu/letting-go-9109114&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/yiibu/letting-go-9109114&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travis Isaacs Demonstrates the Keynote Wireframe Toolkit</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/travis-isaacs-demonstrates-keynote-wireframe-toolkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/travis-isaacs-demonstrates-keynote-wireframe-toolkit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re curious about Keynote prototyping, Travis Isaacs&#39; describes how he works with the presentation software to produce click-through prototypes. As Travis notes, it&#39;s even useful to people who like to go between a low-fidelity wireframe created in another application to interactive demonstrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;width:610px&#34; id=&#34;__ss_4347737&#34;&gt;&lt;strong style=&#34;display:block;margin:12px 0 4px&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/tbisaacs/keynote-kungfu-how-to-wireframe-like-a-ninja&#34; title=&#34;Keynote Kung-Fu: How to wireframe like a ninja&#34;&gt;Keynote Kung-Fu: How to wireframe like a ninja&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;object id=&#34;__sse4347737&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;510&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://static.slidesharecdn.com/swf/ssplayer2.swf?doc=keynote-kung-fu-100528224132-phpapp01&amp;amp;stripped_title=keynote-kungfu-how-to-wireframe-like-a-ninja&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;/&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowScriptAccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;/&gt;&lt;embed name=&#34;__sse4347737&#34; src=&#34;http://static.slidesharecdn.com/swf/ssplayer2.swf?doc=keynote-kung-fu-100528224132-phpapp01&amp;amp;stripped_title=keynote-kungfu-how-to-wireframe-like-a-ninja&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;510&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/keynote-wireframe-toolkit?q=store/product/keynote-wireframe-toolkit&#34;&gt;purchase Travis&#39; Keynote Wireframe Toolkit&lt;/a&gt; here on Konigi.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/keynote-wireframe-toolkit?q=store/product/keynote-wireframe-toolkit&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/product/keynote-wireframe-toolkit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kathy Sierra on Creating Awesome Users</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/kathy-sierra-creating-awesome-users/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/kathy-sierra-creating-awesome-users/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/96807822?byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;color=ffffff&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;The model for sustaining customer loyalty is reverse engineering user awesomeness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peldi pointed me to a video of &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.businessofsoftware.org/2010/05/kathy-sierra-at-business-of-software-2009.html&#34;&gt;Kathy Sierra&amp;rsquo;s presentation at Business of Software 09&lt;/a&gt;, where she talks about sustaining passionate and loyal customers. Positioning and generating sustainable relationships is not what you think it should be about. It&amp;rsquo;s about user benefits, and not features&amp;ndash;about how they feel about themselves in the context of what you provide them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t make a better [X], make a better [user of X].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What creates the conditions for a user to be happy is how they experience what they do in the world because of what you give them. To jump to the chase, it&amp;rsquo;s not about good products, good service, or good companies. It&amp;rsquo;s not about you at all. It&amp;rsquo;s about your users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The model for sustaining customer loyalty is reverse engineering user awesomeness. Doing things that continue to let them say, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m awesome&amp;rdquo; because of things your product lets them do. Helping people kick ass FTW. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t sell me, teach me and I&amp;rsquo;ll do the rest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One example she gives has to do with how you treat examples vs. documentation. She references a Nikon learning site that shows people how to capture a waterfall, and cuts right to that user voice that says, &amp;ldquo;I want to do that.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By providing a learning experience that tells this story rather than expecting users to read the manual, the user can do more and go further than any technical document will ever enable them to do. Manuals let users understand tools, but stories and examples help users have great experiences. If you help users have that experience, they associate you with that experience&amp;ndash;that awesomeness they create themselves. It&amp;rsquo;s not about creating better products necessarily, it&amp;rsquo;s about enabling people to become better users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She suggests focussing on compelling questions, like the ones below, that have to do with creating that user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on what the user does, not what you do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask, &amp;ldquo;What does having a solution mean to our users? What [bigger cooler thing] is enabled?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give them super powers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offer better gear and help them justify it to others. Give them higher &amp;ldquo;resolution&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Motivate and Inspire. Give them motivation for things they WANT to do but aren&amp;rsquo;t. Get stuck camera users out of P mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the right thing easy and the wrong thing difficult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make them actually smarter. Keep users working on the smart things. Offer exercises, games, etc. that support deliberate practice of the right things. Make the time more fun. Turn the brain on with cognitive pleasures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shrink the user&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Outliers_(book)&#34;&gt;10,000 hours&lt;/a&gt; (time spent working on a specific task), by giving them patterns or shortening the duration of that time. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make your product or your documentation reflect how they really feel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does being your user SAY about your user? What would their tshirt read?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the heroes journey, we have to think about who we are to our users, and what role we actually play.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t insist on inclusivity. It&amp;rsquo;s OK to split off the advanced ass kickers from the newbies in your community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to agree with the closing point she makes. What we&amp;rsquo;re doing by making software is increasing the resolution of the universe for people&amp;ndash;increasing their ability to see more and feel expert in their world. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.businessofsoftware.org/2010/05/kathy-sierra-at-business-of-software-2009.html&#34;&gt;watched the hour long video above&lt;/a&gt;, I highly recommend making the time to come back to it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.businessofsoftware.org/2010/05/kathy-sierra-at-business-of-software-2009.html&#34;&gt;http://blog.businessofsoftware.org/2010/05/kathy-sierra-at-business-of-software-2009.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ten Commandments Of User Experience</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/ten-commandments-user-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/ten-commandments-user-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;visibility:hidden;width:0px;height:0px;&#34; border=0 width=0 height=0 src=&#34;http://counters.gigya.com/wildfire/IMP/CXNID=2000002.0NXC/bT*xJmx*PTEyNjg5MjgxNjQyNjEmcHQ9MTI2ODkyODE3MTkyNCZwPTEwMTkxJmQ9c3NfZW1iZWQmZz*yJm89MGRjNDg1OTEzNDVl/NDlkYWIzZWFiZWNjYWU5YTJhNGUmb2Y9MA==.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;width:610px&#34; id=&#34;__ss_3463603&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;509&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://static.slidesharecdn.com/swf/ssplayer2.swf?doc=thetencommandmentsofuserexperience-100318020617-phpapp02&amp;amp;stripped_title=the-ten-commandments-of-user-experience&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;/&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowScriptAccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;/&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://static.slidesharecdn.com/swf/ssplayer2.swf?doc=thetencommandmentsofuserexperience-100318020617-phpapp02&amp;amp;stripped_title=the-ten-commandments-of-user-experience&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;509&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:5px 0 12px&#34;&gt;View more &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/&#34;&gt;presentations&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/nickf&#34;&gt;Nick Finck&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick Finck and Raina Van Cleave&amp;rsquo;s presentation slides from the SXSWi talk are up. Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;User experiences are your everyday experiences—anything from operating a car, to making a pot of coffee, to ordering a pair of shoes online. User experience is the result of your interactions with a product or service, specifically how it’s delivered and its related artifacts according to the design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this presentation Nick Finck and Raina Van Cleave will explore the ten characteristics of a great user experience. They will cover all aspects of user experience design such as user research, information architecture, information design, technical writing, interaction design, visual design, brand identity design, accessibly, usability and web analytics. Nick and Raina will also explain how following the ten commandments can boost your web sites, web app, or mobile app’s ease of use, appeal, conversion rates, and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nickfinck.com/blog/entry/the_ten_commandments_of_user_experience/&#34;&gt;Read more on Nick&amp;rsquo;s site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nickfinck.com/blog/entry/the_ten_commandments_of_user_experience/&#34;&gt;http://www.nickfinck.com/blog/entry/the_ten_commandments_of_user_experience/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the Right Way to Wireframe Videos</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/all-right-way-wireframe-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/all-right-way-wireframe-videos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wanted to capture all of the slides and videos into one entry to compare each of the guys&amp;rsquo; approaches. The right way? There isn&amp;rsquo;t one right way. That&amp;rsquo;s the point. The one thread that does carry through, however, is a general process of discovery/research, sketching/ideation, selection/refinement, visual design. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Will Evans&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;489&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/QSxF-pISj1w&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/QSxF-pISj1w&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;489&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;width:610px&#34; id=&#34;__ss_3440749&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;509&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://static.slidesharecdn.com/swf/ssplayer2.swf?doc=rwtwpresentation-willevans-sxsw-100315175721-phpapp01&amp;amp;stripped_title=rwtw-presentationwill-evanssxsw&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;/&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowScriptAccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;/&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://static.slidesharecdn.com/swf/ssplayer2.swf?doc=rwtwpresentation-willevans-sxsw-100315175721-phpapp01&amp;amp;stripped_title=rwtw-presentationwill-evanssxsw&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;509&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Todd Zaki Warfel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;367&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/EvaOuKck1hk&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/EvaOuKck1hk&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;367&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Russ Unger&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;367&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/RjIDHTyY1zM&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/RjIDHTyY1zM&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;367&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fred Beecher&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;489&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/eFHWx9Poums&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/eFHWx9Poums&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;489&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>25 User Experience Videos That Are Worth Your Time</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/25-user-experience-videos-are-worth-your-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/25-user-experience-videos-are-worth-your-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2010/01/05/25-user-experience-videos-that-are-worth-your-time/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2259&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4b43a441a4c92_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Smashing Magazine have curated a list of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2010/01/05/25-user-experience-videos-that-are-worth-your-time/&#34;&gt;25 videos UX videos and presentations worth watching&lt;/a&gt;. It will take you more than 16 hours to watch all of these videos.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2010/01/05/25-user-experience-videos-that-are-worth-your-time/&#34;&gt;http://www.smashingmagazine.com/2010/01/05/25-user-experience-videos-that-are-worth-your-time/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Bierut: 5 Secrets from 86 Notebooks</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/michael-bierut-5-secrets-86-notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/michael-bierut-5-secrets-86-notebooks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; width=&#34;572&#34; height=&#34;429&#34; data=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=7252845&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&amp;amp;show_title=0&amp;amp;show_byline=0&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=e91c6b&#34;&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;quality&#34; value=&#34;best&#34; /&gt;   &lt;param name=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34; /&gt;   &lt;param name=&#34;scale&#34; value=&#34;showAll&#34; /&gt;  &lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=7252845&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&amp;amp;show_title=0&amp;amp;show_byline=0&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=e91c6b&#34; /&gt; &lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is fantastic presentation from Pentagram&amp;rsquo;s Michael Bierut at The 99 Percent conference. Shows how a quiet, humble, and empathetic bedside manner can be such useful attributes in a designer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Renowned graphic designer Michael Bierut claims that he&amp;rsquo;s not creative. Instead, he likens his job to that of a doctor who tends to patients  – &amp;ldquo;the sicker, the better.&amp;rdquo; Digging into the 86 notebooks he&amp;rsquo;s kept over the course of his career, Bierut walks us through 5 projects – from original conception to final execution – extracting a handful of simple lessons (e.g. the problem contains the solution; don&amp;rsquo;t avoid the obvious) at the foundation of brilliant design solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View more videos and register for the upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;http://the99percent.com/videos/6056/michael-bierut-5-secrets-from-86-notebooks&#34;&gt;99 Percent conference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://the99percent.com/videos/6056/michael-bierut-5-secrets-from-86-notebooks&#34;&gt;http://the99percent.com/videos/6056/michael-bierut-5-secrets-from-86-notebooks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jane Austin &amp; Chris Neale on Sketch Prototypes</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/jane-austin-chris-neale-sketch-prototypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/jane-austin-chris-neale-sketch-prototypes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;335&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=6415203&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=6415203&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;335&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper prototype is generally used as a design tool and even usability testing tool, but the folks at IG Index have figured out a creative way to use sketches and paper prototypes as a communication tool in place of wireframes for demonstrating interaction to development teams. Martin Belam posted video from UX London 09 of Jane Austin, Chris Neale and Frances Eida discussing this simple method of taking wireframe/storyboard sketches or paper prototypes, and creating stop-motion animation to demonstrate interface. Wonderful stuff. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.currybet.net/cbet_blog/2009/09/uxlondon_redux_jane_austin_chris_neale.php&#34;&gt;More at Currybet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.currybet.net/cbet_blog/2009/09/uxlondon_redux_jane_austin_chris_neale.php&#34;&gt;http://www.currybet.net/cbet_blog/2009/09/uxlondon_redux_jane_austin_chris_neale.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SlideSix Multimedia Presentation Sharing</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/slidesix-multimedia-presentation-sharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/slidesix-multimedia-presentation-sharing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://slidesix.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2738&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt5230068804f94_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;SlideSix is a presentation sharing service that let&amp;rsquo;s you upload presentations (PowerPoint, OpenOffice, PDF) with recorded narration or video imported from the web, e.g. from YouTube. Presentation pages provide social features (comments and chat), embedding info, and rating.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://slidesix.com/&#34;&gt;http://slidesix.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redub Designs a Better Online Magazine</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/redub-designs-better-online-magazine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/redub-designs-better-online-magazine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;visibility:hidden;width:0px;height:0px;&#34; border=0 width=0 height=0 src=&#34;http://counters.gigya.com/wildfire/IMP/CXNID=2000002.0NXC/bT*xJmx*PTEyNDcxMzU1NjAyMDAmcHQ9MTI*NzEzNTU2NTM*MyZwPTEwMTkxJmQ9c3NfZW1iZWQmZz*yJnQ9Jm89MGRjNDg1OTEzNDVlNDlkYWIzZWFiZWNjYWU5YTJhNGUmb2Y9MA==.gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;width:425px;text-align:left&#34; id=&#34;__ss_1686868&#34;&gt;
&lt;object style=&#34;margin:0px&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;510&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://static.slidesharecdn.com/swf/ssplayer2.swf?doc=dontmakemescroll-090706092213-phpapp01&amp;amp;stripped_title=dont-make-me-scroll&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;/&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowScriptAccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;/&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://static.slidesharecdn.com/swf/ssplayer2.swf?doc=dontmakemescroll-090706092213-phpapp01&amp;amp;stripped_title=dont-make-me-scroll&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;510&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across Redub&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t Make Me Scroll&amp;rdquo; presentation embedded above, which looks at the current offering of magazine readers which are modeled after print layouts, are difficult to read, SEO-unfriendly, and which rarely use the full capabilities provided by web browsers, e.g. multi-media. Or they&amp;rsquo;re modeled largely after blogs with articles are long and scrolling, are limited by the possibilities of HTML/CSS, and have layouts that aren&amp;rsquo;t differentiated from blogs and which pale in comparison to the layout in the printed version of the original magazine article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redub is working on a magazine reader, built on Flash, with a keyboard-enabled UI (input devices work as well) that scales to any screen size, does not scroll, and provides designer-friendly layout possiblities. You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://reader.redub.org/good/&#34;&gt;check out the GOOD magazine demo to experience the reader&lt;/a&gt;. There&amp;rsquo;s some really interesting interface design happening there including unobtrusive menus and prev/next paging controls, a pagination bar that is scaled to indicate the amount of content on the page, great examples of interactive media in the content, e.g. interactive charts, and hints at personal options like annotations. It&amp;rsquo;s very well thought-out and works better for reading magazines than any of the readers out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like they&amp;rsquo;re trying to do for online magazine reading what the Kindle does for ebooks. Exciting stuff to see the full potential of Flash being utilized to improve the magazine reading experience, rather than just port it over to an digital, PDF-like version that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work as well on screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://redubllc.com/2009/07/dont-make-me-scroll/&#34;&gt;http://redubllc.com/2009/07/dont-make-me-scroll/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Humanity into Your Products</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/designing-humanity-your-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/designing-humanity-your-products/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://blip.tv/play/g9NcgYj0f5fsPQ&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;503&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the video of the keynote from Ziba Design&amp;rsquo;s Bill DeRouchey, at the June 2009 conference &amp;ldquo;From Business to Buttons: Designing for Effect&amp;rdquo; in Malmo, Sweden&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://businesstobuttons.com/2009/06/12/keynote-designing-humanity-into-your-products-bill-derouchey-from-ziba-design/&#34;&gt;http://businesstobuttons.com/2009/06/12/keynote-designing-humanity-into-your-products-bill-derouchey-from-ziba-design/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oooh, that&#39;s Clever! (unnatural experiments in web design)</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/oooh-thats-clever-unnatural-experiments-web-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/oooh-thats-clever-unnatural-experiments-web-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;__ss_1188576&#34;&gt;
&lt;object style=&#34;margin:0px&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;510&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://static.slidesharecdn.com/swf/ssplayer2.swf?doc=oooh-clever-sxsw-publish-090324054010-phpapp01&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;stripped_title=oooh-thats-clever-unnatural-experiments-in-web-design&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;/&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowScriptAccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34;/&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://static.slidesharecdn.com/swf/ssplayer2.swf?doc=oooh-clever-sxsw-publish-090324054010-phpapp01&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;stripped_title=oooh-thats-clever-unnatural-experiments-in-web-design&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;510&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearleft&amp;rsquo;s Paul Annet talks about simple, clever little tricks that can make web pages pleasing. This is a slideshow with audio. No accompanying video, but if you jump to the end, you&amp;rsquo;ll find links for the videos shown during the talk. &lt;a href=&#34;http://paulannett.co.uk/sxsw09&#34;&gt;More at Paul Annet&amp;rsquo;s site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/nicepaul/oooh-thats-clever-unnatural-experiments-in-web-design&#34;&gt;http://www.slideshare.net/nicepaul/oooh-thats-clever-unnatural-experiments-in-web-design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>