<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Macintosh on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/macintosh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Macintosh on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/macintosh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Alfred/Hazel Workflow for Screen Capture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/alfredhazel-workflow-screen-capture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/alfredhazel-workflow-screen-capture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you take a lot of screenshots on a Mac like me, you probably have a good workflow for doing it using something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://realmacsoftware.com/ember&#34;&gt;LittleSnapper/Ember&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/awesome-screenshot-captur/alelhddbbhepgpmgidjdcjakblofbmce?hl=en&#34;&gt;Awesome Screenshot&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://evernote.com/skitch/&#34;&gt;Skitch&lt;/a&gt;. The biggest problem I&#39;ve had is that after I take a screenshot, I often want to do something with it. I can do this by just getting &lt;a href=&#34;http://getcloudapp.com/&#34;&gt;Cloud&lt;/a&gt; to watch and upload files passively, but I&#39;ve always wanted to save to my own server after just issuing one command to capture the page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love Alfred. Launchers like Quicksilver and Alfred are what I think of as the best minimal UI apps that I use on the Mac. I finally got around to searching for a way to capture a full scrolling screen from it and do something with the output. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alfredforum.com/topic/2062-scrennshot-of-web-pages/&#34;&gt;excellent Alfred workflow&lt;/a&gt; by user moom on the Alfred Forum that uses a shell script to run &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paulhammond.org/webkit2png/&#34;&gt;Webkit2Png&lt;/a&gt; in the background. It&#39;s awesome. I just copy the URL of the page I&#39;m on, summon Alfred with a few keystrokes, and then it gets captured, optimized, and uploaded to my server in the background. I made a video of the workflow showing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alfredapp.com/&#34;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noodlesoft.com/hazel.php&#34;&gt;Hazel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://imageoptim.com/&#34;&gt;ImageOptim&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://panic.com/transmit/&#34;&gt;Transmit&lt;/a&gt; working together with lots of spit and chewing gum in case anyone else has this need. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/72290954?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&#34; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a lot of steps to set up, but if you have this need, you&#39;ll appreciate it. ;) You can modify the steps for your workflow to move it to note in Evernote, to Cloud, or wherever your heart desires. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alfredforum.com/topic/2062-scrennshot-of-web-pages/&#34;&gt;Download the workflow here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re interested to know how I modified the workflow, these are the options I used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote style=&#34;font-style: normal&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;python webkit2png -F -W 980 --delay=5 &#34;$(pbpaste)&#34;&lt;br /&gt;
ls *.png | grep -v icon.png |&lt;br /&gt;
xargs -I {} mv {} ${HOME}/Sites/media.konigi.com/snaps/2013/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-F -W 980 outputs a full scrolling screen at 980px wide. You can see what the options are by running this command in the terminal: webkit2png --help.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/72290954&#34;&gt;https://vimeo.com/72290954&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Google&#43; Menubar Application</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/creating-google-menubar-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/creating-google-menubar-application/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t spend my whole day in Gmail or other Google sites, but I like the idea of checking in on Google+ occasionally. Until G+ comes up with a standalone client, I&#39;m installing it as a menubar application on my Mac using Fluid, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.balsamiq.com/ux/2011/02/17/creating-a-mac-menubar-app-for-pivotal-tracker/&#34;&gt;a trick I use for Pivotal as well&lt;/a&gt;, inspired by the article on how to do the same with &lt;a href=&#34;http://productblog.37signals.com/products/2011/02/tip-get-the-basecamp-mobile-interface-in-your-menu-bar-with-fluid-.html&#34;&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Might be a temporary solution, but the result looks like this on my Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6029/5904990381_9494328c0b_z.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 610px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s the instructions for doing this yourself if you have Plus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Prepare&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download and launch Fluid from here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fluidapp.com/&#34;&gt;http://fluidapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download a Google+ icon in PNG format. I found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.premiumpixels.com/freebies/google-plus-icons-png-psd/&#34;&gt;this one on Premium Pixels&lt;/a&gt; to be good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Create App&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;URL: &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/&#34; title=&#34;https://plus.google.com/&#34;&gt;https://plus.google.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name: Google+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Icon: Select other and browse to the icon you saved above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click Create.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Success dialog window appears. Cick &#34;Launch Now.&#34;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sign in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the menu: Google+ &gt; Convert to Menu Extra SSB, and click OK in the dialog window.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google+ icon should now appear in your menubar and you can click it to open Google+ in a drop down window.  Drag the grippie in the corner to change the window size. Use two-finger scrolling to move in the window, because window scrollbars will be suppressed.&lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Realizations of Rounded Rectangles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/realizations-rounded-rectangles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/realizations-rounded-rectangles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uiandus.com/2009/07/27/theories/realizations-of-rounded-rectangles/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1845&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4a76fe347eb48.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plasq designer, Keith Lang, recounts the story from computer folklore of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uiandus.com/2009/07/27/theories/realizations-of-rounded-rectangles/&#34;&gt;how the rounded rectangle came to dominate&lt;/a&gt; the Mac OS, and discusses its effect on visual cognition. He gets Professor Jürg Nänni, author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blelb.com/english/blelbpub/publications_en.htm&#34;&gt;Visual Perception&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; to offer his opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;A rectangle with sharp edges takes indeed a little bit more cognitive visible effort than for example an ellipse of the same size. Our “fovea-eye” is even faster in recording a circle. Edges involve additional neuronal image tools. The process is therefore slowed down.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor Nänni is saying that rounded rectangles are literally easier on the eye. Put another way, compared to square-edged rectangles, rounded rectangles are more computationally efficient for the human brain. To me, this is a revelation. An idea that at the very least demands more investigation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comment by Voideka provides a perfect visual reading of the difference between the rounded and sharp angled shapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;to me the difference I perceive is a single line versus four lines. In other words, when corners are involved, the brain processes from point A to B, then B to C, and so on, until it completes a circuit. With rounded corners, the line never comes to a point, which we interpret as a stop, and so there is a single computation following the entire shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the key is in thinking of a point as a full stop (much like a period in a sentence).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The point being made is that a particular use of shape, color, position, and movement are not simply aesthetic decisions, but can impact visual cognition. Mullet Sano&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0133033899&#34;&gt;Designing Visual Interfaces&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is another good source for the kinds of principles that can be used in practice. I haven&amp;rsquo;t read Nänni&amp;rsquo;s book, but have read a lot of literature on visual literacy, and tend to like the argument, however subtle, about the impact of the rounded shape on effort and perception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uiandus.com/2009/07/27/theories/realizations-of-rounded-rectangles/&#34;&gt;Read the full article.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uiandus.com/2009/07/27/theories/realizations-of-rounded-rectangles/&#34;&gt;http://www.uiandus.com/2009/07/27/theories/realizations-of-rounded-rectangles/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xSort: Free card sorting application for Mac OS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/xsort-free-card-sorting-application-mac-os/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/xsort-free-card-sorting-application-mac-os/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xsortapp.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1364&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt48d7818199ddc.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xsortapp.com/&#34;&gt;xSort&lt;/a&gt; is a card sorting application for researchers and information architects that want to get a better idea of their users&amp;rsquo; mental models for any given application or task. The software is free and works on Mac OS X.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xsortapp.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.xsortapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mac Tip: Mounting a Server Automatically</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/mac-tip-mounting-server-automatically/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/mac-tip-mounting-server-automatically/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/mounting-mac-server.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve always found a chore, being a producer of graphic documents, is versioning and organizing the docs for a team. I&amp;rsquo;ve had to use different tools like Source Safe, Sharepoint, Basecamp, and just shared drives to this. One nice thing I like about working with our Traction server is that it does Webdav for document management and file versioning. That&amp;rsquo;s one of the projects I&amp;rsquo;m working on a preview release of to make the web-based interface a bit more friendly.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing with Webdav is that I can mount the shared folders in my Mac Finder and drag and drop tons of documents in there without going to the web site. But I don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to manually connect to the shared folder. Luckily it&amp;rsquo;s easy to have the Mac OS automatically connect to servers when you log in. Someone tweeted today wondering how you do that, so I posted a screenshot showing how I&amp;rsquo;ve set up my Mac. You can do the same thing with whatever share point or server you use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure you&amp;rsquo;re in the Finder. Connect to the server using menu Go &amp;gt; Connect to Server, or keyboard shortcut Command-K.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the volume mounted, open System Preferences &amp;gt; Accounts, and select your user account. Click the Login Items tab (you may need to click the lock icon in the lower left to edit login items).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now just drag the mounted volume from the Finder in to your System Preferences &amp;gt; Login Items list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it. Now your Mac should automatically try to connect to your server volume whenever you log in, and it will show up in your Finder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scribbles, incredibly simple drawing app for Mac</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/scribbles-incredibly-simple-drawing-app-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/scribbles-incredibly-simple-drawing-app-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atebits.com/software/scribbles/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1423&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt49481259d6483.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atebits.com/software/scribbles/&#34;&gt;Scribbles&lt;/a&gt; is perhaps the simplest drawing program I&amp;rsquo;ve ever tried. The app, created by atebits, gives you 4 tools: brush, move, pan, and zoom. There are 12 brush styles, a color picker, a big slider for brush size, and a layer manager. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks deceptively simple on the surface, but when you explore a bit, you&amp;rsquo;ll find some really interesting functionalities that even the advanced Mac freehand drawing tools like Sketchbook and ArtRage don&amp;rsquo;t do well. One is the tracing paper mode, which gives you a transparent canvas so you can position the window over anything on screen. The other is the infinite canvas, which lets you zoom out infinitely to widen canvas by just dragging a magnifying glass cursor. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty wild, and you kind of get a sense of scale of your zoomed canvas when grids are on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems like kind of a fun toy, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure you could do a lot more with this if you got creative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atebits.com/software/scribbles/&#34;&gt;http://www.atebits.com/software/scribbles/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silverback: Usability Testing Software for the Mac</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/silverback-usability-testing-software-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/silverback-usability-testing-software-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://silverbackapp.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/silverback.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://silverbackapp.com/&#34;&gt;Silverback&lt;/a&gt; launches to provide UX pros with Macintoshes a simple, inexpensive tool for recording usability test sessions, so you won&amp;rsquo;t have to ever touch another Windows box if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to. (I&amp;rsquo;m kidding. I&amp;rsquo;m sure you will at some point in your life.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silverback provides most of the functionality you need for discount usability. People wanting a full featured tool like Morae won&amp;rsquo;t find their solution here, but if all you want is to organize test sessions, capture audio/video of screen interactions and participants face and voice, then Silverback might be for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process is pretty simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You set up projects and individual test sessions in the tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re ready to start a session, click the &amp;ldquo;Start Session&amp;rdquo; button and Silverback hides, leaving only a menubar icon for when you&amp;rsquo;re ready to stop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During recording you can use your Apple Remote to drop in chapter markers by pressing the + button. Use this for start of each task or to log errors or questions, for instance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re finished with the sesion, click stop from the menubar icon or by pressing Command Option S to open pause/stop dialog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Afterwards you may export the session as a QuickTime file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This application is a bit like using the screen capture tool ScreenFlow, but provides a few nice functionalities that make sense for usability testing. I admit to not doing a lot of time on task reporting in Morae, since my focus has mostly been on qualitative research, but that&amp;rsquo;s one thing you might miss. I also like the post-test surveys built into Morae, but you can easily create a SurveyMonkey survey or something and have the user fill that out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other thing that you won&amp;rsquo;t find are simple video editing tools so you can cut pieces out for your highlight reel when presenting your findings&amp;ndash;if you do that sort of thing. You can easily do that in QuickTime though and stitch together your clips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this tool has the right functionality you&amp;rsquo;d need to do discount testing on the Mac right now. All of the features you need to go the extra mile to make clips presentable are pretty much at your disposal if you have QuickTime Pro or iMovie. For me as a discount usability tester, the best part of this is, I won&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about needing a separate PC to do simple testing. If you bundle this with screensharing tools like those built into iChat or using VNC, you have the makings of a decent Mac UX toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purchase price is only $49.95 and Clearleft are donating 10% of all profits to The Dian Fossey Gorilla Fund. That&amp;rsquo;s two reasons too feel good about making this purchase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://silverbackapp.com/&#34;&gt;http://silverbackapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Dashcode</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/apple-dashcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/apple-dashcode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/2440900509/&#34; title=&#34;Apple Dashcode by jibbajabba, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3077/2440900509_20a61efb02_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Apple Dashcode&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.apple.com/tools/dashcode/&#34;&gt;Apple&#39;s Dashcode widget builder&lt;/a&gt; provides a nice library interface for viewing the parts you can include in your widget, and a code library to view snippets.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.apple.com/tools/dashcode/&#34;&gt;http://developer.apple.com/tools/dashcode/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>