<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notebooks on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/notebooks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notebooks on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/notebooks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireframe Sketch Book Now Available</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/wireframe-sketch-book-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/wireframe-sketch-book-now-available/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small?q=store/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-sketchbook.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sketch book is &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small?q=store/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small&#34;&gt;finally available in the store&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a small 8.25 x 5.5 inch wirebound book that lays flat, has a 24 x 24 grid with note block on the front (landscape orientation) and 48 x 24 grid on the back (landscape or portrait). Includes 50 perforated sheets (100 pages) printed in non-photo blue ink, and an interior flap on the back cover. For the first set sold, I&amp;rsquo;m also including a Zebra 0.7mm mechanical pencil. Yay, you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may know, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a notebook with a grid that works well for a UI designer&amp;rsquo;s workflow, similar to the larger letter sized graphpaper, but made to be small and portable. I&amp;rsquo;m accustomed to doing initial sketches small and rough. The smaller sized paper lets you work more freely and loosely I find, so you can generate many ideas before selecting and refining. This sketch book is the one I&amp;rsquo;ve been using for this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It helps with my workflow because I now have the small format for sketches, the larger format for refinement of ideas, and the OmniGraffle templates for deliverables. Each of these has the same number of grid columns and I&amp;rsquo;m continually working to improve the consistency between them so the flow makes the translation of ideas smooth from one format to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy using these as much as I do. They go on sale for $16 and I&amp;rsquo;ll be selling them in limited quantities for the time being. More info about the book &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small?q=store/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small&#34;&gt;in the store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small?q=store/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/product/wireframe-sketch-book-small&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Notebook for Konigi Friends at SXSW Wireframe Talk</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/free-notebook-konigi-friends-sxsw-wireframe-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/free-notebook-konigi-friends-sxsw-wireframe-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;chrome://speeddial/content/speeddial.xul&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/konigi-notebooks-sxsw.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve made some 8.5 in. by 5.25 in. graph paper notebooks because I wanted something a little more functional than what I was using for sketching. They&amp;rsquo;re basically a mini version of the wireframe grid I use, with markers for 1/3s and 1/4s, but without the gutters. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with a prototype of this for a few months now and have a bunch of these ready to put up for sale, but haven&amp;rsquo;t been rushing to do it, mostly because I made them for myself and selling stuff like notebooks isn&amp;rsquo;t profitable until you get into selling large quantities, and unfortunately I haven&amp;rsquo;t the time to market the pads and books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I had a great idea for now. I am going to sell these eventually, when other higher priorities get out of the way, but for now, I&amp;rsquo;m going to start off by giving the first 30 or so away, starting with a little gift for my Konigi readers who happen to be able to make it to SXSW to hear the &lt;a href=&#34;http://panelpicker.sxsw.com/ideas/view/2186&#34;&gt;wireframe panel&lt;/a&gt; that Nick Finck, Donna Maurer and I are doing. After the talk, if you&amp;rsquo;re one of the first 30 to come up to me and give me the secret word, which I&amp;rsquo;ll announce on Twitter a few days before the talk, you&amp;rsquo;ll get one of the books. My little thank you for being a reader and making it out to the talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;chrome://speeddial/content/speeddial.xul&#34;&gt;chrome://speeddial/content/speeddial.xul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Out Notebooks Has Become an Obsession</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/trying-out-notebooks-has-become-obsession/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/trying-out-notebooks-has-become-obsession/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../index.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/trying-notebooks.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a collection of notebooks that are in heavy rotation now, and the last Rhodia I used before I started making my own. Click through for notes. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/3103201627/&#34;&gt;View the photo in flickr&lt;/a&gt; for notes about the ones in this picture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../index.html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://konigi.com/&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do you look for in a sketch notebook?</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/what-do-you-look-sketch-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/what-do-you-look-sketch-notebook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/wirebinder.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s getting kind of old skool over here in the home office. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet gotten around to talking about why I&amp;rsquo;m spending time on notepads and notebooks, and just how I use these things. But I&amp;rsquo;m going to post an article describing just that. This photo is just a teaser to let you know that I&amp;rsquo;m still working away at this sketch paper stuff because it&amp;rsquo;s an itch that just won&amp;rsquo;t go away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That big old looking machine you see is a wire ring binder. I&amp;rsquo;ve been going through various needs I have for notebooks. I can&amp;rsquo;t live without my Moleskine or Rhodia. One of them goes with me everywhere. Lately it&amp;rsquo;s a Moleskine softcover plain notebook for my sketches, and a small cahier for my todo lists. These are great, but I still want a better notebook just for sketching user interfaces and interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things I look for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) It lays flat and cover can fold over&lt;br /&gt;
2) Is small and portable&lt;br /&gt;
3) Has some tooth&lt;br /&gt;
4) Has a sturdy cover&lt;br /&gt;
5) Has perforations for removable pages&lt;br /&gt;
6) Has a good graph paper design  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be interested in hearing what other people look for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, I&amp;rsquo;m mainly concerned with creating the tool that&amp;rsquo;s most useful for the type of work I do. Sometimes a blank canvas is better. Sometimes a grid is better. Some people will always only want blank paper. But maybe there are others out there, like me, who are looking for something a little better. I spent some days trying and being frustrated with what&amp;rsquo;s out there. Most of the time I&amp;rsquo;m happy with what I have, but other days I just want nicer grids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just working on finding the right tools to make my life easier. But I&amp;rsquo;d love to hear if there are things you look for in a designer&amp;rsquo;s sketch book that you just can find right now. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking that what might come out of this process for me are a small collection of customizable notebooks that I&amp;rsquo;ll produce for fellow designers with various papers that they select and configure. I don&amp;rsquo;t foresee producing a lot of these now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Handcrafted Notebooks</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/creating-handcrafted-notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/creating-handcrafted-notebooks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/my-first-notebook-2.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is my first case bound book notebook. I took a one day workshop at the Center for Book Arts to continue pursuing my obsession with notebooks. It is half filled with Bienfang 8x8 to the inch graph paper and the other half is Borden and Riley bleed proof paper. The section of papers is stitched into a text block that is drilled on left side to create this landscape orientation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get To The Point Bookmarks</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/get-point-bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/get-point-bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spoonsisters.com/Merchant2/merchant.mvc?Screen=PROD&amp;amp;Store_Code=100&amp;amp;Product_Code=44308&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/get-to-the-point-bookmark.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seems like someone has come up with a better solution for marking my note and sketch pages in my Moleskines. Dog eared pages never suited me, and the colored tabs I get at MUJI and the occasional PostIt note are OK. But I love the idea of these &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spoonsisters.com/Merchant2/merchant.mvc?Screen=PROD&amp;amp;Store_Code=100&amp;amp;Product_Code=44308&#34;&gt;magnetic page markers&lt;/a&gt; from Folio because it means I won&amp;rsquo;t need to buy anymore sticky tabs from the stationery store. And the little pointed arrows are pretty useful for pointing out lines of interest in books too. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spoonsisters.com/Merchant2/merchant.mvc?Screen=PROD&amp;amp;Store_Code=100&amp;amp;Product_Code=44308&#34;&gt;http://www.spoonsisters.com/Merchant2/merchant.mvc?Screen=PROD&amp;Store_Code=100&amp;Product_Code=44308&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Mobile Sketch Rig: Pilot Couleur Mini Pencils and Moleskine</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/my-mobile-sketch-rig-pilot-couleur-mini-pencils-and-moleskine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/my-mobile-sketch-rig-pilot-couleur-mini-pencils-and-moleskine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/pilot-coleur-cyan.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of Pilot and Pentel mechanical pencils. At home I use the larger Pentels, but when I&amp;rsquo;m out, I carry around the small red Pilot Couleur above attached to my small Moleskine. Ideas often come when I&amp;rsquo;m away from the desk so I feel like I always have to have pencil and paper wherever I go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pilots have a rubberized coating, hold 0.5mm leads, and hide an eraser under the push button. They stay snugly attached to the Moleskine strap and don&amp;rsquo;t flop around. I also found that you can buy cyan leads at 0.5mm, so I recently acquired a second Pilot. As you can see, they both fit perfectly to the side of the notebook. Now I can sketch in gray or blue, and if I want to share, I can use a paper trimmer, tear out pages and scan. Love love love. These pencils are from Japan, so you can get them at places like Kinokuniya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought the pics might interest some. I spent a little time trying different ways to attach a pen/pencil to my Moleskine, and have found that what I&amp;rsquo;m doing works very. The Moleskine above is a Reporter, so the strap goes across the short side rather than the long. This lets you clip your pencil perpendicular to the strap on the long side as shown above. Much better positioning than with the regular Moleskines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of other creative hacks out there to attach your pencil to your Moleskine if you don&amp;rsquo;t like my method. Everyday Innovations, makers of the PicoPad sell a pen holder called the &lt;a href=&#34;http://everydayinnovations.com/pages/products_booksling.php&#34;&gt;Book Sling&lt;/a&gt; that also seems well designed, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried one yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope this gives someone some inspiration for their ultra mobile sketching rig. Happy sketching!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moleskine Soft Cover Notebooks</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/moleskine-soft-cover-notebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/moleskine-soft-cover-notebooks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.moleskine.com/eng/_interni/catalogo/Cat_int/catalogo_notebooks.htm&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/moleskine-softcover.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got my hands on the new &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.moleskine.com/eng/_interni/catalogo/Cat_int/catalogo_notebooks.htm&#34;&gt;soft cover Moleskine&lt;/a&gt; notebooks. The faux cover feels like a luxurious thin leather, and is soft, but sturdy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.moleskine.com/eng/_interni/catalogo/Cat_int/catalogo_notebooks.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.moleskine.com/eng/_interni/catalogo/Cat_int/catalogo_notebooks.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To All the Notebooks I&#39;ve Ever Loved Before</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/all-notebooks-ive-ever-loved/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/all-notebooks-ive-ever-loved/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/rhodias.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recently talked to someone about the graph/grid paper books I&amp;rsquo;ve acquired over the years which have become a central part of my process. This is a listing of those pads, and a telling of their virtues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rhodia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my workhorse. At first I didn&amp;rsquo;t get why so many designers carried these around, until I got my hands on one. To me the Rhodias are an all-around notepad for in office or outside use. They&amp;rsquo;re well constructed and durable. They have the nicest covers of all the notepads, so portability/carry-ability is what this notepad is about. The cover is hefty and scored so you can fold it back and out of the way. I sometimes dislike the violet hue of the gridlines and paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A5 is my basic sketch pad. I do thumbnail sketches on it before doing a detailed version on my letter-sized graph paper. It&amp;rsquo;s reasonably priced considering the quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A7 is always with me. I carry the one you see above with the black leather cover in my back pocket. I abolutely love this notepad. It has even doubled as a wallet when I want to go out with nothing else with me but my Rhodia and a mechanical pencil.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Load up on Rhodia at better stationery and art stores or online at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exaclair.com/brands_rhodia.shtml&#34;&gt;Exalair&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Moleskine&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like many UX people, I have loved Moleskine for years. But I stopped carrying around the lined and sketch books because they were bulky. I have so many of these laying around now because I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up quite a few from event swag bags.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beige Cahier is another story altogether. I love the warm color of the paper and the fact that leaves are perforated. The weight is right for sketches, almost analogous to using newsprint or butcher sheets when warming up. It got a little costly for me to keep buying these though. I used to go through a Cahier pretty quickly. Maybe because the texture of the paper reminded me of newsprint and I used it for jotting down everything on it. I keep a few around the house because I love them so for their multi-purpose qualities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get your hands on a Moleskine Cahier at stationery and art stores in every civilized city on the planet or via the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.moleskineus.com/&#34;&gt;Moleskine&lt;/a&gt; store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Behance dot grid&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behance makes cool business-oriented notepads for their &amp;ldquo;Action Method&amp;rdquo; concept, which seems sort of like a lightweight GTD for creatives, or more specifically for design meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got my first Behance Action Method notepad from a design director who had no use for it. I use the back side of an action pad for its dot grid. I love the design of both sides and the colors used. The design is thoughtful and elegant. Sometimes I love the dots. Other times I feel like lines work better for me when I&amp;rsquo;m doing more rigid drawing. It&amp;rsquo;s great for sketching and the weight is nice. You can buy a gummed edge notepad drilled for 3 hole binders or a spiral with perforations.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spiral Dot Grid book also looks good. It&amp;rsquo;s got a rigid cover, a squarish shape at 9 x 10.5&amp;rdquo;, and is perforated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can acquire Behance goodness at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.creativesoutfitter.com/&#34;&gt;Behance Outfitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tufte Graph&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I went to Tufte&amp;rsquo;s seminar in 2000, I snatched up a bunch of letter and tabloid notepads. My Tufte paper ran out years ago, except for a single tabloid pad I use on special occassions. I loved the color and weight of the grid lines, and the weight of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edwardtufte.com/tufte/posters&#34;&gt;Get your Tufte on here&lt;/a&gt; by scrolling down to the bottom of the posters page. Guess they couldn&amp;rsquo;t be bothered giving the pads their own page. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the list of past and present loved notepads and notebooks. Would love to hear what you use now, what you&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past, and what you loved or hated about using them in your daily UX work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhodia Drive</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/rhodia-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/rhodia-drive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rhodiadrive.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1308&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4853dfa7b7ddc_0.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rhodiadrive.com/&#34;&gt;Rhodia Drive&lt;/a&gt; is a fantastic blog written by someone named Tedo, a Filipino journalist currently based in Chicago, that is devoted to Rhodia notepads. Tedo posts random stories, artwork and photos from Rhodia lovers around the world. I always carry around a &lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt; x 4.5 Rhodia notepad and traded in my Tufte graph paper for Rhodia a little over a year ago. If you&amp;rsquo;re one of us, check out Rhodia Drive and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/groups/rhodiadrive/&#34;&gt;flickr group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rhodiadrive.com/&#34;&gt;http://rhodiadrive.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>