<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Giveaway on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/giveaway/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Giveaway on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/giveaway/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>&amp;amp;quot;Beautify Your Workspace&amp;amp;quot; Giveaway</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/beautify-your-workspace-giveaway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/beautify-your-workspace-giveaway/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/allmodern-1.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;Konigi is having a &amp;ldquo;Beautify Your Workspace&amp;rdquo; giveaway thanks to the fabulous people at All Modern. What better way to keep producing inspiring work than to create an inspiring workspace, surrounded by the clean and modern design of the lighting and desk accessories we&amp;rsquo;ve chosen for you.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Modern Office Gear&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.allmodern.com/&#34;&gt;All Modern&lt;/a&gt; has a fantastic selection of modern furniture, home décor and lighting from brands like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.allmodern.com/Knoll-%AE-C61166.html&#34;&gt;Knoll&lt;/a&gt;, Herman Miller, Heller and Blu Dot. I love the look and feel of modern and minimalist designed office furniture and desk accessories, and want to share the love with our readers. So we&amp;rsquo;re giving one lucky winner their choice of one of the following items from the George Kovacs or Jack Georges collections.  Due to shipping costs, the contest is limited to participants from the U.S. only. Apologies to those outside the U.S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Desk Lamps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.allmodernlighting.com/George-Kovacs-P231-084-gkv1123.html&#34;&gt;Cubic One Light Table Lamp, by George Kovacs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The Cubic Collection receives its name for its featured cube shaped lamp shade. This contemporary table lamp consists of a slender brushed nickel arm that stands on a base, which complements the shade&amp;rsquo;s shape. The etched cased opal glass shade is the stand-out attribute of this piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.allmodernlighting.com/George-Kovacs-P101-084-gkv1068.html&#34;&gt;Wah-Hoo Pharmacy Lamp, by George Kovacs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This pharmacy lamp is perfect for helping you read or do work, this lamp can be moved into different positions until you find the most comfortable one. The brushed nickel finish and overall shape of this fixture makes it an attractive, minimalist piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Notepad Folios&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot marbot1 martop1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://konigi.s3.amazonaws.com/notebook/allmodern-2.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.allmodern.com/Jack-Georges-2111-JM1112.html&#34;&gt;University Letter Size Writing Pad, by Jack Georges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This letter size writing pad is handcrafted from full-grain, American steer hide leather. It features inside pockets and suede leather lining. Available in Black and Brown. We&amp;rsquo;re giving this away with choice of 1 Konigi Wireframe or Storyboard Notepad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.allmodern.com/Jack-Georges-3111-JM1045.html&#34;&gt;Milano Letter Size Writing Pad with Snap Closure, by Jack Georges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sophisticated yet practical, the Milano Collection is made from Italian leather. These durable, lightweight, and scratch resistant pieces feature unique shapes and functional designs. Available in Black, Blue, Red, Green, Brown, Cherry, Orange, Yellow and Pink. We&amp;rsquo;re giving this away with choice of 1 Konigi Wireframe or Storyboard Notepad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;To participate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To participate, all you have to do is add a comment, and either: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Tell us one thing that inspires you when you design (an idea, a person, a place, a thing), and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AND/OR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) Tell us about a site that inspires you and why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you leave your comment, you must be sure to include a real email address so we can contact you. At the close of the contest, I&amp;rsquo;ll put the total number of comments into a randomizer, which will pull out one number in the range. If your comment number is the one that&amp;rsquo;s pulled, we&amp;rsquo;ll contact you to ask which item you&amp;rsquo;d like and ship you the prize. Again, due to shipping, only &lt;strong&gt;participants inside the U.S. please&lt;/strong&gt;. Only one item will be awarded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contest submission ends on June 30th, 2009 at 11:59 PM, Eastern Time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Update: We have a winner!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;39 entries were submitted. The random number that was generated from 1-39 was 11, which means that Dan Ciupuliga gets to choose one of the items from our list of giveaway items from All Modern. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who entered, and to All Modern for sponsoring this contest. We hope to have another different giveaway for our readers towards the end of the summer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Michael&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>