<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quotes on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/quotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quotes on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/quotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/wiki/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/wiki/quotes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;book-body&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are some of the quotes I&#39;ve collected from artists and designers that have some relevance to doing business in web and software product design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Art and Design Movie Quotes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve made it a habit to try and find documentaries about an art/craft to watch whenever I fly, so it made sense to take notes as I would in my journal and put them up here for inspiration. You&#39;ll find quotes from the following movies here:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc0&#34;&gt;Sound City (2013)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2306745/&#34; title=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2306745/&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2306745/&#34;&gt;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2306745/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://soundcitymovie.com/&#34; title=&#34;http://soundcitymovie.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://soundcitymovie.com/&#34;&gt;http://soundcitymovie.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc1&#34;&gt;Keith Olsen, producer engineer, on the role of the producer.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;He is the vehicle to get the artist&#39;s creativity on the tape in a way that is accessible to the marketplace. What you have to do is get the listener to claim what you&#39;ve done as theirs.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
00:36:18&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc2&#34;&gt;Trent Reznor on digital tools and starting with a message.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Now that everyone is empowered with these great tools to create stuff has there been a lot more great shit coming up? Not really. You have to have something to do with those tools. You should really try to have something to say.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
01:29:00&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc3&#34;&gt;Dave Grohl / James Brown on constraints.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;One of the things that I think makes good music is some sort of restriction. ... That&#39;s where 24 track mentality comes in. You commit to what it is. With Pro Tools you can always come back to it, or you can change it, or you can add to it to try and make it work, because you&#39;re being forced to make choices--creative ones.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc4&#34;&gt;Dave Grohl on creativity.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Do it. Make it simple. Make it fast. Don&#39;t overthink it. Let it come straight out of you and do it.”&lt;br /&gt;
01:33:30&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc5&#34;&gt;Watch:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Sound-City-NEIL-YOUNG/dp/B00B4Z5J92/&#34;&gt;On Amazon Instant Play (free for Prime)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/movies/details/Sound_City?id=MX1A-H_lrTk&#34;&gt;On Google Play&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/movie/sound-city/id587612681&#34;&gt;On iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc6&#34;&gt;Side by Side (2012)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sidebysidethemovie.com/&#34; title=&#34;http://sidebysidethemovie.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sidebysidethemovie.com/&#34;&gt;http://sidebysidethemovie.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2014338/&#34; title=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2014338/&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2014338/&#34;&gt;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2014338/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc7&#34;&gt;Director Danny Boyle on the evolution of movie watching from the movie theater to computer and mobile devices.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You gotta go with it, and if you become unable to deal with it, then thats fine because it means your time is finished and it&#39;s time for othe people to take it on. &lt;br /&gt;
01:22:34&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc8&#34;&gt;Vittorio Storaro, cinematographer on accepting change.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you are participating in the revolution, we will be lost in past. We can’t count ourselves out and say, “We don’t care. It’s up to you guys.” No. So we have to be in.&lt;br /&gt;
01:34:20&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc9&#34;&gt;Michael Ballhause, cinematographer, on creativity and medium.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything comes down to one thing. If you do something with your heart. If you do something you&#39;re convinced of and feel about it, it doesn&#39;t matter what you&#39;re using. &lt;br /&gt;
01:35:43&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc10&#34;&gt;Watch:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Side-Derek-Ambrosi/dp/B0090EJZA8/&#34;&gt;On Amazon Instant Play&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/movies/details/Side_by_Side?id=jxovgnr3ODY&#34;&gt;On Google Play&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/movie/side-by-side/id550069703&#34;&gt;On iTunes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;On Creativity&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Secret to creativity is knowing how to hide your sources.&lt;br /&gt;
–Albert Einstein&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything you can imagine is real.&lt;br /&gt;
–Pablo Picasso&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience is the name everyone gives to their mistakes.&lt;br /&gt;
–Oscar Wilde&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In order to be irreplaceable one must always be different.” &lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://aconversationoncool.tumblr.com/post/556377546/in-order-to-be-irreplaceable-one-must-always-be&#34;&gt;Coco Chanel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just as Steve loved ideas, and loved making stuff, he treated the process of creativity with a rare and a wonderful reverence. You see, I think he better than anyone understood that while ideas ultimately can be so powerful, they begin as fragile, barely formed thoughts, so easily missed, so easily compromised, so easily just squished.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/nPUsuY8JZJI&#34;&gt;Jonathan Ive at the Steve Jobs Tribute&lt;/a&gt; on the Apple campus. His talk starts around 47:17 right after Tim Cook introduces him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d like to talk about the one thing that&#39;s been consistent over the years—the genesis and power of creativity. ... It’s all about how you’re putting what you do together. The elements you’re using don’t matter. Purity of human expression and experience is not confined to guitars, to tubes, to turntables, to microchips. There’s no right way, no pure way of doing it—there’s just doing it.&lt;br /&gt;
– From Bruce Springsteen&#39;s inspiring &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/2012/03/16/148778665/bruce-springsteens-sxsw-2012-keynote-speech&#34;&gt;2012 SXSW Keynote Speech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rumble, young musicians, rumble. Open your ears and open your hearts. Don&#39;t take yourself too seriously, and take yourself as seriously as death itself. Don&#39;t worry. Worry your ass off. Have unclad confidence, but doubt. It keeps you awake and alert. Believe you are the baddest ass in town-and you suck! It keeps you honest. Be able to keep two completely contradictory ideals alive and well inside of your heart and head at all times. If it doesn&#39;t drive you crazy, it will make you strong.  And stay hard, stay hungry and stay alive. And when you walk on stage tonight to bring the noise, treat it like it&#39;s all we have-and then remember it&#39;s only rock &#39;n&#39; roll.&lt;br /&gt;
– From Bruce Springsteen&#39;s inspiring &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/2012/03/16/148778665/bruce-springsteens-sxsw-2012-keynote-speech&#34;&gt;2012 SXSW Keynote Speech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;On Product Design&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good design is as little design as possible. &lt;br /&gt;
-Dieter Rams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simplest way to achieve simplicity is through thoughtful reduction.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://lawsofsimplicity.com/2006/07/23/law-1-reduce-3&#34;&gt;John Maeda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working on the right thing is probably more important than working hard.&lt;br /&gt;
–Caterina Fake&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You spend so much more time to make it less conspicuous, less obvious. And if you think about it, so many of the products we&#39;re surrounded by, they want you to be very aware of just how clever the solution was. &lt;br /&gt;
-Jonathan Ive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we do the job of those 6 parts as one?&lt;br /&gt;
–Jonathan Ive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very important turning point for me was the term &#39;obsessive sketch&#39; by Takama Kyoshi, the haiku master. When the poet&#39;s sentiments are overly visible, the audience may become uncomfortable. By writing simply and only about what is there, the audience is drawn into the poet&#39;s world. Their imagination is stimulated, and a silent connection is established. I believe this is where the most important aspect of the Japanese sense of beauty lies. &lt;br /&gt;
-Naoto Fukasawa&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had to summarize our learnings in three words: &amp;quot;simple trumps complete.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.quora.com/What-types-of-things-does-Netflix-A-B-test-aside-from-member-sign-up&#34;&gt;Neil Hunt on Netflix A-B testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t need every customer. I’m primarily in the business of selling a product for money. How much effort do I really want to devote to satisfying people who are unable or extremely unlikely to pay for anything?…&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marco.org/2011/04/28/removed-instapaper-free&#34;&gt;Marco Arment, Instapaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people argue software should be agnostic. They say it&#39;s arrogant for developers to limit features or ignore feature requests. They say software should always be as flexible as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think that&#39;s bullshit. The best software has a vision. The best software takes sides. When someone uses software, they&#39;re not just looking for features, they&#39;re looking for an approach. They&#39;re looking for a vision. Decide what your vision is and run with it.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://gettingreal.37signals.com/ch04_Make_Opinionated_Software.php&#34;&gt;Jason Fried, Getting Real&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you build an app always look out for the non-essential features. Make sure they don’t make it into your v1.0. They slow down your release, they dilute your focus, they require resources that pull you away from perfecting the core of your app, and they open the door to more bugs at launch.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/archives2/essential_vs_nonessential.php&#34;&gt;Jason Fried&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best designers and the best programmers aren’t the ones with the best skills, or the nimblest fingers, or the ones who can rock and roll with photoshop or vim, they are the ones that can determine what just doesn’t matter. That’s where the real gains are made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time you spend is wasted time on things that just don’t matter. If you can cut out the work and thinking that just doesn’t matter you’ll achieve productivity you’ve never imagined. It’s there if you just don’t pay attention to the things that don’t matter.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/archives2/it_just_doesnt_matter.php&#34;&gt;Jason Fried&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Minimum Viable Product”. MVP, if you aren’t familiar, is an idea from the Lean Startup scene. In a nutshell, it means to do as little as possible so you can learn if you did the right thing or not.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2963-what-happens-to-user-experience-in-a-minimum-viable-product&#34;&gt;Jason Fried&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you know when it&#39;s done? The question is: when is it good enough?&lt;br /&gt;
Good enough, for those that seek perfection, is what we call it when it&#39;s sufficient to surpass the standards we&#39;ve set. Anything beyond good enough is called stalling and a waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&#39;t like your definition of &#39;good enough&#39;, then feel free to change that, but the goal before shipping is merely that. Not perfect.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/06/how-do-you-know-when-its-done.html&#34;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Good design, when done well, should be invisible.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/brainsparks/2008/10/01/uietips-communicate-quick/&#34;&gt;Jared Spool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;So much complexity in software comes from trying to make one thing do two things.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/2316-so-much-complexity-in-software-comes-from&#34;&gt;Ryan Singer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;When the form changes, so does the underlying business model, which of course changes the function as well. … The question that gets asked about technology, the one that is almost always precisely the wrong question is, &amp;quot;How does this advance help our business?&amp;quot; The correct question is, &amp;quot;how does this advance undermine our business model and require us/enable us to build a new one?&amp;quot; … When a change in form comes to your industry, the first thing to discover is how it will change the function.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/10/form-and-function.html&#34;&gt;Seth Godin on how to react to change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;When discussing any product, technology, or idea, it’s easy to focus only on its value, what problem it is trying to solve for the user. This is a good start, and has historically been the only consideration. Recently however, people have started to realize that it also has to be well designed; it can’t be painful to use. &lt;br /&gt;
…&lt;br /&gt;
What’s most important is their relationship: as long as value is greater than pain, you’ll be ok.&lt;br /&gt;
…&lt;br /&gt;
Just because value &amp;gt; pain doesn’t mean that you’re done, it just means that it’s good enough to ship.&lt;br /&gt;
…&lt;br /&gt;
As pain goes down, people will use a product more often for less valuable tasks. Value is still &amp;gt; pain but now it takes much less value to trigger usage. … [R]educing pain, not improving the value of a product in any way, can significantly affect usage.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://designmind.frogdesign.com/blog/mobile-apps-must-die.html&#34;&gt;Scott Jenson on Mobile Apps and value versus pain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Making something obvious has a cost. You can’t make everything obvious because you have limited resources. I’m not talking money–although that may be part of it too. I’m primarily talking screen real estate, attention span, comprehension, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making something obvious is expensive because it often means you have to make a whole bunch of other things less obvious. Obvious dominates and only one thing can truly dominate at a time. It may be worth it to make that one thing completely obvious, but it’s still expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obvious is all about always. The thing(s) people do all the time, the always stuff, should be obvious. The core, the epicenter, the essence of the product should be obvious.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3047-the-obvious-the-easy-and-the-possible&#34;&gt;Jason Fried on designing The Obvious, the Easy, and the Possible&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;If we limit ourselves to what we envision at the outset, we&#39;ll miss opportunity. If we had stopped at what the Wright Brothers could envision, we wouldn&#39;t have gotten very far.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(In 1910, Wilbur Wright didn&#39;t believe planes would be able to carry large numbers of people as trains did, or would be ever able to carry freight. The first air cargo was in 1913.)&lt;br /&gt;
–Brock Rumor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there’s a benefit to being one of six people that no one knew. No VCs would return our calls and we were broke and bootstrapping it and operating under the radar so we could focus on the most important things: the product, the users, what we were building. There’s all this noise, the tech-crunch, which you have to tune out if you want to build a good product. None of that stuff is additive; it all takes away from building a product.&lt;br /&gt;
-Caterina Fake on developing in obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are not embarrassed by the first version of your product, you’ve launched too late.&lt;br /&gt;
-Reid Hoffman, quoted in Mark Goldenson’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://venturebeat.com/2009/04/29/10-lessons-from-a-failed-startup/&#34;&gt;10 lessons from a failed startup&lt;/a&gt;, found &lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/1718-if-you-review-your-first-site-version-and&#34;&gt;via svn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any intelligent fool can make things bigger, more complex, and more violent. It takes a touch of genius–and a lot of courage–to move in the opposite direction.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://rescomp.stanford.edu/~cheshire/EinsteinQuotes.html&#34;&gt;Albert Einstein&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designers prune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Left to its own devices, the mob will augment, accessorize, spam, degrade and noisify whatever they have access to, until it loses beauty and function and becomes something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tragedy of the design commons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems democratic and non-elitist to set it and forget it and let the users take over. But the tools we use (Wikipedia) and the brands we covet (Nike or Ducati) resolutely refuse to become democracies.&lt;br /&gt;
-&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/08/a-tacky-mess-the-masses-vs-great-design.html&#34;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to get people to do what you want them to do is to start with people who want what you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identify, organize and excite people who are already predisposed to achieve what you had in mind and you&#39;re much more likely to have the outcome you seek. It&#39;s far easier (but less compelling) than turning strangers or enemies into customers/voters/supporters/colleagues. Over time, an engaged and motivated base of followers is the single best way to earn more followers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You used to be stuck with whoever walked in the door or opened your mail. Today, you change minds indirectly, by building a tribe that influences via connections to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/10/the-easiest-way-to-get-people-to-do-what-you-want-them-to-do.html&#34;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;On Running a Design Business&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;My model for business is The Beatles: They were four guys that kept each other&#39;s negative tendencies in check; they balanced each other. And the total was greater than the sum of the parts. Great things in business are not done by one person, they are done by a team of people.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
–Steve Jobs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insulate yourself…&lt;br /&gt;
from anonymous angry people&lt;br /&gt;
Expose yourself to art you don&#39;t yet understand&lt;br /&gt;
Precisely measure the results that are important to you&lt;br /&gt;
Stay blind to the metrics that don&#39;t matter&lt;br /&gt;
Fail often&lt;br /&gt;
Ship&lt;br /&gt;
Lead, don&#39;t manage so much&lt;br /&gt;
Seek out uncomfortable situations&lt;br /&gt;
Make an impact on the people who matter to you&lt;br /&gt;
Be better at your baseline skills than anyone else&lt;br /&gt;
Copyedit less, invent more&lt;br /&gt;
Give more speeches&lt;br /&gt;
Ignore unsolicited advice&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/12/insulate-yourself.html&#34;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two elements of successful leadership: a willingness to be wrong and an eagerness to admit it.&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/01/i-was-wrong.html&#34;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;80 percent of success is just showing up.&lt;br /&gt;
–Woody Allen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are what we repeatedly do. Excellence, therefore, is not an act, but a habit.&lt;br /&gt;
-Aristotle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my walks, every man I meet is my superior in some way, and in that I learn from him.&lt;br /&gt;
-Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wisdom from a dog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wisdom-dog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wisdom-dog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://society6.com/MAKE141/Wisdom-from-a-dog&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/snaps/jakewisdom.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a good bit of advice for kids and adults alike from Jake the Dog. Adventure Time is my son&#39;s favorite show, and one of mine as well. I made the print for his birthday, and will put it on of our walls. I like having the reminder every time I feel discouraged when starting something new. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the extended version &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/vrBWJLC22mE&#34;&gt;on YouTube&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://society6.com/MAKE141/Wisdom-from-a-dog&#34;&gt;purchase a print at Society6&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The tragedy of the design commons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tragedy-design-commons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/tragedy-design-commons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Designers prune. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left to its own devices, the mob will augment, accessorize, spam, degrade and noisify whatever they have access to, until it loses beauty and function and becomes something else. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems democratic and non-elitist to set it and forget it and let the users take over. But the tools we use (Wikipedia) and the brands we covet (Nike or Ducati) resolutely refuse to become democracies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2012/08/a-tacky-mess-the-masses-vs-great-design.html&#34;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: @brennen &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/brennen/status/240305510711164928&#34;&gt;takes issue&lt;/a&gt; with the Wikipedia example when it comes to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mediawiki.org/wiki/Manual:MediaWiki_feature_list&#34;&gt;feature selection&lt;/a&gt;, and convinced me that it&amp;rsquo;s not the best example to make. Although I think maybe the point is that Mediawiki implementation on Wikipedia is controlled, but whether or not the decisions about what is used in Wikipedia is democratic or not, I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jack White on Constraints</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/jack-white-constraints/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/jack-white-constraints/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;t14&#34;&gt;Telling yourself, “Oh, you have all the time in the world, you have all the money in the world, you have all the colors in the palette you want, anything you want,” I mean, that just kills creativity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;#8212;Jack White&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was going through the parts I had highlighted in my Kindle version of Austin Kleon&#39;s book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.austinkleon.com/steal/&#34;&gt;Steal Like An Artist,&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and I keep thinking of how much I like this quote from musician Jack White, talking about using constraints to stay creative. I think about how much constraints and removal of the unnecessary makes a difference in helping flow in the tools I use as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quote was actually taken from an interview of White that you can watch in the documentary &lt;em&gt;Under Great White Northern Lights&lt;/em&gt;. There&#39;s an extended except in the Makin&#39; Ads blog &lt;a href=&#34;http://makinads.blogspot.com/2010/04/jack-white-on-creativity.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/fDl-if5Du70?t=1m26s&#34;&gt;watch a video clip on YouTube here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your app is a collection of tiny details</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/your-app-collection-tiny-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/your-app-collection-tiny-details/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;t14&#34;&gt;&#34;Getting the details right is the difference between something that delights, and something customers tolerate.&#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;#8212;Jeff Atwood&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/05/this-is-all-your-app-is-a-collection-of-tiny-details.html&#34;&gt;Jeff Atwood&#39;s article about cat feeders&lt;/a&gt; right away, because it really is 90% about a cat product. It&#39;s also a terrific demonstration of what he&#39;s saying above. The first version of the product, a cat feeder, served a core need well enough for him to &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satisficing&#34;&gt;satisfice&lt;/a&gt; with its shortcomings because the net return in time savings and improved quality of life, for him anyway, was absolutely worth it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The punchline is this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure you&#39;re first getting the primary function more or less right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the work of listening to users every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refine the details of your product based on their feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening to the opinions expressed by customers, obsessing over the details, and getting them right in the design is necessary and hard. But over time, if the points of pain are incrementally addressed and the design improved, the collection of those well-thought-out details embody a better experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get better slowly, but &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; get better. Suck it up and feel your users&#39; pain. Assure them that you&#39;re listening by sweating the details. &lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/05/this-is-all-your-app-is-a-collection-of-tiny-details.html&#34;&gt;http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/05/this-is-all-your-app-is-a-collection-of-tiny-details.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bruce Springsteen on Creativity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/bruce-springsteen-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/bruce-springsteen-creativity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;I&#39;d like to talk about the one thing that&#39;s been consistent over the years—the genesis and power of creativity. ... It’s all about how you’re putting what you do together. The elements you’re using don’t matter. Purity of human expression and experience is not confined to guitars, to tubes, to turntables, to microchips. There’s no right way, no pure way of doing it—there’s just doing it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Bruce Springsteen&#39;s inspiring &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/2012/03/16/148778665/bruce-springsteens-sxsw-2012-keynote-speech&#34;&gt;2012 SXSW Keynote Speech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/2012/03/16/148778665/bruce-springsteens-sxsw-2012-keynote-speech&#34;&gt;http://www.npr.org/2012/03/16/148778665/bruce-springsteens-sxsw-2012-keynote-speech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teddy on haters</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/teddy-on-haters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/teddy-on-haters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/teddyhaters.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the doers who do. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never read Theodore Roosevelt&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Citizenship_in_a_Republic&#34;&gt;Citizenship in a Republic/Man in the Arena&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; speech before hearing it in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://blip.tv/business-of-software/business-of-software-2011-what-happened-the-short-version-5960533&#34;&gt;BoS2011&lt;/a&gt; recap video. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is not the critic who counts; not the man who points out how the strong man stumbles, or where the doer of deeds could have done them better. The credit belongs to the man who is actually in the arena, whose face is marred by dust and sweat and blood; who strives valiantly; who errs, who comes short again and again, because there is no effort without error and shortcoming; but who does actually strive to do the deeds; who knows great enthusiasms, the great devotions; who spends himself in a worthy cause; who at the best knows in the end the triumph of high achievement, and who at the worst, if he fails, at least fails while daring greatly, so that his place shall never be with those cold and timid souls who neither know victory nor defeat.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m seeing him with his pince nez saying, &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not the critic who counts,&amp;rdquo; and thinking, even Roosevelt agrees, &amp;ldquo;haters gonna hate.&amp;rdquo; I think that&amp;rsquo;s a good reminder to every one of us showing up every day, trying, failing, and succeeding, despite the obstacles, critics, haters, etc. But don&amp;rsquo;t take it from me. Teddy told you so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design is the fundamental soul of a human-made creation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/design-fundamental-soul-human-made-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/design-fundamental-soul-human-made-creation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/apple1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Apple I&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://adam-pritzker.com/post/11099896089/in-most-peoples-vocabularies-design-means&#34;&gt;Adam Pritzker&lt;/a&gt; deftly combined this image of an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_I&#34;&gt;Apple I&lt;/a&gt; and this &lt;a href=&#34;http://money.cnn.com/magazines/fortune/fortune_archive/2000/01/24/272277/&#34;&gt;Steve Jobs quote on design&lt;/a&gt; from an interview in 2000 that appeared in Fortune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In most people’s vocabularies, design means veneer. It’s interior decorating. It’s the fabric of the curtains of the sofa. But to me, nothing could be further from the meaning of design. Design is the fundamental soul of a human-made creation that ends up expressing itself in successive outer layers of the product or service.” - Steve Jobs&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an expression of that soul of the creator, in the running failures and successes of the executed design, that attempts to make a connection with the user of the product. Some products are imbued with the soul of a passionate creative force, others become refined to the point of feeling somber. Underneath the surface of Apple products, there&amp;rsquo;s always been a sense of human connection, either in the literal early smiley Mac icons, or in the more polished and subtle interactions and connections we have with machines using our touch screens today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no way to understate how much Apple products have influenced what I do every day. I learned Basic and how to type in high shool on an Apple II. I played Tetris for the first time on a friend&amp;rsquo;s original beige Mac. The first computer I ever spent my own money on was a PowerBook 520c, the very one I learned HTML on. With each successive generation of polish, in every one of these machines I&amp;rsquo;ve touched, I&amp;rsquo;ve always felt that connection, and that desire to want to play with computers. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be doing what I do now if Jobs&amp;rsquo; Mac never existed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every product starts somewhere, but as with people, the soul is what sustains the connection. It&amp;rsquo;s heartening and inspiring to me to think back on this legacy of product design and where it started. It makes me feel like every naive notion I have about design is OK as long as I have a passion to improve and deliver something with soul.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seth Godin on the Importance of Domain Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/seth-godin-importance-domain-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/seth-godin-importance-domain-knowledge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seth Godin&#39;s blog often talks about where successful ideas come from, and in this post talks about &lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/08/bypassing-the-leap.html&#34;&gt;bypassing the need to make huge leaps in innovation&lt;/a&gt; by synthesizing what we know and have learned from history, using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.appleinsider.com/articles/10/01/09/palm_ceo_former_apple_exec_says_hes_never_used_an_iphone.html&#34;&gt;Palm as the cautionary tale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;It&#39;s not enough to be aware of the domain you&#39;re working in, you need to understand it. Noticing things and being curious about how they work is the single most common trait I see in creative people. Once you can break the components down, you can put them back together into something brand new.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why we are constantly doing competitive monitoring and analysis of the products in the industries we work in. At times I feel kind of crazed signing up for betas out there, because the speed at which they appear now is overwhelming. I just have to remind myself that it&#39;s ok to spend the time if there&#39;s some research value, and then quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether we&#39;re just looking at the landscape from a high level, or deeply investigating and deconstructing how things work, continually expanding or improving domain knowledge is always going to be an important activity for us as designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/08/bypassing-the-leap.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Fsethsmainblog+%28Seth%27s+Blog%29&#34;&gt;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/seths_blog/2011/08/bypassing-the-leap.html?utm_source=feedburner&amp;utm_medium=feed&amp;utm_campaign=Feed%3A+typepad%2Fsethsmainblog+%28Seth%27s+Blog%29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Steve Jobs on Saying No</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/steve-jobs-saying-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/steve-jobs-saying-no/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;“People think focus means saying yes to the thing you’ve got to focus on.  But that’s not what it means at all.  It means saying no to the hundred other good ideas that there are. You have to pick carefully.  I’m actually as proud of the things we haven’t done as the things I have done.  Innovation is saying ‘no’ to 1,000 things.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;Steve Jobs on product development, from &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.forbes.com/carminegallo/2011/05/16/steve-jobs-get-rid-of-the-crappy-stuff/&#34;&gt;Steve Jobs: Get Rid of the Crappy Stuff&lt;/a&gt;&#34; in Forbes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gallo exaggerates a little, but I like the point he tries to argue later in the article about focus and reduction. It takes courage to reduce and say no, and that is a big differentiator when it comes to Apple hardware and software. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple is the easy example, but for good reason. Many argue that hindsight analysis of Jobs&#39; strategy might be easy, but the company&#39;s success in product development continues to provide lessons to learn. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of knowing when to say no seems obvious and is something you might say is always top of mind. But, if you&#39;re working on a product, you&#39;re likely to be challenged every day with decisions to say yes or no to the possible products you might design, and the features you might build into your products. Every one of these challenges requires courage to say no if the outcome compromises your vision, because in the moment it will seem like the world is begging for you to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know as a user of different products, I&#39;ve been vocal about the pet features I&#39;ve wanted as a &#34;power user&#34; of said products, and bitched when that voice didn&#39;t get heard. But I believe that the tech products that I continue to use and that are of value are those that hold onto a clearly defined vision and purpose, and whose features reflect that with selectivity and refusal to deviate from it. More often than not, to me, these products have provided a more focussed experience. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.core77.com/blog/object_culture/carmine_gallo_on_the_root_of_apples_less-is-more_philosophy_19407&#34;&gt;Core77&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.forbes.com/carminegallo/2011/05/16/steve-jobs-get-rid-of-the-crappy-stuff/&#34;&gt;http://blogs.forbes.com/carminegallo/2011/05/16/steve-jobs-get-rid-of-the-crappy-stuff/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Invest in Sketching?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/why-invest-sketching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/why-invest-sketching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;Jumping in and immediately starting to build the product, even if it does get completed and ship, is almost guaranteed to produce a mediocre product in which there is little innovation or market differentiation. When you have only one kick at the can, the behaviour of the entire team and process is as predictable as it will be pedestrian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;Bill Buxton in &lt;em&gt;Sketching the User Experience&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Buxton writes in this passage on the impact of iterative sketching on risk, exploration and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The more you know, the less you need.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/more-you-know-less-you-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/more-you-know-less-you-need/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;“The more you know, the less you need. The experienced fly fisherman with only one rod, one type of fly, and one type of line will always outfish the duffer with an entire quiver of gear and flies. I never forget Thoreau&#39;s advice: &#39;I say beware of all enterprises that require new clothes...&#39;&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;Yvon Chouinard in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Let-People-Surfing-Education-Businessman/dp/0143037838&#34;&gt;Let My People Go Surfing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Chouinard is a mountain climber, environmentalist, and founder of Patagonia. He was writing about product design in the quote above. &lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ed Parker on Competition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ed-parker-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ed-parker-competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;&#34;It is always better to improve and strengthen your own line or knowledge than to try and cut your opponent&#39;s line.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;Ed Parker, Martial Arts Instructor and Author&lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debussy on White Space</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/debussy-white-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/debussy-white-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;&#34;Music is the space between the notes.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;Claude Debussy, as quoted in Turning Numbers into Knowledge (2001) by Johnathan G. Koomey&lt;/p&gt;
    
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensible Defaults</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/sensible-defaults/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/sensible-defaults/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;dek&#34;&gt;&#34;Sensible defaults can reduce friction and provide simplicity anywhere one can think to apply them. They are the bedrock of minimalist practice and a quiet mind.&#34;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8212;Patrick Rhone&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://patrickrhone.com/2010/11/08/sensible-defaults/&#34;&gt;http://patrickrhone.com/2010/11/08/sensible-defaults/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>