<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beta on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/beta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beta on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/beta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Twingr Registration: My mind was made up before I even tried the product</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/twingr-registration-my-mind-was-made-i-even-tried-product/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/twingr-registration-my-mind-was-made-i-even-tried-product/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twingr.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1403&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt491deb743c162.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I very rarely will say anything about a site if the only opinion I have is negative. &lt;a href=&#34;http://twingr.com/&#34;&gt;Twingr&lt;/a&gt; looked like an interesting idea. The service let&amp;rsquo;s you create your own Twitter-clone microblogging site, as does Yammer, but without any constraints regarding who you may invite. Alas, I can&amp;rsquo;t say that I know what the experience is like because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get past the front door, so I walked away possibly never to return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;rsquo;s the criticism, and my advice for how not to run a product alpha/beta. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Don&amp;rsquo;t put a very prominent form to create an account on your front page if this is what you happens when you submit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-image&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://s3.amazonaws.com/konigi/notebook/twingr.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) Don&amp;rsquo;t make a second create button on the page (see bottom of the first screenshot) that does nothing when you click it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3) Don&amp;rsquo;t do all the above, blocking people from registering, and then leave out a sign up for beta form to remind prospective customers to come back. I won&amp;rsquo;t remember ever hearing about this site and probably won&amp;rsquo;t likely be back if not reminded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First impressions matter, and I know it can be very difficult to recover from a bad first impression with a product. If I were these guys, I would make those few fixes real fast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twingr.com/&#34;&gt;http://twingr.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>