<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Screen Capture on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/screen-capture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Screen Capture on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/screen-capture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Alfred/Hazel Workflow for Screen Capture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/alfredhazel-workflow-screen-capture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/alfredhazel-workflow-screen-capture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you take a lot of screenshots on a Mac like me, you probably have a good workflow for doing it using something like &lt;a href=&#34;http://realmacsoftware.com/ember&#34;&gt;LittleSnapper/Ember&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/awesome-screenshot-captur/alelhddbbhepgpmgidjdcjakblofbmce?hl=en&#34;&gt;Awesome Screenshot&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://evernote.com/skitch/&#34;&gt;Skitch&lt;/a&gt;. The biggest problem I&#39;ve had is that after I take a screenshot, I often want to do something with it. I can do this by just getting &lt;a href=&#34;http://getcloudapp.com/&#34;&gt;Cloud&lt;/a&gt; to watch and upload files passively, but I&#39;ve always wanted to save to my own server after just issuing one command to capture the page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love Alfred. Launchers like Quicksilver and Alfred are what I think of as the best minimal UI apps that I use on the Mac. I finally got around to searching for a way to capture a full scrolling screen from it and do something with the output. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alfredforum.com/topic/2062-scrennshot-of-web-pages/&#34;&gt;excellent Alfred workflow&lt;/a&gt; by user moom on the Alfred Forum that uses a shell script to run &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paulhammond.org/webkit2png/&#34;&gt;Webkit2Png&lt;/a&gt; in the background. It&#39;s awesome. I just copy the URL of the page I&#39;m on, summon Alfred with a few keystrokes, and then it gets captured, optimized, and uploaded to my server in the background. I made a video of the workflow showing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alfredapp.com/&#34;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.noodlesoft.com/hazel.php&#34;&gt;Hazel&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://imageoptim.com/&#34;&gt;ImageOptim&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://panic.com/transmit/&#34;&gt;Transmit&lt;/a&gt; working together with lots of spit and chewing gum in case anyone else has this need. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/72290954?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&#34; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s a lot of steps to set up, but if you have this need, you&#39;ll appreciate it. ;) You can modify the steps for your workflow to move it to note in Evernote, to Cloud, or wherever your heart desires. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.alfredforum.com/topic/2062-scrennshot-of-web-pages/&#34;&gt;Download the workflow here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re interested to know how I modified the workflow, these are the options I used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote style=&#34;font-style: normal&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;python webkit2png -F -W 980 --delay=5 &#34;$(pbpaste)&#34;&lt;br /&gt;
ls *.png | grep -v icon.png |&lt;br /&gt;
xargs -I {} mv {} ${HOME}/Sites/media.konigi.com/snaps/2013/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-F -W 980 outputs a full scrolling screen at 980px wide. You can see what the options are by running this command in the terminal: webkit2png --help.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/72290954&#34;&gt;https://vimeo.com/72290954&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bounce: Screenshot annotation service</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/bounce-screenshot-annotation-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/bounce-screenshot-annotation-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bounceapp.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2758&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt5230577a698ad_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bounceapp.com/&#34;&gt;Bounce&lt;/a&gt; is a new screen capture service from Zurb that lets you invite other collaborators to annotate screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bounceapp.com/posts/new?screen_id=8215&#34;&gt;test page of Konigi&lt;/a&gt; for you to defile, er, test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bounceapp.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.bounceapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screenr Screencasting Service</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/screenr-screencasting-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/screenr-screencasting-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://screenr.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2694&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt522fc4474a4aa_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://screenr.com/&#34;&gt;Screenr&lt;/a&gt; is a web-based screen capture tool that lets you record screen video and audio from your Mac or PC and posts a link to the video, hosted on Screenr.com, to your Twitter stream.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://screenr.com/&#34;&gt;http://screenr.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camtasia for Mac</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/camtasia-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/camtasia-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techsmith.com/camtasiamac/default.asp&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2684&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt522fb24ce0713_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;TechSmith, makers of Morae and Snagit, have released a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techsmith.com/camtasiamac/default.asp&#34;&gt;Mac version of Camtasia&lt;/a&gt;, the screencast video recording software. The software allows you to capture the screen, audio and iSight input, and provides simple drag and drop editing including a lot of built-in transitions and effects. You can then easily export the HTML and SWF for embedding in a web page. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looks like an easy to use alternative that might take the work out of producing screencasts. The video suggests that TechSmith have really thought about the primary demo and training use cases.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techsmith.com/camtasiamac/default.asp&#34;&gt;http://www.techsmith.com/camtasiamac/default.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clixpy.com Click Path Tracking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/clixpycom-click-path-tracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/clixpycom-click-path-tracking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://clixpy.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2768&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt52307896a41d5_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clixpy is a service that tracks everything your site’s users do, from mouse movement, clicks, and scrolling, to form inputs. The user sessions are as video for you to analyze. Installation requires pasting a few lines of JavaScript into your pages. Check out their excellent &lt;a href=&#34;http://clixpy.com/demo&#34;&gt;demo&lt;/a&gt; to see how it works.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://clixpy.com/&#34;&gt;http://clixpy.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>userfly: Instant web-based usability testing service</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/userfly-instant-web-based-usability-testing-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/userfly-instant-web-based-usability-testing-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;460&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=2451370&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=2451370&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;460&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/2451370&#34;&gt;userfly.com&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/user930239&#34;&gt;Chris Estreich&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://userfly.com/&#34;&gt;Userfly&lt;/a&gt; is a new web-based usability testing service that looks pretty exciting. When you set up a new test on the service, you&amp;rsquo;re given JavaScript to enter into your site template. Userfly captures sessions including link clicks and time spent on the page, and records screen events including mouse movement and keystrokes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This looks like a pretty nice service for certain types of observation. There doesn&amp;rsquo;t appear to be any options for interacting with users, e.g. video/audio capture, task marking. I suppose on a siloed test server you could drive test session tasks and do an additional recording via other software. But at that point, you might as well go a more traditional route using web-based methods. But this should definitely be useful for some testing needs. Would love to hear more about people&amp;rsquo;s experiences with this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://userfly.com/&#34;&gt;http://userfly.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Layers App Creates Layered PSDs from Screen Captures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/layers-app-creates-layered-psds-screen-captures/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/submissions/layers-app-creates-layered-psds-screen-captures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://layersapp.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2748&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt52303e0e9aa33_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just when you thought there couldn&amp;rsquo;t be a way to improve the screencapture app space, &lt;a href=&#34;http://layersapp.com/&#34;&gt;Layers&lt;/a&gt; hits the net. Layers for the Mac, captures your displays as a Photoshop layered image. Press the capture hotkey or customize your capture in the inspector and you&amp;rsquo;ll obtain a full fledged PSD file with one layer per window, including menu and desktop icons, dock and menubar. Sweetness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/davidkaneda/status/1137150372&#34;&gt;@davidkaneda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://layersapp.com/&#34;&gt;http://layersapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Screenshot Utilities You Should Know About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/6-screenshot-utilities-you-should-know-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/6-screenshot-utilities-you-should-know-about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/2452008412/&#34; title=&#34;Screenshot Utilities You Should Know About by jibbajabba, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2136/2452008412_20087047d9_b.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot Utilities You Should Know About&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use different screen capture utilities depending on the type of screen I&amp;rsquo;m trying to grab. Some are great for a quick and dirty capture of a page I want to send someone. Others are good for annotating an interface I want to post to a web page. And still others are best for archival screen capture or for interfaces with video. Below are the 6 screenshot utilities that Mac users should know about. Don&amp;rsquo;t skip over the first one, because there&amp;rsquo;s a tip in there you might not be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/pro/tips/secretcapture.html&#34;&gt;Apple Screen Capture (Mac)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The built in screen capture tools provided by the Mac allow you to capture full screen (Command-Shift-3) or portions of screens (Command-Shift-4). The PNG images are then placed on your desktop named as Picture-1, etc. Adding Control (Control-Command-Shift-4 or 3) places the screenshot in your clipboard so you can paste right into Photoshop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.skitch.com/&#34;&gt;Skitch (Mac, free)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Skitch is an excellent screen capture tool from Plasque, the makers of Comic Life. The tool provided a twitchy interface for quickly capturing screens, annotating, and uploading to a photo site like Flickr, to it&amp;rsquo;s image portal, or to your FTP directory. This tool is easy to use, and I would argue provides greater flexibility and control than Apple&amp;rsquo;s built in tools in terms of file naming, screen selection, and editing. The only downside of this tool is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t capture complete windows requiring a scroll below the fold. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jingproject.com/&#34;&gt;Jing (Windows and Mac, free)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Jing is a screen capture utility from Techsmith, the makers of PC screen capture  tool SnagIt, and video capture tool Camtasia. The tool copies the simple flow that makes Skitch so succesful, but adds video capture (exported as Flash/SWF) to the mix. As with Skitch, Jing doesn&amp;rsquo;t capture complete scrolling windows. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.screengrab.org/&#34;&gt;Screengrab for Firefox (Windows and Mac, free)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If you use Firefox, Screengrab is a handy extension that makes it easy to save or copy (to clipboard) a complete web page, a selection, or only visible portions of the browser window. A small icon is installed in the status bar of your browser, so whenever you see a page you want to grab, you can select your save/copy options, and the directory where you want the PNG to go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tribalmedia.com/bts/SnapWeb/SnapWeb.html&#34;&gt;SnapWeb (Mac, Commercial)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
SnapWeb is a tool I&amp;rsquo;ve used for several years to grab complete pages including content below the fold. This is essentially a slimmed down browser that give you a lot of control over how you&amp;rsquo;re saving files&amp;#8212;you choose from multiple formats, browser dimensions, and file naming preferences. It takes a few more steps to use this tool, but it&amp;rsquo;s proven the most effective at grabbing trickier Flash sites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tastyapps.com/&#34;&gt;Tasty Apps&amp;rsquo; Web Snapper (Mac, Commercial)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Web Snapper is a nice tool you can use with Safari that allows you to queue up screens you want to capture, and either save off one at a time, or using the Web Snapper window. The application allows you to capture pages in their currently viewed state so you can snap DHTML layers or Flash elements. One very nice feature is that you can save off all those screenshots into a multi-paged PDF. Love it. To trigger the capture so you can capture interactive elements on hover, you can invoke the keyboard shortcut Command-Shift-E.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, a supporting cast member&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.johnhaney.com/backdrop/&#34;&gt;Backdrop (Mac, free)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Jing and Skitch will take screencaptures of individual windows (on Skitch, use CMD-Shift-5 and click the window) and put them on a white background. But if you want to capture several windows, you probably want a clean background. Backdrop is an application that simply fills the background with solid white.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://realmacsoftware.com/littlesnapper/&#34;&gt;Little Snapper&lt;/a&gt; from Realmac Software came onto the scene, and now I can recommend this above all the others. Aside from my Firefox Screengrab utility, this one is turning out to be the most useful to me because it lets me organize and tag my screenshots in the desktop software, and save them to the online QuickSnapper service. Excellent piece of software and well worth the $40.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>