<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Storyboards on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/storyboards/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Storyboards on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/storyboards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Ridley Scott Demystifies the Art of Storyboarding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ridley-scott-demystifies-art-storyboarding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/ridley-scott-demystifies-art-storyboarding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/tifrKC8P3XM&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ridley Scott, director of Alien and Blade Runner, talks about the importance of fast thumbnail sketching and storyboards in helping him make movies. Scott discusses how storyboards help him capture the imagery of scenes, and how talking through storyboards prepare the creative team by establishing a direction for what they intend to create. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openculture.com/2012/05/ridley_scott_demystifies_the_art_of_storyboarding.html&#34;&gt;Read more at the article on Open Culture&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Via Ian Smile.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openculture.com/2012/05/ridley_scott_demystifies_the_art_of_storyboarding.html&#34;&gt;http://www.openculture.com/2012/05/ridley_scott_demystifies_the_art_of_storyboarding.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhotoSketch Storyboard Application</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/photosketch-storyboard-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/photosketch-storyboard-application/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video&#34;&gt;
&lt;object width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;458&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowscriptaccess&#34; value=&#34;always&#34; /&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=6496886&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=00ADEF&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; /&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=6496886&amp;amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;amp;show_title=1&amp;amp;show_byline=1&amp;amp;show_portrait=0&amp;amp;color=00ADEF&amp;amp;fullscreen=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; allowscriptaccess=&#34;always&#34; width=&#34;610&#34; height=&#34;458&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PhotoSketch is an online tool created by five students from Tsinghua University in China and the National University of Singapore. It creates storyboards from sketches by finding &amp;amp; stitching background images &amp;amp; item layers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;We present a system that composes a realistic picture from a simple freehand sketch annotated with text labels. The composed picture is generated by seamlessly stitching several photographs in agreement&lt;br /&gt;
with the sketch and text labels; these are found by searching the Internet. Although online image search generates many inappropriate results, our system is able to automatically select suitable photographs to generate a high quality composition, using a filtering scheme to exclude undesirable images. We also provide a novel image blending algorithm to allow seamless image composition. Each blending result is given a numeric score, allowing us to find an optimal combination of discovered images. Experimental results&lt;br /&gt;
show the method is very successful; we also evaluate our system using the results from two user studies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.creativereview.co.uk/cr-blog/2009/october/photosketch&#34;&gt;Creative Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.creativereview.co.uk/cr-blog/2009/october/photosketch&#34;&gt;http://www.creativereview.co.uk/cr-blog/2009/october/photosketch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireframe and Storyboard Notepads are Back: Now sold via Amazon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-and-storyboard-notepads-are-back-now-sold-amazon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/wireframe-and-storyboard-notepads-are-back-now-sold-amazon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/paper-products?q=store/paper-products&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1589&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt49fb0a11193d7.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/paper-products?q=store/paper-products&#34;&gt;Wireframe and Storyboard notepads&lt;/a&gt; have been reprinted and are now selling exclusively via Amazon.com. The good news is, now that you ordered via Amazon, your order may qualify for Free Super Saver Shipping, and may be combined with other Amazon purchases in your cart. So if you spend $25 at Amazon, even by combining your purchase with other qualified products fulfilled via Amazon, your shipping will be free. Yay, you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more info about the note pads, &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/paper-products?q=store/paper-products&#34;&gt;see the product pages in the store&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/paper-products?q=store/paper-products&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store/paper-products&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Gmail Client Wireframe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/better-gmail-client-wireframe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/better-gmail-client-wireframe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/bettergmail.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I posted on Twitter about how frustrating it can be to have to use email. With every day that I use Twitter via Twhirl I become less and less interested in using email. So I moaned to my Twitter peeps about the pain I feel. Some people wanted to know what I wanted, so I responded with the ideal flow, using Mac OS X&amp;rsquo;s Growl alerting app as the starting point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Growl alert. Click and a Quicksilver-like diaogue appears. Click. Reply. Done. Gmail archives. Optionally tag the thread.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, I&amp;rsquo;ve been designing a feature on the product I&amp;rsquo;m working on that does something like this. We have a plugin for our app, a CMS, that turns a project into a Twitter-like micromessaging application. It&amp;rsquo;s only in release 0.1, but I&amp;rsquo;ve designed a few iterations ahead, which we plan to review. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gist for me is this. At work we use Jabber to get alerts for new activity on our internal CMS. We use our Live Blog micromessaging project to do status updates, and other discussion in real time. We want something as easy as IM, as easy as Twitter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing all this stuff that makes the stream of messaging easy to respond to when I see something urgent that needs attention. And I begin to notice email differently, and think that it&amp;rsquo;s a big speed bumps in the day when I have to look at it. There are some messages that come in that I wish I could just quickly reply to because they&amp;rsquo;re urgent. But I hate having to load Gmail or Mail.app to stop what I&amp;rsquo;m doing.     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I know with added intrusions into your day, this could add to your already full, multi-tasking life. But I simply feel like I want and need it. I want email on my terms until it goes away. So I took some of the ideas I was working on in a project I&amp;rsquo;m doing and saw how those behaviors might apply to email. The wireframe you see above is part of that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve posted the files below so you can look at this single page storyboard if you&amp;rsquo;re curious. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in taking a peek at how I wireframe, download the OmniGraffle document too and play with it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download the files&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can view this wireframe as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/wireframes/BetterGmail-large.png&#34;&gt;full-sized PNG&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/wireframes/BetterGmail.pdf&#34;&gt;download as PDF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may also download the &lt;a href=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/wireframes/BetterGmail.graffle.zip&#34;&gt;OmniGraffle file&lt;/a&gt; to see how this wireframe was made.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people won&amp;rsquo;t agree that email should work this way. If you don&amp;rsquo;t agree, feel free to tell me why  email is fine just the way it is, or tell me that this is a good idea. If you know of an app that has all of these features and functionality, please tell me, because I need it. If you want to develop it, go ahead. I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to be involved because I want this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Chris Messina reminded me about &lt;a href=&#34;http://mailplaneapp.com/&#34;&gt;MailPlane&lt;/a&gt;, which I tried preview releases of last year. Turns out that when you click Mailplane Growl alerts, MailPlane will open a window with the message, and you can click reply to enter your reply, click send, and close the window. This comes close enough without being quite as subtle and effortless as what I&amp;rsquo;ve wireframed above, so this is the solution I&amp;rsquo;m going with for now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Storyboard Paper for Stop Motion Animation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/using-storyboard-paper-stop-motion-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/using-storyboard-paper-stop-motion-animation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-image&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/2881764197/&#34; title=&#34;Using the Konigi Storyboard Graph Paper to plan stop motion animation by jibbajabba, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3266/2881764197_7229420b4e_o.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Using the Konigi Storyboard Graph Paper to plan stop motion animation&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My son got his hands on the storyboard paper and started sketching a stop motion animation sequence in the cells. He just started his second session in a stop motion class. This is one of the things I used our printed graph paper for, but because that was printed in black/gray on our laser printer, I had a hard time knocking out the grid lines mixed in with his drawings. Now, since this is on the cyan grid, I can scan 6 cells on each page, cut/crop each box visually, then knock out the blues. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait to try this out myself for something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the &lt;a href=&#34;../tools/graph-paper.html&#34;&gt;free printable storyboard&lt;/a&gt; graph papers in the tools section. Notepads are &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/product/storyboard-notepad?q=store/product/storyboard-notepad&#34;&gt;on sale here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing the Konigi Store</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/announcing-konigi-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/announcing-konigi-store/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/?q=store&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-1369&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt48d912e3ecae6.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to announce the first of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/?q=store&#34;&gt;series of products&lt;/a&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;m producing for creatives involved in design for the screen. The first 2 products are graph paper notepads formatted for user interface design and design of time-related sequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Wireframe Graph Paper Notepad&lt;/strong&gt; is made for visual designers, interaction designers, and information architects designing for the screen. The notepad has 50 sheets at 8 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; x 11 inches on white 70# paper, glued on the left side. The ink is a non-photo blue (cyan) so that the grid lines and any sketch lines made in non-photo blue pencil can be knocked out when scanned and processed in graphics software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Storyboard Notepad&lt;/strong&gt; is made for creatives who think about interactions over time, whether doing user interface or interaction design or planning video, film, and animation sequences. The notepad has 50 sheets at 8 1/2×11 inches on white 70# paper, glued on the left side. The ink is a non-photo blue (cyan).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about these products at &lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/?q=store&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store&lt;/a&gt;. Due to several large advanced orders supplies are limited. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I welcome your &lt;a href=&#34;../contact.html&#34;&gt;feedback&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://shop.konigi.com/?q=store&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OmniGraffle UX Template</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/omnigraffle-ux-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/omnigraffle-ux-template/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../tools/omnigraffle-ux-template.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://media.konigi.com/notebook/og-ux-template-screenshots.jpg&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the OmniGraffle web design template formerly hosted on my blog at urlgreyhot. The new UX template is now formatted for OmniGraffle Pro version 5. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this template you&amp;rsquo;ll find shared layers (masters) for a title page, wireframe, wireframe/storyboard hybrid, simple storyboard, and storyboard with notes. Guides and adherence to a regular grid make it easy to use. The doc is sized so you can work at 100%, and print at 8.5&amp;rdquo; x 11&amp;rdquo; or 11&amp;rdquo; x 17&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You you can view screenshots and &lt;a href=&#34;../tools/omnigraffle-ux-template.html&#34;&gt;download here at Konigi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../tools/omnigraffle-ux-template.html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://konigi.com/tools/omnigraffle-ux-template&#34;&gt;http://konigi.com/tools/omnigraffle-ux-template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OmniGraffle Web Design Template Updated</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/omnigraffle-web-design-template-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/omnigraffle-web-design-template-updated/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://urlgreyhot.com/personal/resources/omnigraffle_web_design_template&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://urlgreyhot.com/files/omnigraffle/ux-template.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot&#34; class=&#34;notebook-image&#34; style=&#34;width:610px;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I updated the &lt;a href=&#34;http://urlgreyhot.com/personal/resources/omnigraffle_web_design_template&#34;&gt;OmniGraffle Web Design Template&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This web design template is for people who do wireframes and storyboards. The template was created for OmniGraffle Professional provides the basic layout for a design deliverable including the following master canvases: document title, section title, wireframe (portrait and landscape), storyboard, and blank. The wireframes were created at 950px wide with guides following the Blueprint CSS Grid system. Wireframes also have 2 small hairline marks around the 600px point to mark the approximate fold. Go &lt;a href=&#34;http://urlgreyhot.com/personal/resources/omnigraffle_web_design_template&#34;&gt;grab it here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://urlgreyhot.com/personal/resources/omnigraffle_web_design_template&#34;&gt;http://urlgreyhot.com/personal/resources/omnigraffle_web_design_template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>