<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Communication on Konigi</title>
    <link>http://konigi.com/tags/communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Communication on Konigi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://konigi.com/tags/communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Give it five minutes</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/give-it-five-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/give-it-five-minutes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m certainly no stranger to being opinionated and argumentative. I&#39;ve put my foot in my mouth a few times by pushing back on others&#39; ideas, and am well aware that being quick to react can be detrimental. The older I get, the more I realize how little I know and how much more time I need to spend thinking after listening, before I open my mouth or start to type to respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admire Jason Fried&#39;s recent blog post, &lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Give it five minutes.&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; In it, he writes candidly about the issue of pushing back on ideas, starting from an exchange he had with Richard Saul Wurman, where the two had given talks at the same event. Wurman approached Fried to congratulate him, and Fried replied by telling Wurman what he disagreed with about his talk. The take away from that exchange was that Wurman taught Fried to stop and think, to give ideas a chance before challenging them with little respect or consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like this bit of advice from Fried, who turned that lesson into an opportunity to grow personally, and share what he learned from that exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;There are two things in this world that take no skill: 1. Spending other people’s money and 2. Dismissing an idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dismissing an idea is so easy because it doesn’t involve any work. You can scoff at it. You can ignore it. You can puff some smoke at it. That’s easy. The hard thing to do is protect it, think about it, let it marinate, explore it, riff on it, and try it. The right idea could start out life as the wrong idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So next time you hear something, or someone, talk about an idea, pitch an idea, or suggest an idea, give it five minutes. Think about it a little bit before pushing back, before saying it’s too hard or it’s too much work. Those things may be true, but there may be another truth in there too: It may be worth it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a fantastic little Jonathan Ive anecdote in there as well, where Ive explains Steve Jobs&#39; respect for the fragility of ideas, the best of which can start out naive, but lead to beautiful things if they&#39;re allowed the time and space to be explored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some of the best products can grow out of one&#39;s work done in isolation, the ideas need to be shared to grow into products. Stifling others&#39; ideas with immediate push back is not only a quick way to alienate your team, but squashing them too early can really do the most harm to you, by depriving you from seeing what it might become. This is one of those rare reminders that with maturity, hopefully we can learn to become more humble and grow. We just have to be open to the ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes&#34;&gt;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dogs on Design: Danzico and Lucy</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/dogs-design-danzico-and-lucy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/dogs-design-danzico-and-lucy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.core77.com/blog/featured_items/dogs_on_design_danzicos_obedient_vizsla__16733.asp&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2397&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4c1a293c95c99_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Core77&amp;rsquo;s Sarah Cox wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.core77.com/blog/featured_items/dogs_on_design_danzicos_obedient_vizsla__16733.asp&#34;&gt;a lovely article&lt;/a&gt; after talking with &lt;a href=&#34;http://bobulate.com/&#34;&gt;Liz Danzico&lt;/a&gt; about her thoughts on interaction design, life with her dog Lucy and communicating simply and humanly. Below is her summary of what dogs can teach us about interaction design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. It&#39;s important to know who is in charge.&lt;/strong&gt; Just like training a pet, a designer need to establish a rapport with clients that mixes trust and expertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Pay attention to the tail.&lt;/strong&gt; A dog&#39;s tail communicates emotions silently, but it&#39;s easy to miss this detail if you are not paying attention. Interaction designers need to be aware of customer data for clues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Keep gestures simple.&lt;/strong&gt; Complicated hand gesture confuses a dog, and complicated language confuses users. Simplicity is best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good advice for communicating with humans and dogs alike. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.core77.com/blog/featured_items/dogs_on_design_danzicos_obedient_vizsla__16733.asp&#34;&gt;Read more on Core77&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.core77.com/blog/featured_items/dogs_on_design_danzicos_obedient_vizsla__16733.asp&#34;&gt;http://www.core77.com/blog/featured_items/dogs_on_design_danzicos_obedient_vizsla__16733.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shades of Grey: Wireframes as Thinking Device</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/blog/shades-grey-wireframes-thinking-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/blog/shades-grey-wireframes-thinking-device/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notebook-screenshot&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uxmag.com/design/shades-of-grey-wireframes-as-thinking-device&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2368&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail large&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt4bd9eb96aa402_large.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Will Evans writes for UX Mag about &lt;a href=&#34;http://uxmag.com/design/shades-of-grey-wireframes-as-thinking-device&#34;&gt;his process for creating wireframes&lt;/a&gt;, or more precisely how he uses wireframes for ideation and problem solving. Will breaks his design process into three phases: divergence, transformation, and convergence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems similar to a common theme I come across when designers talk about their process&amp;ndash;framing/ideating, reframing/ideating, selection/refining. Buxton also refers to this, citing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/4563398985/&#34;&gt;Stuart Pugh&amp;rsquo;s idea&lt;/a&gt; by illustrating the expanding/contracting nature of a designer&amp;rsquo;s concept selection, which I find easy to map to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/jibbajabba/4564034112/&#34;&gt;sketching-&amp;gt;wireframing&lt;/a&gt; as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something Victor Lombardi wrote about the process of &lt;a href=&#34;http://noisebetweenstations.com/personal/weblogs/?p=2214&#34;&gt;concept design&lt;/a&gt; seems related here. Victor discusses expert vs. novice designers in an article that focussed on the designers&amp;rsquo; tendencies to frame and reframe the problem and approach solutions differently depending on expertise. The idea was basically that the experts, those with years of experience, had the tendency to simultaneously spend time on inquiry and problem framing as well as solution generation, but then abandon deep inquiry and rigor in favor of selection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reminds me of the few times I&amp;rsquo;ve worked a desk in a reference library in the past, where people framed their problem verbally only to have us help them reframe the problem in terms of a question that could be asked of the information. Language, questions and answers are the communication artifact there. The artifacts are really beside the point, but their usefulness in coming to a solution is important to the process when the discovery requires iterations of inquiry/framing/solving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The communication of ideas that things like wireframes facilitate is what is interesting. Replace wireframe with sketch, model, prototype, what have you. What Will Evans is showing here is that wireframes used in this way, serve as one of the communication artifacts we use for problem framing and solving. THAT is the right way to wireframe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uxmag.com/design/shades-of-grey-wireframes-as-thinking-device&#34;&gt;http://uxmag.com/design/shades-of-grey-wireframes-as-thinking-device&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gabble Client for Yammer</title>
      <link>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/gabble-client-yammer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://konigi.com/tools/submissions/gabble-client-yammer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tool-screenshot mb1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://erikhinterbichler.com/software/gabble/&#34;&gt;&lt;img id=&#39;bluga-thumbnail-2715&#39; class=&#39;bluga-thumbnail custom&#39; src=&#39;http://media.konigi.com/bluga/
wt522fea4f7d534_custom.jpg&#39;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://erikhinterbichler.com/software/gabble/&#34;&gt;Gabble&lt;/a&gt; is a native Mac OS X client for &lt;a href=&#34;http://yammer.com/&#34;&gt;Yammer&lt;/a&gt;, the micro-messaging application for companies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://erikhinterbichler.com/software/gabble/&#34;&gt;http://erikhinterbichler.com/software/gabble/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>